<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Business</title>
<item>
<url>http://hot-topic.co.nz/2007/12/13/the-canary-croaked/</url><title>The canary croaked</title><date>2007-12-13 08:27:34.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://hot-topic.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/1765-greuze-canary.jpg"><img src="http://hot-topic.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/1765-greuze-canary-tm.jpg" width="86" height="100" /></a> From AP (via <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2007/TECH/science/12/11/arctic.melt.ap/index.html" target="_top">CNN</a>): <span>"The Arctic is often cited as the canary in the coal mine for climate warming," said Zwally, who as a teenager hauled coal. "Now as a sign of climate warming, the canary has died. It is time to start getting out of the coal mines."</span> The annual American Geophysical Union meeting in San Francisco is bringing bad news about the Arctic - most of it listed in the foregoing linked article. One paragraph is particularly&nbsp;shocking:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><span>Still to be released is NASA data showing the remaining Arctic sea ice to be unusually thin, another record. That makes it more likely to melt in future summers. Combining the shrinking area covered by sea ice with the new thinness of the remaining ice, scientists calculate that the overall volume of ice is half of 2004's&nbsp;total.</span></p>
</blockquote>
<p>In three years, half of the summer ice has gone. In <span>Hot Topic</span> I suggest that it might all be gone in my lifetime - and I thought I was being pretty daring, given that the IPCC talks about the end of the century. One ice modeller who has been predicting an early demise for the summer sea ice is the US Navy's Wieslaw Maslowski. From the <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/sci/tech/7139797.stm">BBC</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>
  <span>"Our projection of 2013 for the removal of ice in summer is not accounting for the last two minima, in 2005 and 2007," the researcher from the Naval Postgraduate School, Monterey, California, explained to the BBC. "So given that fact, you can argue that may be our projection of 2013 is already too conservative</span>."
</p></blockquote>
<p>RealClimate is providing coverage of AGU highlights (<a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2007/12/live-almost-from-agu-dispatch-1/langswitch_lang/sk" target="_top">here</a>, <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2007/12/live-almost-from-agu%E2%80%93dispatch-2/langswitch_lang/sk" target="_top">here,</a> <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2007/12/hot-off-the-projector-3-atmospheric-co2-to-800-kyr-ago/langswitch_lang/sk" target="_top">here</a> and (update - sea ice specific) <a href="http://www.realclimate.org/index.php/archives/2007/12/notes-from-the-gathering-5-arctic-sea-ice-is-it-tipped-yet/langswitch_lang/sk" target="_top">here</a>. The <span>Herald</span> runs with a very <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/feature/story.cfm?c_id=26&amp;objectid=10482139&amp;ref=rss" target="_top">US-angled Reuters story</a>. As I've pointed out before, the consequences of the loss of summer sea ice in the Arctic for northern hemisphere climate is not known, but I would expect that there's some urgent work being done to find out. We're into the land of the unknown unknowns, and there's nothing we can do to stop&nbsp;it.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://jtc.blogs.com/just_left/2007/12/econ-indicators.html</url><title>Econ Indicators Report</title><date>2007-12-13 00:16:27.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div><p>Yesterday's <a href="http://www.med.govt.nz/templates/MultipageDocumentTOC____32722.aspx">economic indicators report</a>, from the Treasury, MED and StatsNZ, shows an interesting mixed picture of New Zealand's economic situation. From the Foreword:</p><blockquote><p><em>This report shows that New Zealanders overall have a good quality of life and that the economy has performed well over the past few years, with per capita growth in gross domestic product (GDP) somewhat above the OECD average. However, much of New Zealand’s recent economic growth can be attributed to our high levels of labour utilisation, evidenced by record low unemployment. If we are to achieve per capita incomes similar to those countries in the top half of the OECD, or in the more successful states of Australia, <strong>we need to match our high labour utilisation with high labour productivity. Labour productivity is influenced by levels of business innovation, investment in the latest technology and equipment, and by skills, infrastructure and scientific research. </strong>This report provides indicators that show how we are doing on all these fronts.<br /><br />Overall, New Zealand’s ranking within the OECD for many of the indicators in this report is not high. That said, the direction of change in many areas such as investment, patenting and expenditure on research and development (R&amp;D) is positive. Many of New Zealand’s economic foundations, such as our institutional and regulatory environment, remain solid.</em></p></blockquote><p>I've added the emphasis above because it comes back to something I have said a number of times. "business innovation, investment in the latest technology and equipment, and skills..." all are items that businesses themselves should be primarily responsible for. Government can provide a sound general framework. New Zealand indeed is a liberal fantasyland from that point of view. What government cannot do is make the micro level decisions that can actually have a determining impact on business level productivity.</p>

<p>If you think about it, the calls from some parties for tax cuts being a panacea are likely to have exactly the opposite effect. If you can make more money than you do now for running a business with middle of the road productivity, how would tax cuts give you the incentive to change your behaviour? They wouldn't. They would provide an incentive simply for more of the same.</p>

<p>That's why the changes to depreciation etc in the last Budget were good, because they incentivise the sorts of behaviour that would actually lead to higher productivity. But that is all they do. Provide incentives.</p>

<p>It is up to the talents and ambitions of those who run our organisations and businesses, big and small, to get more done for every dollar and make more as a result. Government isn't the solution, or the problem. It's just not relevant to that level of detailed decisionmaking.</p>

<p>As for the things govt can do, apart from broadly non-intervening frameworks (which I am prepared to accept for argument's sake give business less to worry about than a more hands on approach), investment in infrastructure is sharply higher now than it was a few years ago, but it will take years to make a real visible difference. The broadband stuff being talked about now is good, but years too late. The roading improvements in Auckland are really coming on stream, but rail is still shockingly behind the game. Other physical asset investment, well, the government could do more of it if the private sector wasn't doing so well that unemployment has largely vanished and wages are rising.</p>

<p>I would like to think NZ, with some persistence and good policy, could catch up Australia in the income stakes. Only twenty five years ago, before our mad flirtation with liberal extremism began, we were level pegging. I am not foolish enough to think that would be nirvana, or that it would suddenly stop people moving to the sunnier shores of our bigger neighbour. But it would be cool to have more disposable income here for everyone. No doubt about it.</p></div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/arctic-summers-ice-free-by-2013.html</url><title>Arctic summers ice-free 'by 2013'</title><date>2007-12-13 07:15:44.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp0.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2AlRF_qjVI/AAAAAAAACP8/wHPmLpv9lbQ/s1600-h/laun+copy+1.jpg"><img src="http://bp0.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2AlRF_qjVI/AAAAAAAACP8/wHPmLpv9lbQ/s400/laun+copy+1.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143151750054317394" /></a><br /><b>alt tv/fleet fm breakfast news comment</b><br /><a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/science/nature/7139797.stm">Arctic summers ice-free 'by 2013'</a><br /><b>Scientists in the US have presented one of the most dramatic forecasts yet for the disappearance of Arctic sea ice.</b> <br /><br /><i>Their latest modelling studies indicate northern polar waters could be ice-free in summers within just 5-6 years.<br /><br />Professor Wieslaw Maslowski told an American Geophysical Union meeting that previous projections had underestimated the processes now driving ice loss.<br /><br />Summer melting this year reduced the ice cover to 4.13 million sq km, the smallest ever extent in modern times.<br /><br /> Remarkably, this stunning low point was not even incorporated into the model runs of Professor Maslowski and his team, which used data sets from 1979 to 2004 to constrain their future projections.<br /><br /> "Our projection of 2013 for the removal of ice in summer is not accounting for the last two minima, in 2005 and 2007," the researcher from the Naval Postgraduate School, Monterey, California, explained to the BBC.<br /><br />"So given that fact, you can argue that may be our projection of 2013 is already too conservative."</i><br /><br />I have always argued that the IPCC is too conservative on the reality of global warming and that their sudden rush within 5 years from moderate language to ‘sudden’ and ‘catastrophic’ is a realization that the change is occurring so fast that the worst case scenario is rapidly becoming the most likely scenario. The heating of the Earth and the unprecedented speed of change due to our pollution is much worse and occurring much much faster than anyone guessed in the same way that most scientists used to believe comets and meteours were no threat when hitting the planet. Because we have all witnessed the stability (until recently) of the Weather we believe it impossible based on all our of our collective human experiences that there can be any sudden lurch of our global environment, so getting the message through that the ramifications that unchecked global warming is truly catastrophic in the very real sense of the word is incredibly difficult, add to that difficulty the vested interests of those making the largest contribution to the pollution and that to make this wrong right those who can most afford the changes necessary won’t, and we have a problem so entrenched that one is left with an impending sense of doom due to our collective ignorance and greed. <br /><br />Which is why todays news is so important in attempting to jolt our society of possums caught in the head lights, for the first time instead of walking in and the Dr telling you that smoking a pack of ciggies a day might make you puff a bit when you walk up stairs 20 years from now, the Dr instead tells you that you’ve got an advanced case of a very aggressive cancer – prior to this study the time we were told the arctic would be free of ice was the end of the century, then it was 2050, then 2040 maybe 2020, oh and now it could be 2013 – 6 years from now. With the 90% reflective power of the arctic cap gone, the oceans will absorb that heat from the sun, the oceans get hotter and hotter, leading to the frozen methane on the bottom of the ocean floor to melt and bubble to the top. This would start a chain reaction as methane holds heat 27 times more than CO2, and we would get a global spike of heat that would then melt the Greenland ice shelf, leading to a massive release of fresh water shutting down the ocean conveyor current that regulates heat from the tropics throughout the rest of the planet, this would trip Europe into an ice age, dramatically dragging down the temperatures and swinging the planet into an ice age, it is this sudden veering from extreme hot to extreme cold that will create the extinctions as the animals and plants can’t evolve that fast.  <br /><br />We have 6 years to do something, because once those feedback loops are breached it can’t be stopped.<br /><br /><a href="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2AXQV_qjUI/AAAAAAAACP0/b0_sbiaiorM/s1600-h/header04.gif"><img src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2AXQV_qjUI/AAAAAAAACP0/b0_sbiaiorM/s400/header04.gif" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143136344006626626" /></a>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199599209/online_accounting_google_apps.php</url><title>Online Accounting: The Next Killer App For Google Apps</title><date>2007-12-13 06:51:07.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><em>This article was a joint collaboration between chartered accountant Jonathan Bradford and computer scientist Ian Leader. They blog at <a href="http://blog.jayeyesea.com/">Jay Eye Sea</a>.</em></p>


<p><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/115/302869132_610ed22246.jpg?v=0" vspace="5" hspace="5" align="left" />In September Google added <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/google_presentations_launched.php">a presentation application</a>  to its Google Apps suite, thus creating an online office version of the
  "holy trinity&quot;: word processor, spreadsheet and presentation tool. So what's next for Google Apps? What might be the next killer app? We think it will be an <strong>accounting system</strong> and in this article we will outline why. There are strong benefits to an online accounting service in Google Apps – both to users and
  to the targeted advertising-driven business of Google. <i>[Ed's note: we are also running a poll at the end of the article]</i></p>
<h2>
  Online advantages</h2>
<p>
  To date, there have been a number of online accounting systems developed - e.g. <a href="http://www.mint.com/">Mint</a> and <a href="http://www.xero.com/">Xero</a> - which
  showcase some of the obvious benefits of online accounting:<br />
</p>
<ul>
  <li>
      <strong>Collaboration</strong>: More often than not, accounts are prepared collaboratively by a business owner and their accountant – and there may be
      a bookkeeper involved for all but the smallest companies.  </li>
  <li>
      <strong>Retention of records</strong>: Typically businesses are required to retain their
      records for a fixed period of time by the tax authorities (six years in
      the UK).  </li>
  <li>
      <strong>Accessibility</strong>: Typically the stakeholders are located in different places
      – currently requiring spreadsheets to be sent back and forth between the
      various individuals.  </li>
</ul>

<h2>
  Drawbacks to Current Online Accounting Systems</h2>
<p>
  There are a number of drawbacks in the solutions currently available:</p>
<p><strong>Simplification</strong></p>
<p>The greatest drawback from which accounting systems suffer is their UI. Accounting systems are invariably designed “by accountants for
  accountants”, which makes them overly complex for the small businessperson - who typically doesn't have accountancy training. At the end of the
  day, it's just debits and credits. Accounting systems need to be “Googlised” -
  in the same way that Gmail broke the mold from what had come before (compared
  to mainstream products like Yahoo! Mail and Microsoft Outlook), accounting
  systems need a simplified interface that makes sense to business people.</p>
<p><strong>
Costs</strong></p>
<p>Accounting software providers are well known for limiting the functionality in their “starter
  systems” - forcing users to upgrade to more expensive systems if they want to
  do much more than they can already do in Excel. Online solutions have
  exacerbated this problem by charging small amounts on a monthly basis
  <i>forever</i>.</p>
<p>What are the marginal costs of operating an online accounting system? They do
  not require significant processing capability, nor do they have significant
storage or bandwidth requirements. </p>
<p>
  Basic online accounting systems should be FREE. There are significant
  opportunities to generate revenues from other sources other than the core
  functionality. Small businesses are overcharged for “limited” accounting
  systems. Offering free business services is familiar territory for Google or start-ups
  working off a cloud computing platform, such as Amazon Web Services.</p>
<h2>Why Would Accounting be Attractive to Google?</h2>
<p>
  Google could bring significant expertise to online accounting, thanks to their
  ability to deliver simple, effective online applications with
  high-performance and reliable infrastructure. </p>
<p>But other than providing an
  attractive service to small businesses, which could be integrated into Google
  Checkout and Google Docs, what else would make this proposition attractive to
  Google?</p>
<p>
<strong>Historical information</strong></p>
<p>Eric Schmidt stated this year that it is “Google's
      goal to organize your daily life". However he also said that "we cannot even answer the
      most basic questions because we don't know enough about you. That is the
      most important aspect of Google's expansion."</p>
<p>
  Let's revisit the records within an accounting system and consider them from a
  different perspective: what we have is a detailed multi-year repository of information about a small business. Remember, business owners
  are required to retain records for a certain period by tax authorities.</p>
<p>
  The records would include: what it has been bought, when it was bought, from
  whom it was bought it and how much was paid. This is the information that
  'loyalty cards' regularly look to acquire. So it creates significant
  opportunities to deliver targeted and localized adverts. Undoubtedly Google could generate revenues from an online accounting application that
exceed its low incremental cost. Yes, there are privacy issues, some of which Google faced when it launched
  Gmail. But consider this: the threshold a business owner places on his/her
  business records are lower than his/her personal information. You regularly
  share your financial information with your accountant and bank manager – but
you wouldn't do the same for your personal data.</p>
<p>A business owner might also <b>benefit </b>from sharing this information to
  allow Google to present more cost competitive suppliers. Furthermore, it is
  not unusual for small business expenditure to be greater than an owner’s
  personal expenditure – thereby creating a more attractive opportunity for
  advertisers.</p>
<p><strong>Other revenue opportunities </strong></p>
<p>There are two exceptions to 'accounting
  systems should be free': one is payroll, and the other is automated
  submission of returns (VAT, income tax and national insurance). </p>
<p>Both of these
  business processes require updating and validating on at least an annual
  basis, to keep up with changes in national legislation. Almost all small
  businesses pay an accountant and / or payroll agency to handle these - but an
  online system could offer this at substantially lower cost. This might not
  be that far away, given the recent additions by Google of Gtaxes to their
  DNS records... </p>
<p><strong>Lack of innovation</strong></p>
<p>Sometimes it takes someone to look at things from
  “left field” to move an application forward. By way of example:<br />
</p>
<p>Online scanning. Since the launch of Book Search, Google has developed
    significant capability in scanning and the TesseratOCR technology. This
    could easily be used to scan invoices and bank/credit card statements –
    removing the tedium of its input. Furthermore, it will  include
    additional information which would be valuable to Google. Rather than just
    record the flight costs, the invoice might include other information such
    as time, destination etc. These documents could be scanned or faxed –
    similar to the service provided by File123.</p>
<p><strong>Mechanical Turk</strong></p>
<p>If scanning documents does not appeal, why not use a
  service such as Mechanical Turk to outsource the manual input of less
  sensitive information, such as such as invoices. Scanned invoices could be
  randomly presented to different Mechanical Turk users to be input for a few cents. </p>
<p><strong>
    Integration capability </strong></p>
<p>Google already has a variety of services available
  that could be tightly integrated into an accounting system:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Google Search; the use of scanning/OCR technology would create a much
    larger repository of information on which a user and Google could search.</li>
  <li>Google Docs; invoices, spreadsheets and charts could all be generated
    using existing applications.</li>
  <li> Google Base/Checkout; online traders could integrate their online presence
    on Base and also Checkout to integrate with the accounting system. </li>
</ul>
<p>Tell us what you think in the comments - is Online Accounting the next business frontier for Google to enter? Or will one of the current crop of online accounting startups get there first?</p>
<p><i>Top image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/57728319@N00/302869132/">10e20.com</a></i></p>
<p> <a href="http://www.polldaddy.com">survey software</a> - <a href="http://www.polldaddy.com/p/153125/">Take Our Poll</a> </p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=Su4omA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=Su4omA" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=hJRsyiC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=hJRsyiC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=38fdJ0C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=38fdJ0C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=YA9O5jc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=YA9O5jc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=EtUiMZc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=EtUiMZc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=zeTtl5c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=zeTtl5c" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=G4LbEiC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=G4LbEiC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199599209" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/theanalyst/2007/12/13/productivity-is-the-path-to-riches/</url><title>Productivity is the path to riches</title><date>2007-12-13 01:50:07.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/graph1.jpg" title="graph1.jpg"></a>Ask any economist.  How do we get rich as a nation?  The answer will invariably round on the subject of growth rates of labour productivity, or the amount of output per hour worked.  New Zealand has low labour productivity compared to the OCED and the nations that we like to compare ourselves with (Australia).  We just ain't as rich as them and the migration statistic speak for themselves - you are really better off going and living in Australia.</p>
<p>The <a target="_blank" href="http://www.med.govt.nz/templates/MultipageDocumentTOC____32722.aspx"><strong>Economic Development Indicators Report 2007</strong></a>, just released by the Ministry of Economic Development, makes for sobering reading.  When this Government was elected in 1999 it had a goal of returning NZ to the top half of the OECD rankings.  Well that goal lasted all of about 5 minutes as the Government got about the business of increasing taxes and handouts rather than trying to get the economy's engine of wealth creation going.</p>
<p>We can blather on all we like about digital "that" and creative "this", but we won't be better off until the economy becomes more efficient and increases the rate at which we can turn inputs into output.  Labour productivity is key because it is a measure of how much value can be created from each hour of work.  One thing that has improved is the rate of participation, so that we now have high rates of utilisation of labour, which is good.  But it's not the whole picture.</p>
<p><img border="1" vspace="5" align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/graph1.jpg" hspace="5" alt="graph1.jpg" title="graph1.jpg" />The report on page 29 (figure 2.1) shows how NZ stacks up against the rest of the OECD.  We aren't going very well.  The <strong>chart</strong> shows two lines which indicate constant GDP per capita between the different countries; New Zealand sits just below the bottom of this line, which implies that labour productivity is not high enough to keep GDP constant on a per head basis - Australia is doing much better.</p>
<p>New Zealand's measure of GDP per hour worked is just below 30, whereas Australia's is just over 40.  The top performer is Luxembourg at around 68 and the worst is Mexico at about 14.  We are easily in the lower half of the OECD.  In terms of hours worked per capita, New Zealanders work more than Australians.  So we work harder to produce less.  Ain't that just what you want to hear!</p>
<p>While the Government may say that our labour productivity growth rate has been improving (which it has), it has been below the rate of labour productivity growth that Australia has been enjoying for damn near 20 years.  So we are getting ahead compared to where we were, but we are falling behind the others, and in particular Australia.</p>
<p>Which means that we have to run faster to stand still and really run very hard just to try and catch up!</p>
<p>What is the answer?  More focus by Government on improving productivity growth - screw creative industries and picking winners.  Help businesses become more productive and efficient by having policies that focus on productivity growth.  Investment markets are there and can be accessed, research and development is not what it should be and the pool of savings (finally) is starting to grow thanks to KiwiSaver and tax changes to investment products.</p>
<p>The economics are unequivocal.  If we want to be richer as a nation then we need to have faster labour productivity growth.  End of story.  Government - get the policy setting right and make it happen.  If not, we face getting relatively poorer by the day and more New Zealanders will piss off to Australia.</p>
<p>Not becuase they like Australians, far from it, but because they will have a better life.</p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
