<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Entertainment</title>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~3/199607185/</url><title>Taika Waititi to film feature based on Two Cars, One Night</title><date>2007-12-13 07:16:33.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Taika Waititi, who directed Eagle vs. Shark, and was nominated for an Academy Award for his short film Two Cars, One Night, is looking for cast members, mostly children, for a feature length version of Two Cars, One Night called The Volcano, to be filmed in and around the Eastern Bay next year.
He said that [...]<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=PPABk8C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=PPABk8C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=o3m84Kc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=o3m84Kc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~4/199607185" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://hosking.blogspot.com/2007/12/argghhh.html</url><title>Argghhh......</title><date>2007-12-14 17:02:01.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_S57sX5HxwcY/R2H8Dd6ziPI/AAAAAAAAAAw/rWtgxcxCpVs/s1600-h/bunnahabhain.jpg"><img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_S57sX5HxwcY/R2H8Dd6ziPI/AAAAAAAAAAw/rWtgxcxCpVs/s320/bunnahabhain.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143669385934899442" border="0" /></a><br />It is Friday Arvo.<br /><br />A day at Nat Archives, doing research for a project I'm doing on political/economic history, a swim at the Freyberg (1km) and Chrissie party at the Toddler's creche: back to the home office and tidying up for the day.<br /><br />Nice new discovery, this stuff in the pic: Bunnahabhain.<br /><br />It's one of those fine Scottish single malts very carefully crafted so it is impossible to pronounce the name after one glass of the stuff.<br /><br />The correct pronunciation involves sounding as if you are a gravel crusher clearing its throat.<br /><br />Great way to kick back at the end of the week: glass of this stuff, and fired up the stereo.  Mine's got a five CD rotate so bunged in five different CDs and toed the 'shuffle' button.<br /><br />Two Aussies: Cold Chisel's <a href="http://www.coldchisel.com.au/album4.html">East,</a> Paul Kelly's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Wanted-Man-Paul-Kelly/dp/B000000EN8">Wanted Man; </a><br /><br />Two Kiwis - <a href="http://www.simongrigg.info/screamin.htm">Screaming Meemees</a> compilation ; and the Chills <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kaleidoscope-World-Chills/dp/B000000IMY">Kaleidoscope World</a><br /><br />And the<a href="http://www.amazon.com/Best-Pogues/dp/B000025SGU/ref=sr_1_19?ie=UTF8&amp;s=music&amp;qid=1197604425&amp;sr=1-19"> Pogues Best Of</a><br /><br />Weird mix.<br /><br />The Bunnahtahtauhahgraig or whatever the stuff is called is kicking in nicely now, thanks.<br /><br />It'll never replace my  liquid God, though:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://hosking.blogspot.com/2007/12/hosanna-in-excelcis.html</url><title>Hosanna in Excelcis</title><date>2007-12-14 18:19:06.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
The toddler has discovered Christmas carols.<br /><br />This is great: her health issues mean she is way behind in her language and related social skills. But she's always responded well to music and she has picked up about half a dozen Christmas carols in the space of a week.<br /><br />So we've been woken (she's like her dad, an early riser: I'd assumed I would welcome this but I now see the downside) several mornings with 'We Wish You a Merry Christmas' 'Good King Wencelas' or a sort of  blend of 'Hark the Herald Angels' and 'Once in Royal David's City'.<br /><br />Or 'We Three Kings' (also known as ' Star of Wonder'.)<br /><br />Now, this last one is kind of interesting. I don't know the 'proper' words to it: I only know the Fred Dagg version, which was done way back in 197omumble.<br /><br />I've been running this past a lot of people - of, I guess, a broadly similar age to myself -  and first I get a quizzical look as they try to think of what the real words are. Then they say, 'yeah, me too...'<br /><br />So, herewith, both versions<br /><br /><div><span>Fred Dagg</span><br /><span></span><br />We three kings of Orient are<br />One on a tractor, two in a car<br />One on a scooter tooting a hooter<br />Following yonder star.<br /><br />Ooh - Ooooh....<br /><br />Star of wonder<br />Star of light<br />Star of beauty, she'll be right<br />Star of glory, that's the story<br />Following yonder star.<br /><br /><div>Somewhat surprisingly, no-one has Youtubed this yet. There was a video clip done of it at the time but perhaps it has long since been shredded.<br /><br /></div><br /><span>The Original Version</span><br /><span></span></div><br /><br /><div>We three kings of Orient are<br />Bearing gifts we traverse afar<br />Field and fountain, moor and mountain<br />Following yonder star<br /><br />O Star of wonder, star of night<br />Star with royal beauty bright<br />Westward leading, still proceeding<br />Guide us to thy Perfect Light<br /></div><br /><br />There's a heap of other verses, but we don't need to labour the point, I feel.<br /><br /><span><span></span><br /></span><span><span><span><br /><br /></span></span></span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwibohemian.com/2007/12/13/The+Lukardo++Frontado.aspx</url><title>The Lukardo / Frontado</title><date>2007-12-13 00:40:35.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
      Where I work at <a href="http://www.fronde.com/">Fronde</a> we have an excellent
      coffee machine - in fact a proper real coffee machine that everyone gets trained up
      to use. So getting a good coffee is as easy as going to the kitchen and spending a
      few minutes grinding, expressing and frothing. 
   </p>
        <p>
      I must admit since I've been at Fronde I've really started to enjoy my espresso and
      even more so making it. My personal all time favourite coffee is a "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cortado">Cortado</a>",
      which is <span>essentially </span>a
      strong short black with an equal quantity of milk depending on how it's made. So in
      honour of my company I have "created" a coffee - or more realistically refined an
      existing coffee <span>recipe</span>.
      For Fronde purposes the name is a "Frontado" but for global domination purposes it
      can also be know as the "Lukardo" :). The idea is to have a strong coffee with an
      equal amount of steamed milk to take strong acidity away but leave a good strong
      taste. Very much an afternoon perk you up type of coffee. Apologies to any coffee
      snobs - but here is the <span>recipe </span>to
      make it: 
   </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <table cellpadding="0" width="100%" cellspacing="0">
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>
                    <p class="MsoNormal">
                      
                  </p>
                  </td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
          </span>
          <font color="#000000">
            <b>
              <span>
                <font size="5">The
      Lukardo/Frontado<span><font size="5"><img src="http://www.kiwibohemian.com/content/binary/Frontado%20012%20-%202%20[320x200].JPG" hspace="15" align="right" height="200" width="241" alt="Frontado 012 - 2 [320x200].JPG" border="0" /></font></span><span><font></font></span><span><font></font></span></font>
              </span>
            </b>
          </font>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <font color="#000000">
            <b>
              <span>
              </span>
            </b>
          </font>
          <b>
            <span>
              <font color="#000000">An
      adapted Cortado<span><font></font></span></font>
            </span>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">The Lukardo/Frontado
      is essentially a “shorter” Cortado.<span>  </span>A Cortado is an </font>
          </span>
          <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espresso" title="Espresso">
            <span>espresso</span>
          </a>
          <span>
            <font color="#000000"> "cut"
      (from the Spanish “Cortar”) with a small amount of warm </font>
          </span>
          <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milk" title="Milk">
            <span>milk</span>
          </a>
          <span>
            <font color="#000000"> to
      reduce the acidity. The ratio of milk is between 1:1 - 1:2, and the milk is added
      after the espresso.</font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <b>
            <span>
              <font color="#000000">To prepare
      a Lukardo/Frontado:<span><font></font></span></font>
            </span>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
        </p>
        <span>
          <font>
          </font>
        </span>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">Prepare and
      brew a double shot espresso into an espresso cup. Do not allow past half way and ideally
      it should be about 3/7 of the cup. This leaves the strength between a Ristretto and
      a double shot espresso. <span> <span><font></font></span></span></font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">Heat a small
      amount of milk, carefully not to produce large amounts of foam or bubbles. Without
      breaking the surface of the espresso to the edges pour the warmed milk slowly in the
      centre of the cup until it meets the beginning of the lip of the espresso cup. </font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">The <b>Lukardo/Frontado</b> should
      look like a mini flat white in an espresso cup.</font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <img src="http://www.kiwibohemian.com/aggbug.ashx?id=a5a203bd-7289-4fe0-b22d-5bf16910cba1" height="0" width="0" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/be-on-stars-in-their-eyes.html</url><title>Be on Stars in Their Eyes</title><date>2007-12-13 21:52:32.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
The New Zealand version of popular singing contest Stars in Their Eyes is coming to TV One! If you can sing and look a bit like your favourite star, then now is your chance to apply for Stars in Their Eyes. You'll need a video or DVD of your singing, and you need to be aged 18+ to appear on this primetime show. Whether you're a complete amateur, keen on Karaoke or a professional singer, the producers of Stars in Their Eyes would love to hear from you. You'll be given coaching on voice technique, timing, style, choreography and stage presence - everything it takes to become your Star! Register to be part of the Stars in Their Eyes competition and you could be named best in the land. Completed applications (and DVD or Video) can be posted to: Stars In Their Eyes Contestants Private Bag 93205 Parnell Auckland 1151 If you have any queries or problems with the application please email Imagination Television The closing date for applications is 1st February 2008. Related Stories: Click here for other opportunities to be on TV game shows, competitions and reality TV Photos: TVNZ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://sunnyo.blogspot.com/2007/12/armoured-bears.html</url><title>Armoured Bears</title><date>2007-12-14 11:09:49.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Since I read & loved the Hotel New Hampshire, I've often said that everyone needs a bear... I guess if underneath the hair & stuff they looked like Nastassja Kinski, it'd be a bonus.<br /><br />The movie version of Phillip Pullman's Northern Lights (filmed as The Golden Compass) is getting <a href="ttp://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/his_dark_materials_the_golden_compass/">mixed reviews</a>. But I'm keen to see how Iorek Byrneson is portrayed.<br /><br />Because really, if you have to travel a dangerous wilderness, what better and safer company than a talking, armoured polar bear.<br /><br />Rock on.<br /><br /><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v157/llew5/Iorek.jpg" width="350" vspace="5" hspace="5" align="centre" alt="Phew, seal breath." title="Phew, seal breath" /><br /><br />Update: "If I were you... I'd hire myself an armoured bear."<br /><br />Trailers <a href="http://movies.yahoo.com/movie/1808718640/video/5005627/#4451177">here</a>. The "teaser" one is best.<br /><br />"I have a contract with the child!"<br /><br />The film isn't doing so crash hot at the box office, <a href="http://www.reelviews.net/reelthoughts.html">Berardinelli </a>reckons sequels aren't on the cards. Pity. It looks quite good.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wellingtonista.com/cinephilia-opening-this-week-25</url><title>Cinephilia: Opening This Week</title><date>2007-12-13 11:29:24.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://miracle-pictures.com/funerals_and_snakes/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/200712132354.jpg"><img src="http://miracle-pictures.com/funerals_and_snakes/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/200712132354-tm.jpg" width="150" height="222" alt="Mr. Magorium poster" /></a>Just the one new film opening this week: <span><a href="http://www.magorium.com/" title="Mr. Magorium's Wonder Emporium official site" target="_blank">Mr. Magorium’s Wonder Emporium</a></span> about a magic toyshop facing unexpected change. It stars Dustin Hoffman and Natalie Portman and is reviewed <a href="http://miracle-pictures.com/funerals_and_snakes/2007/12/13/culture/cinema/review-into-the-wild-this-is-england-etc/" title="Magorium at F&amp;S" target="_blank">here</a>, at Funerals &amp; Snakes. <span>Magorium</span> is playing at <a href="http://www.readingcinemas.co.nz/cinemas/courtenaycentral.asp" title="Readings Courtenay Central">Readings</a>, <a href="http://www.hoyts.co.nz" title="Hoyts" target="_blank">Regent-on-Manners</a>, <a href="http://www.empirecinemas.co.nz" title="Empire Cinema, Island Bay" target="_blank">Empire</a> and <a href="http://www.skycitycinemas.co.nz/" title="Sky City Cinemas" target="_blank">Sky City Queensgate</a>.</p>
<p>It’s a quiet week before the big Boxing Day and New Year’s Day releases which, by my calculation, will see 13 more films open in cinemas around Wellington.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wildebeestasylum.blogspot.com/2007/12/sing-my-angel-of-music.html</url><title>Sing! My Angel Of Music!</title><date>2007-12-13 00:36:35.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<b>Nightwish – <i>End of an Era</i></b><br /><br />As previously mentioned on this blog, the band Nightwish underwent a drama filled change of lead woman a couple of years back, and in true ghoulish twenty first century media fashion they have documented it on DVD. We don't quite get to see the look on Tarja's face and the tears in her eyes when she realises she's been ditched, but they've recorded their last concert with her (she was fired immediately afterwards) and included a documentary of the last few weeks of the tour, complete with ominous title cards saying 'X days until Helsinki concert...' and full of retroactively ironic statements by Tarja about her perceived future with the band.<br /><br />The documentary is a little weird for that reason but fortunately the concert footage is fantastic, despite the best efforts of an obviously demented director whose passion for ill advised post production effects (overlayed flames, slo mo, etc.) is remarkable in it's lameness. Fortunately the  performance still shines through. In fact, this DVD makes me incredibly sad that when I see Nightwish in February Tarja won't be with them. I'm sure the new singer will do fine but I very much doubt that she'll generate the same stage presence as Tarja displays here.<br /><br />Nightwish's stage show is full of spectacle: Rammstein style pyrotechnics, huge video screens and all the over emoting of metal and opera combined, but even that is overwhelmed by the power of their music, which rocks and stomps it's way into the category of unbelievable awesomeness and beyond. Highlights include the old school singles 'Wishmaster' and 'Ever Dream' as well as 'The Siren' and their cover of Pink Floyd's 'High Hopes' (both of which I posted as videos in <a href="http://wildebeestasylum.blogspot.com/2007/09/hearken-to-sound-of-calling.html">my review of <i>Once</i></a><span>). Perhaps best of all their version of Andrew Lloyd Webber's 'Phantom of the Opera', which confirms my long held suspicion that that song was always supposed to be done metal.</span><br /><br />I think this disc would probably make a great drinking game. Drink every time one of the other band members visibly snobs Tarja onstage, drink for every shot of a teenybopper goth chick crying in the audience, drink every time Tarja changes outfits and I'm sure the astute viewer could think of more.<br /><br />Here's 'Phantom of the Opera':<br /><br />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/the_shortland_street_serial_killer_is_.html</url><title>The Shortland Street serial killer is ….</title><date>2007-12-14 01:35:09.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>So tonight we find out the Shortland Street serial killer.  I see two main possibilities.</p>
<p>If the <a href="http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/the_shortland_street_killer_revealed_-_probably.html">leaked video clips</a> do represents the three actual endings, then my pick is Luke Durvel.</p>
<p>If they were just planted by South Pacific Pictures to throw people off the trail, then I pick Joey.</p>
<p>I think Joey is more likely.  Serial killers often are not the grumpy no mates types, but go out of their way to befriend everyone.</p>
<p>He's just too clingy and needy.  I hope it is him anyway as his character is so annoying.</p>
<p>Thursday's episode suggest it could still be Scotty. And that was one of the three leaked endings.</p>
<p>The funniest twist would be if it was Yvonne!</p>
<p>We'll find out soon.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://sunnyo.blogspot.com/2007/12/armoured-bears.html</url><title>Armoured Bears</title><date>2007-12-13 03:40:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Since I read & loved the Hotel New Hampshire, I've often said that everyone needs a bear... I guess if underneath the hair & stuff they looked like Nastassja Kinski, it'd be a bonus.<br /><br />The movie version of Phillip Pullman's Northern Lights (filmed as The Golden Compass) is getting <a href="ttp://www.rottentomatoes.com/m/his_dark_materials_the_golden_compass/">mixed reviews</a>. But I'm keen to see how Iorek Byrneson is portrayed.<br /><br />Because really, if you have to travel a dangerous wilderness, what better and safer company than a talking, armoured polar bear.<br /><br />Rock on.<br /><br /><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v157/llew5/Iorek.jpg" width="350" vspace="5" hspace="5" align="centre" alt="Phew, seal breath." title="Phew, seal breath" /><br /><br />Update: "If I were you... I'd hire myself an armoured bear."<br /><br />Trailers <a href="http://movies.yahoo.com/movie/1808718640/video/5005627/#4451177">here</a>. The "teaser" one is best.<br /><br />"I have a contract with the child!"<br /><br />The film isn't doing so crash hot at the box office, <a href="http://www.reelviews.net/reelthoughts.html">Berardinelli </a>reckons sequels aren't on the cards. Pity. It looks quite good.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/tommy/2007/12/13/i-nearly-died-on-monday/</url><title>I nearly died on Monday</title><date>2007-12-13 03:50:50.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/janebeans2.jpg" alt="janebeans.jpg" />I was trapped in an elevator on Monday. Terrifying. It was exactly like something out of the movies. Actually, I hate it when people say “it was just like the movies” and don’t specify which movie exactly they were talking about. Unfortunately I can’t think of a movie off the top of my head where someone is trapped in a elevator, but I’m sure there are plenty. I want to say <em>Die Hard</em>, but that’s probably not right. <em>Teen Wolf</em> is a good movie but there are no elevators in that one. It wasn’t like <em>The Lion King</em> at all. It wasn’t anything like <em>Control</em>, although I highly recommend seeing it if you haven’t already. <em>Happy Feet</em> made me dance in the street, and coincidentally I did do a little dance, out of boredom, while I waited for the lift to plummet five floors and turn my poor neglected body into bloody pulp. So yeah, I guess it was kind of like <em>Happy Feet</em>.</p>
<p>So there I was, trapped in the lift. Stuck between the fourth and fifth floors. The power had gone out, and then come back on again. There was some weird electric buzzing, like when you taser a beehive. Bees are right terrifying. I pressed all the buttons on the lift. The buzzing got louder. The bees were closing in. I pressed the telephone button that was only for use in emergencies. I was trapped in an elevator full of electric bees so I think it counted as an emergency. The elevator phone rang for five sexy minutes and then a lady picked up. I told her about the bees. Then I told her that the lift had stopped also. She said that she would send some washed up celebrities over to rescue me as soon as possible. I asked if she could just send some regular elevator repair people, or the Power Rangers - if it would be quicker. She said yes. I still had to wait half an hour for them to show up. Apparently it was a busy day to be a Power Ranger.</p>
<p>At first I was glad I was alone in the lift. Then I started thinking, about what would happen to me if no one ever came. What if everyone in my building got the stairs from then on and never paid a single thought to what became of the elevator or the tall chap in 5A. I’d get really hungry. If there was someone there with me I could eat them. I wouldn’t kill them of course, I’m not into killing anyone, but I could just take nibbles off them when they were facing the other direction, or while they were asleep, or paralyzed because the bees got them because they were wearing blue and bees go crazy for blue.</p>
<p>I sang <em>Love Will Tear Us Apart</em> for a quick minute, then I figured that if I could find the beehive then there would be honey and I would have something to eat. I couldn’t find it. I danced some more, then I chewed on my hand. It had a flavour, but not a very nice one. Charcoal with a hint of mayonnaise and a dash of sand from the pocket of a girl who had been to the beach during winter and hadn’t washed her armpits since. Beggars can’t be choosers.</p>
<p>The door opened. Two blue power rangers with curious accents appeared. One of them said “Good Afternoon Mate!” Maybe for him. I didn’t tell him about the bees. I climbed out of the elevator and stood there awkwardly for a second. I felt like I should give them a hug or something for saving me. I didn’t. I was late for my meeting. I took the stairs down to the street, lit a cigarette and went on my way.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/reeling/2007/12/13/the-most-shocking-announcement-of-the-day/</url><title>The most shocking announcement of the day</title><date>2007-12-13 02:11:17.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/tpratchett.jpg" title="tpratchett.jpg"></a><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/terry_pratchett2.jpg" title="terry_pratchett2.jpg"></a>While it may have been a surprise for the general public to discover that <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/thepress/4322693a23059.html"><strong>Jessica Alba is pregnant</strong></a> (where were the women's mags with their speculative "is that a baby bump" photos? Looks like they dropped the ball on this one) is anyone really shocked to learn that <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/thepress/4322806a23059.html"><strong>Jodie Foster's a lesbian?</strong></a> And frankly, who cares? She's been with her film producer partner Cydney Bernard for 15 years.</p>
<p><img vspace="5" align="left" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/tpratchett.jpg" hspace="5" alt="tpratchett.jpg" title="tpratchett.jpg" />What's more shocking for fans of whimsical fantasy and humour is today's <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322919a1860.html"><strong>announcement</strong></a> (NZ time) that award-winning, best-selling author Terry Pratchett, OBE, has early-onset Alzheimer's.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.paulkidby.com/news/index.html"><strong>See his signed announcement, titled in typical Pratchett style as "An Embuggerance", here.</strong></a></p>
<p>While he is quick to point out he ain't dead yet and has a number of projects under way, it surely is alarming and sad news to his millions of readers around the world.</p>
<p>England's most fanatically followed novelist, Pratchett is also one of the world's most accessible. The stand-up comedian of fantasy, Pratchett does numerous book tours around the world and has even been known to post to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.lspace.org/fandom/afp/"><strong>his own newsgroup</strong></a>, which, to the devoted, is a bit like God turning up in church and sitting in a pew.</p>
<p>No one has yet managed to successfully adapt a Pratchett novel to the screen, although <a target="_blank" href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0695332/"><strong>a dozen attempts at TV movies and video-games have been made</strong></a>.</p>
<p>I've been lucky enough to interview the author - twice in 2004 (pictured above mid-interview, and below in a publicity shot with trademark hat and cane). Talking to the author is almost as funny as reading his books and at the time, he even made light of his recent angioplasty - "that's the one where they go up through your groin. I tried telling the doctors. I said: 'the heart is up here, the groin is down there. I thought you knew this stuff'."</p>
<p>Since publishing his first Discworld novel in 1983, Pratchett has written more than 40 books and sold 30 million copies. He was Britain's bestselling author until being overtaken by J. K. Rowling, and is estimated to have earned more than NZ$5 million last year alone.</p>
<p>Despite his OBE in 1998 for services to literature, Pratchett says that his novels are neither literature nor science fiction. There is still, however, a certain amount of literary snobbery towards his novels.</p>
<p><img vspace="5" align="left" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/terry_pratchett2.jpg" hspace="5" alt="terry_pratchett2.jpg" title="terry_pratchett2.jpg" />He says it's a misconception that his books are not reviewed by certain august publications. "I get reviewed a lot. Most of the reviews are good, even in what I call the 'posh papers'. Even when the reviews are bad, they're bad on the basis of 'this one wasn't as good as <em>Nightwatch</em>'. When people say a book of yours wasn't as good as another book of yours, which they thought was very good, that's not exactly a bad review, if you follow me."</p>
<p>When he has had an occasional negative review, it's usually not about his work. "It's about, 'We really don't like this sci-fi stuff and we think the people who read it are all nerds in anoraks', but it's not something that appears to be endemic."</p>
<p>Contrary to popular belief that Pratchett's fans are spotty teenage boys with no social skills, a recent survey of his readership showed that 60 per cent of his readers are women over the age of 25.</p>
<p>"Yes, there is a certain amount of snobbery against fantasy and science-fiction in general," he says, "and even the popularity of <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> has not changed anything at all."</p>
<p>Despite being a fan of <em>The Lord of the Rings</em> novels, he says he tends to keep away from movie deals. He hasn't met Peter Jackson and he doubts Jackson even knows who he is.</p>
<p>"The first movie was absolutely superb. It was like they stuck some electrodes into my head when I was 13 and recorded what I thought. The other two ... there were some things that Peter Jackson got wrong, I think. Or rather that the constraints on him showed. And the last one, you got this feeling that some people were thinking, 'This will make a very nice plastic figure'."</p>
<p>Which isn't to say there aren't a lot of very nice Discworld figurines available to buy, but Pratchett isn't actively trying to get Discworld movies made, saying: "I'm not entirely certain how filmable Discworld is."</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/blogonthetracks/2007/12/14/the-latest-music-dvds-to-arrive-through-my-letterbox/</url><title>The latest music DVDs to arrive through my letterbox</title><date>2007-12-13 20:12:27.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/elvis_1970-275-x-424.jpg" title="elvis_1970-275-x-424.jpg"></a>I seem to be receiving more and more music DVDs lately. I know that in some cases I have specifically requested them. I look forward to getting all the way through the set of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.roadrunnerrecords.com/blabbermouth.net/news.aspx?mode=Article&amp;newsitemID=80325"><strong>AC/DC live clips</strong></a> – and the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0965382/"><strong>Tom Petty documentary</strong></a>. But for every nostalgia trip (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/dominionpost/blogs/blogonthetracks/2007/11/28/plugging-back-in-to-nirvana/"><strong>see this polarising post</strong></a>) there are excursions in to the bland world of “why was I sent this?”</p>
<p>Music DVDs are great for me to review on the <a target="_blank" href="http://tvnz.co.nz/view/page/430905/599116"><strong><em>Good Morning</em> TV show</strong></a>; it means I have a ready-made clip without having to beg for beta footage. We can just use the visuals from the disc. Good stuff. But some of the DVDs that arrive just baffle me. I sit through them all though. I am a professional.</p>
<p>So, I thought I’d whip through a few quickly – ones that I may not get to review elsewhere. Some of these are not (to me) so flash. You might love them. Let’s have a peek…</p>
<p>From the ongoing <em>Live From Austin TX </em>series I sat down to watch the recent offerings (old gigs, but recently released on DVD) from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/John-Mayall-Live-Austin-Texas/dp/B000V6BE1M"><strong>John Mayall</strong></a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/Polyphonic-Spree-Live-Austin-Texas/dp/B000UDLA4M"><strong>The Polyphonic Spree</strong></a>. Both of these discs are pretty cool. But the gig (in each case) is a mere 50 minutes. With no extras. So – if John Mayall and/or The Polyphonic Spree are among your favourite artists then you will want these DVDs. The Spree sprawl across the stage, their sweetly manufactured harmonies and hippy-dippy costumes are either to your taste or not. But I rather enjoyed watching this set. I think they’d be cool to see live. John Mayall looks ridiculous in this gig from 1993. He looks like the embarrassing uncle at any 21st. But it’s a reasonably decent blues-rock set.</p>
<p>I have never understood <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nellyfurtado.com/"><strong>Nelly Furtado’s </strong></a>appeal. Watching <a target="_blank" href="http://www.ilikemusic.co.uk/pop/Nelly_Furtado_Do_It_Loose_Concert_DVD-4285"><em><strong>Loose – The Concert </strong></em></a>didn’t help at all. I hated that song <em>I’m Like a Bird</em>. And when <a target="_blank" href="http://www.penguin.co.uk/static/cs/uk/0/minisites/nickhornby/index.html"><strong>Nick Hornby</strong></a> tried to write in praise of it (<a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/31-Songs-Nick-Hornby/dp/0141013400"><em><strong>31 Songs</strong></em></a>) it made me hate Nick Hornby. Here Furtado, who has had a big year, and basically made herself over as a pop star (again), comes across as <strong>Gloria Estefan </strong>before the crash (in all senses of the word). I wish the rhythm really would get her.</p>
<p><img vspace="5" align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/elvis_1970-275-x-424.jpg" hspace="5" alt="elvis_1970-275-x-424.jpg" title="elvis_1970-275-x-424.jpg" /><a target="_blank" href="http://www.elvis.com/"><strong>Elvis Presley </strong></a>is pretty cool. It is easy to say that he was not a good musician, but that’s missing the point. Big time. Elvis really was the greatest – at what he did. He rocked. It took me years to really get my head around how superb he was – at his best – but I’m there now and one of my favourite music DVDs is <a target="_blank" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0065687/"><em><strong>Elvis – That’s The Way It Is.</strong></em></a> Yes, I know that every year some record company folk decide there must be a way to repackage and re-sell The King. And it seems to (usually) work. This year there was another greatest hits CD. And <a target="_blank" href="http://www.elvis.com.au/presley/dvd/elvis_the_king_dvd_19.shtml"><em><strong>Elvis: The King of Rock’n’Roll</strong></em></a> is the accompanying DVD. I rather enjoyed this – to me it was a bit of a one-watch though. Thirty songs are shown, from early promo clips through to the classic <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elvis_Presley's_'68_Comeback_Special"><em><strong>’68 Comeback Special</strong></em></a> and my aforementioned favourite show/film (from 1970). If you never liked Elvis I guess it is obvious that you should pray that no one gives you this DVD for Christmas. If you know someone who likes Elvis (and statistics suggest that is most definitely the case) then you could do worse than offer this sampler-DVD to the one you love who loves Elvis Presley.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.manchestereveningnews.co.uk/entertainment/music/s/1025694_keane_live_dvd_universal"><em><strong>Keane Live</strong></em></a> was next in the DVD player. Not keen.</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.davidbowie.com/"><strong>David Bowie</strong></a> has had a remarkable career – but two words tend to put fear in the heart of even the most ardent support of the erstwhile Ziggy, the former Thin White Duke. And no, I don’t mean <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tin_Machine"><strong>Tin Machine</strong></a>. I mean two <em>other</em> words. <em>Glass Spider</em>. Finally the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.dvdmg.com/davidbowieglassspider.shtml"><strong>1987 tour comes to DVD </strong></a>(what, there was actually demand for this?). I remember watching the video and not understanding it at all. It is almost hilariously kitsch to watch this show now, 20 years on. What has he thinking? The dancers look like they were modelled on extras from <a target="_blank" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0080120/"><em><strong>The Warriors</strong></em></a> – all this from a guy deemed cutting edge? <a target="_blank" href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0091369/"><em><strong>Labyrinth</strong></em></a> must have rotted his brain. When <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Frampton"><strong>Peter Frampton</strong></a> is playing guitar on stage – and it is not the worst thing happening…well, it is time to look elsewhere for answers, right? But, if, like me, you are a bit of Bowie fan, you might still like a look at this. Just don’t look too closely. One watch should be the rule here.</p>
<p>This year I had the displeasure to hear an album called <em>Life in Cartoon Motion</em> by some berk named <a target="_blank" href="http://www.mikasounds.com/uk.php"><strong>Mika</strong></a>. This guy seems keen to try to take the worst elements of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.scissorsisters.com/intro/"><strong>The Scissor Sisters </strong></a>and <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Darkness"><strong>The Darkness </strong></a>and prove that he can make something even worse! No-Brainer, right? Instead of being a post-millennial <strong>Bee Gees</strong> and/or a post-millennial <strong>Meatloaf</strong>, Mika has desires to be the new <strong>Freddy Mercury</strong>. This is so blatantly obvious that in the interview segments on the DVD I am about to mention he talks about how he is not just a one-man <strong>Queen</strong> revival. Which pretty much guarantees you that he is in fact a one-man Queen revival – so, we get to the DVD: <strong><em><a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/Mika-Live-Cartoon-Motion/dp/B000WOYRJE">Live in Cartoon Motion</a></em></strong> is Mika live in concert playing the hits from his album. It is really horrible. He also covers <strong>The Eurhythmics’ </strong><em>Sweet Dreams (Are Made of This) </em>and manages to make detractors forget about <strong>Marilyn Manson’s </strong>decimation of <em>Sweet Dreams</em>. The painful falsetto prancing over cheap ivory-tinkling is a gimmick that is swiftly worn out. I wouldn’t send this DVD to my worst enemy for Christmas (it would be pointless anyway, sending Mika a copy of his own DVD, right?).</p>
<p>Next up I watched the <a target="_blank" href="http://www.cduniverse.com/productinfo.asp?pid=7519686"><em><strong>Concert For Diana </strong></em></a>– a 2-DVD set chronicling the concert that Princes Harry and William put on for their deceased mother (“the people’s princess”). There are some okay songs/performances here – but it is a long haul. A hard workout – thank god for the skip button or I never would have made it. At least five hours of performances were economically skipped down to about 35 minutes of highlights in my swift viewing. <strong>Duran Duran </strong>shows no feeling for the situation at all by singing <em>Wild Boys</em>. I thought they were going to sing <em>Hungry Like a Wolf </em>and then dedicate it to the rabid paparazzi at the scene of the crash. What, too soon? Ten years on? Of course <strong>Elton John </strong>kicked things off and he played <em>Your Song</em>. Like a total cheese.</p>
<p>Then there were pointless songs by <a target="_blank" href="http://fergie.blackeyedpeas.com/"><strong>Fergie</strong></a>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.lilyallenmusic.com/"><strong>Lily Allen</strong></a>, Nelly Furtado (ugh, I had to watch her on DVD twice in one weekend!) and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.anastacia.com/"><strong>Anastacia</strong></a>. Some of the old heads came through. <strong>Rod Stewart </strong>was great, launching into <em>Maggie May</em> straight away and following it up with <em>Baby Jane</em>. <strong>Bryan Ferry </strong>was all class – as he almost always is. Then the rot really set in with a ridiculous medley of ridiculous songs from the ridiculous pen of the rather, erm, ridiculous <a target="_blank" href="http://www.reallyuseful.com/rug/html/index.htm"><strong>Andrew Lloyd-Webber</strong></a>. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.thebubbleburst.co.uk/bb.php?entry=Jason%20Donovan"><strong>Jason Donovan</strong></a> and <a target="_blank" href="http://www.donny.com/announcements.pl?cmd=view&amp;aid=235"><strong>Donny Osmond </strong></a>battled it out to prove who was the bigger has-been in their duelling renditions of songs from <em>Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat</em>. Any dream indeed! They’re both still hanging on…</p>
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.diddy.com/"><strong>P Diddy </strong></a>tried to remain relevant – pointless considering <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kanye_West"><strong>Kanye West</strong></a> was there to usurp him (again). And there was a good comedy-spot by <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rickygervais.com/"><strong>Ricky Gervais </strong></a>singing that song <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9JitDWQI9qc"><strong>that David Brent does in the episode of <em>The Office</em> when he sabotages the team-training session</strong></a>. Gold.</p>
<p>But what a long-winded DVD to sit through; boring tributes to Diana’s amazing humanity ring out while roadies nearly as old as the members of <a target="_blank" href="http://www.statusquo.co.uk/"><strong>Status Quo </strong></a>plod along behind amps. Here’s a newsflash: <strong>Princess Anne</strong> has done twice as much for humanitarian causes – and she’s competed at the Olympic Games! (A royal doing some real work for once.) Just because she happens to look more like the horse she rides than any human should, she seems to be written off. Sad.</p>
<p>I was sent a DVD by <a target="_blank" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Andr%C3%A9_Rieu"><strong>Andre Rieu</strong></a>. This guy is someone I have avoided for years. I have happily sold his material when I worked in music stores. I have been sent copies of his CDs and always passed them on without a listen. But a DVD? This piqued my curiosity. I wish it hadn’t. I next watched <a target="_blank" href="http://www.moviestars.co.nz/DVDs/1551177.html"><em><strong>Andre Rieu in Wonderland</strong></em></a>. Oh my! This guy is a nut. A total cheese – with a smug look as he saws away rather mundanely at his violin while all around him it is as if Dorothy has gone missing and the rest of the cast of the original <em>Wizard of Oz</em> have been dug up, fed ecstasy pills and been forced to trudge through all their worst moments, being told to make it count this time! It’s music/muzak for people with no clue. I wish I had the minutes of my life back between pressing play and pressing eject (and that is only about 13 minutes in total).</p>
<p>As with the <em>Live from Austin TX</em> series, another ongoing set of DVDs that I like to keep in vague touch with is the <em>Live At Montreux </em>concerts. The Montreux Jazz Festival often has very little to do with actual jazz, spreading out to take in funk, soul and pop artists. Recently I received <a target="_blank" href="http://www.gpstore.co.nz/DVDs/1551714.html"><strong>the Jamiroquai entry</strong></a> – a live set from 2003’s festival. I had always thought that Jamiroquai would be a great live act – I’ve never been a fan of the band, but I’ve never exactly hated them. I started off enjoying this concert, but was bored very swiftly. The first two Jamiroquai albums were not too bad – certainly better than anything <strong>Stevie Wonder</strong> was doing at the time (which is essentially what the JK albums were, unaccredited Stevie Wonder attempts). But I guess the problem was the band continued to release those same two albums every two years for over a decade. This gig is not bad – but it drags on a little toward the end.</p>
<p>From 2005, in the same series, I also watched <a target="_blank" href="http://shop.mtv.com/Isaac-Hayes--Live-at-Montreux-2005-Concerts--nf-_stcVVproductId21227982VVcatId421318VVviewprod.htm"><strong>the Isaac Hayes gig</strong></a>. This is pretty cool. It takes a while for Mr <em>Chocolate Salty Balls</em> to really wind up – starting the gig with some pretty boring material. But then the Bacharach and Jimmy Webb covers kick in – and of course the <em>Theme from Shaft</em>. And it’s a rocking-sweet soul-funk affair. A good way to end – proof that not all was wasted looking through these DVDs.</p>
<p>I am so thrilled that DVD players come with skip buttons, or I never would have made it.</p>
<p>That’s the latest batch that made it through the letterbox. There are more sitting in piles. I will get to them soon.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/checkraise/2007/12/13/the-bigger-they-come/</url><title>The bigger they come…</title><date>2007-12-13 01:10:54.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Was about time for a music heading again... lil Jimmy Cliff for you all, mon...</p>
<p>Two WSOP Main Event winners went to the rail yesterday at the APPT season finale in Sydney.</p>
<p>Greg Raymer and Chris Moneymaker were two of the big names at the tournament but Raymer was an early exit and Moneymaker, after a promising start, soon followed.</p>
<p>Mark Vos was another among the 179 players who took to the tables on Day 1a to be eliminated, along with 2007 WSOP Main Event final table player Raymond Rahme.</p>
<p>The South African lost a monster pot to Grant Levy. On a Js-7d-Qs flop, all the money went in but Rahme's pocket aces were trumped as Levy had flopped a set with his pocket jacks.</p>
<p>My favoutite hand of the day was this one:</p>
<p>In a battle of the blinds, Luigi Apreda raised from the small blind to $6,000 and John Donahue in the big blind called. The flop of 8s-8c-4h was checked by both players and the turn was a 4s. Apreda lead out for $15,000 but Donahue poppedit up to $30,000, which Apreda called.</p>
<p>The river was a 3s and Apreda lead out again for $25,000. Donahue went into the tank for a few minutes before calling - much to his delight, as his Kd-Qs saw off Apreda's bluff with 9h-7c to win a $120,000 pot.</p>
<p>Levy was among the big movers all day but lost a little towards the end before finishing the day comfortably in seventh spot with $173,000. Team PokerStars member Terrence Chan was another to shine, hitting some nice hands in accumulating $253,200 in chips to rank third after the opening day.</p>
<p>Lee Nelson was seating up for day 2a today at time of writing along with Scotty Nguyen as part of the Team PokerStars line-up.</p>
<p>Haven't had a listen yet to this week's edition of the <a href="http://www.bigpoker.ca/" title="Rounders">Rounders Radio Show </a> but intend to shortly - bound to be good, as Andy Bloch talks about the sadly-departed Chip Reese.</p>
<p>The schedule is out for next year's WSOP - I'm so tempted to put together a proposal for my bosses at work to cover this. Pipe dream maybe, but I've always been keen on backing longshot.</p>
<p>Details on the WSOP schedule and a nice take on the Chris Vaughn situation discussed here earlier are at the excellent <a href="http://hardboiledpoker.blogspot.com/" title="Boiled">Hard-Boiled Poker </a> blog.</p>
<p>Home game tonite so hope to have a match report if time allows and I'm not on tilt like last week.</p>
<p>Until tomorrow<br />
Shuffle up and deal</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/coolkit/2007/12/14/ok-gos-ping-pong-programme/</url><title>Ok Go’s ping pong programme</title><date>2007-12-13 20:37:30.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Z57W0g1TRo"></a><a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Z57W0g1TRo"><img align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/11/okgo.jpg" alt="okgo.jpg" /></a>Here's a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Z57W0g1TRo&amp;feature=related"><strong>great clip</strong> </a>starring rock band Ok Go before they got famous with their synchronised treadmill dancing.</p>
<p>Videos like this are how savvy bands are using the inter-tubes to grab audiences. This one is a hilarious spoof on fitness videos.</p>
<p>You gotta love a band with a sense of humour too. That musak version of their song is just classic.</p>
<p>Watch it at: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Z57W0g1TRo"><strong>www.youtube.com/watch?v=9Z57W0g1TRo</strong></a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwibohemian.com/2007/12/13/The+Lukardo++Frontado.aspx</url><title>The Lukardo / Frontado</title><date>2007-12-13 00:40:35.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
      Where I work at <a href="http://www.fronde.com/">Fronde</a> we have an excellent
      coffee machine - in fact a proper real coffee machine that everyone gets trained up
      to use. So getting a good coffee is as easy as going to the kitchen and spending a
      few minutes grinding, expressing and frothing. 
   </p>
        <p>
      I must admit since I've been at Fronde I've really started to enjoy my espresso and
      even more so making it. My personal all time favourite coffee is a "<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cortado">Cortado</a>",
      which is <span>essentially </span>a
      strong short black with an equal quantity of milk depending on how it's made. So in
      honour of my company I have "created" a coffee - or more realistically refined an
      existing coffee <span>recipe</span>.
      For Fronde purposes the name is a "Frontado" but for global domination purposes it
      can also be know as the "Lukardo" :). The idea is to have a strong coffee with an
      equal amount of steamed milk to take strong acidity away but leave a good strong
      taste. Very much an afternoon perk you up type of coffee. Apologies to any coffee
      snobs - but here is the <span>recipe </span>to
      make it: 
   </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <table cellpadding="0" width="100%" cellspacing="0">
              <tbody>
                <tr>
                  <td>
                    <p class="MsoNormal">
                      
                  </p>
                  </td>
                </tr>
              </tbody>
            </table>
          </span>
          <font color="#000000">
            <b>
              <span>
                <font size="5">The
      Lukardo/Frontado<span><font size="5"><img src="http://www.kiwibohemian.com/content/binary/Frontado%20012%20-%202%20[320x200].JPG" hspace="15" align="right" height="200" width="241" alt="Frontado 012 - 2 [320x200].JPG" border="0" /></font></span><span><font></font></span><span><font></font></span></font>
              </span>
            </b>
          </font>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <font color="#000000">
            <b>
              <span>
              </span>
            </b>
          </font>
          <b>
            <span>
              <font color="#000000">An
      adapted Cortado<span><font></font></span></font>
            </span>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">The Lukardo/Frontado
      is essentially a “shorter” Cortado.<span>  </span>A Cortado is an </font>
          </span>
          <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Espresso" title="Espresso">
            <span>espresso</span>
          </a>
          <span>
            <font color="#000000"> "cut"
      (from the Spanish “Cortar”) with a small amount of warm </font>
          </span>
          <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Milk" title="Milk">
            <span>milk</span>
          </a>
          <span>
            <font color="#000000"> to
      reduce the acidity. The ratio of milk is between 1:1 - 1:2, and the milk is added
      after the espresso.</font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <b>
            <span>
              <font color="#000000">To prepare
      a Lukardo/Frontado:<span><font></font></span></font>
            </span>
          </b>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
        </p>
        <span>
          <font>
          </font>
        </span>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">Prepare and
      brew a double shot espresso into an espresso cup. Do not allow past half way and ideally
      it should be about 3/7 of the cup. This leaves the strength between a Ristretto and
      a double shot espresso. <span> <span><font></font></span></span></font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">Heat a small
      amount of milk, carefully not to produce large amounts of foam or bubbles. Without
      breaking the surface of the espresso to the edges pour the warmed milk slowly in the
      centre of the cup until it meets the beginning of the lip of the espresso cup. </font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <p class="MsoNormal">
          <span>
            <font color="#000000">The <b>Lukardo/Frontado</b> should
      look like a mini flat white in an espresso cup.</font>
          </span>
        </p>
        <img src="http://www.kiwibohemian.com/aggbug.ashx?id=a5a203bd-7289-4fe0-b22d-5bf16910cba1" height="0" width="0" />]]></description>
</item>
</category>
