<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>International</title>
<item>
<url>http://nzconservative.blogspot.com/2007/12/pope-benedicts-message-on-climate.html</url><title>Pope Benedict's message on climate change and world peace</title><date>2007-12-14 17:54:18.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Looks like the Pope has caused a bit of a storm with a whole range of people.  Andrei has <a href="http://briefingroom.typepad.com/the_briefing_room/2007/12/climate-change.html">a good post up on the details</a>.  Not PC is <a href="http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/sense-and-non-sense-from-would-be-world.html">a little surprised</a>, but then he puts it all down to the advisers the Pope must have.<br /><br />I'd just like to highlight a couple of statements that stood out to me.<br /><blockquote>... fears over man-made emissions melting the ice caps and causing a wave of unprecedented disasters were nothing more than <span>scare-mongering</span>.<br /><br />The German-born Pontiff said that while some concerns may be valid it was vital that the international community <span>based its policies on science rather than the dogma of the environmentalist movement</span>.</blockquote><span id="fullpost">This has been my position on climate change all along - I'm so glad I don't need to reconsider!<br /><blockquote>... the world needed to care for the environment but <span>not </span>to the point where the <span>welfare of animals and plants</span> was given a <span>greater priority</span> than that of mankind.</blockquote>Yes!  All those people that are so worried about whales or giant snails - are they at all perturbed by tiny human babies being sucked out of their mother's wombs?  Related to that, this Sunday marks 400,000 tiny human lives taken by abortion in NZ in the last 30 years.<br /><blockquote>"The human community cannot do without the service provided by the family. Where can young people gradually learn to savor the genuine 'taste‚' of peace better than in the original 'nest‚' which nature prepares for them."<br /><br />...<br /><br />"Whoever, even unknowingly, circumvents the institution of the family undermines peace in the entire community, national and international, since he weakens what is in effect the primary agency of peace. This point merits special reflection: Everything that serves to weaken the family based on the marriage of a man and a woman constitutes an objective obstacle on the road to peace."</blockquote>It has often been asked why gay marriage threatens traditional marriage.  As if someone else's marriage could threaten another's.  But the threat is not so much direct as indirect.  Once the notion of marriage, all it entails, all it's responsibilities are changed, marriage is weakened.  If it is considered that marriage is temporary, until one "partner" falls out of love, then marriage is weakened, and the children's ability to form life long relationships is weakened, as they've never seen how a life long relationship works.  If any man and his dog can get married, then marriage becomes a joke, something no one really needs or aspires to.  Yet marriage is fundamentally necessary in raising children and instilling values.  Without that, everything falls apart.  And we can see that happening quite clearly in NZ.<br /><br />Related Links: <a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/pages/live/articles/news/worldnews.html?in_article_id=501316&amp;in_page_id=1811">Daily Mail</a>, <a href="http://www.nysun.com/article/67983?page_no=3">New York Sun</a><br /></span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://nzconservative.blogspot.com/2007/12/real-environmental-faith.html</url><title>A Real Environmental Faith</title><date>2007-12-13 11:53:58.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Over the last 30 years, divorce rates have skyrocketed. So much so that it became apparent fairly quickly that if the courts were going to cope, then something needed to be done to speed it up. The result was no-fault divorce laws which sped things so much that it has now become <span>passe</span> for lawyers and judges to dissolve families with the stroke of a pen. The social consequences have been disastrous, but now it seems there might be a new twist that not even Al Gore (that overweight and over-blown, lying <span class="blsp-spelling-error" id="SPELLING_ERROR_0">sook</span> who failed to beat George Bush) could think of. Divorce is bad for the environment.<br /><br /><span id="fullpost"><br />In the on-line up coming papers section of the Proceedings of the Academy of National Sciences (<span class="blsp-spelling-error" id="SPELLING_ERROR_1">PNAS</span>) an article edited by none other than human apocalypse junkie Paul Ehrlich, suggests that <a href="http://www.pnas.org/cgi/content/abstract/0707267104v1">the environmental impact of divorce is high</a>. For example:<br /><br /><span>In the United States (U.S.) in 2005, divorced households spent 46% and 56% more on electricity and water per person than married households. Divorced households in the U.S. could have saved more than 38 million rooms, 73 billion kilowatt-hours of electricity, and 627 billion gallons of water in 2005 alone if their resource-use efficiency had been comparable to married households.</span><br /><br />Which is why the Pope is currently <a href="http://www.ewtn.com/vnews/getstory.asp?number=84482">stressing the correct order of principles </a>when it comes to the environment. Humanity comes first, and should be the over-riding guiding principle for addressing environmental issues. And we should ignore "ideological pressures that draw hasty conclusions".<br /><br />Which all goes to show: save the family and you just might save the world.<br /></span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://newzealandconservative.blogspot.com/2007/12/ideology-and-education.html</url><title>Ideology and education</title><date>2007-12-13 20:26:42.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
As someone who believes that too many people go to university these days, I was mildly pleased to hear that the University of Auckland is planning to restrict entry to all undergraduate courses for 2009 ("<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/metro/story.cfm?l_id=117&amp;objectid=10480136">University Senate back plan on numbers</a>," <em>New Zealand Herald</em> Dec 4, 2007).<br /><br />The university says it is making the changes to cope with a shortfall of money driven by cut backs in central government funding. Hence the university is planning to limit entry for art, education, science, theology and first year law. Not sure about the science limits, but the other cut backs sound excellent.<br /><br />Over the last twenty years, the value of a university degree has steadily declined, as more and more marginal students, who have neither the academic aptitude or the intellectual curiosity for university level courses, have drifted through the system to satisfy the government’s crude targets for more "human capital" throughput.<br /><br />Unfortunately, as I read on, I realised that my initial impression, that for once common sense might trump ideology, was too good to be true.Predictably, the University deputy vice-Chancellor, Professor Raewyn Dalziel, says the institution plans to establish a taskforce to increase enrolment of under-represented students:<br /><br /><em>"The special admission schemes which set aside places for Maori, Pacific, and other under-represented communities operating in facilities which already restrict entry will be expanded."<br /><br /></em>If, by "under represented communities," the University means students from low-income families, then this looks to be another kick in the face for hard-working students and parents from lower-middle class families who tend to suffer the most from affirmative action policies.<br /><br />While low-income families receive generous government allowances, and upper middle class kids can usually rely on parental support, students from middle-income families are caught in the middle - too well-off to be eligible receive allowances, yet not rich enough to be able to rely on significant help from their parents. Now their opportunities to cover the cost of their courses, through scholarships or other subsidies, are likely to be further limited.<br /><br />As I’ve said before, only indigenous minorities have a reasonable case for preferential treatment, and even then, they should have to accept cutbacks in quotas when others are having to make sacrifices.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://blog.greens.org.nz/index.php/2007/12/14/target-practice/</url><title>Target Practice</title><date>2007-12-14 02:18:14.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Well, it looks like the US, China, Canada and Japan are going to hold Bali to ransom and prevent anything substantial from coming out of it. Not that I expected any grand outcome, just a decent framework to keep the post-Kyoto negotiations going. A couple of weeks ago, I posted a link to <a href="http://www.carbonequity.info/PDFs/Arctic.pdf" target="_blank">The Big Melt, Lessons from the Arctic Summer of 2007</a>. The folks over at <a href="http://www.carbonequity.info/index.html" target="_blank">CarbonEquity</a> had already published a sequel, <a href="http://www.carbonequity.info/PDFs/targets.pdf" target="_blank">Target Practice</a>, which talks about the way we are setting our climate change targets and whether or not it makes sense to do it that way. They offer a couple of alternative possibilities.</p>
<p>One such alternative is that if a complete melt of the Arctic Sea ice over summer, which has no effect on sea levels, could trigger a collapse of the Greenland ice sheet which <em>could</em> affect sea levels, maybe one target would be to keep the chance of a complete Arctic melt down to one in a million. NASA decided in the sixties that keeping the odds of a Saturn rocket crashing into population centres at 1 to 1 million was about right. Why not apply the same odds to our climate change debate? This eliminates the politics and injects a definable, science based outcome.</p>
<p>So if we agree that losing Greenland's ice sheet is bad because it means 5 - 10 metres or so of sea level rise, and losing the Arctic Sea ice will likely trigger this, how about we keep the odds of a complete Arctic Sea meltdown at 1 to 1 million? Here's how we've been doing since 1979 and where we're headed now:</p>
<p>

</p>
<p>If you have a moment, follow the link to <a href="http://www.carbonequity.info/PDFs/targets.pdf" target="_blank">Target Practice</a>. It's much more upbeat than <a href="http://www.carbonequity.info/PDFs/Arctic.pdf" target="_blank">The Big Melt.</a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://blog.greens.org.nz/index.php/2007/12/14/anz-campaign-goes-international/</url><title>ANZ campaign goes international</title><date>2007-12-14 01:50:30.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>The campaign against ANZ for providing finance to Rimbunan Hijau in PNG, to enable RH to carry out illegal and unsustainable logging, has linked up with the campaign against ANZ as the potential financier to the Gunns pulp mill in Tasmania. We had protests in NZ while the greens in Oz had similar protests earlier this week. The Sydney Morning Herald had a good <a href="http://news.smh.com.au/greenies-rally-against-anz-over-logging/20071212-1goa.html">article </a>on it.</p>
<blockquote>
<h3>Greenies rally against ANZ over logging</h3>
<ul>
<li class="adSpot-toolbox">
<h3>December 12, 2007 - 8:12PM</h3>
</li>
</ul>
<p><!--articleDetails--></p>
<p class="articleExtras-wrap"><!-- adSpotIsland --></p>
<p id="adSpotIsland" class="islandad">Environmentalists staged protests outside ANZ Bank branches in Australia and New Zealand calling on the bank not to fund logging operations in Tasmania and Papua New Guinea.</p>
<p>The Wilderness Society of Tasmania and New Zealand's Green Party organised the protests to coincide with the United Nations climate change conference in Bali, Indonesia.</p>
<p>Wilderness Society spokesman Paul Oosting said logging and land-clearing in Tasmania already accounted for at least 30 per cent of the state's greenhouse gas emissions and a proposed new pulp mill was conservatively estimated to add two per cent to Australia's annual emissions.</p>
<p>"Both governments and banks have a global responsibility to help cut greenhouse gas emissions," he said.</p>
<p>"This starts with refusing support for destructive logging practices and moving to help protect intact native forests."</p>
<p>In New Zealand, Green Party co-leader Russel Norman called on customers to pressure the ANZ banking group, which has been named as a potential financier of the proposed pulp mill, not to "provide finance for forest destruction" in the state.</p>
<p>Oosting said Tasmanian forests were some of the most "carbon rich" in the world and ancient trees 70-80 metres tall were being felled in the state's Styx Valley, in a woodchip-driven logging operation.</p>
<p>He said the proposed new pulp mill would consume up to 4.5 million tonnes of wood a year, creating greenhouse gases equivalent to putting an extra 2.3 million cars on the road annually.</p>
<p>Oosting said the Malaysian company Rimbunan Hijau, an ANZ client, was carrying out logging in Papua New Guinea that had been condemned internationally.</p>
<p>Australian Greens leader Bob Brown said: "ANZ has a fantastic opportunity to behave as a good corporate citizen. It must take a strong stance against bankrolling the disastrous proposed Tasmanian mill and refuse to support the unsustainable and illegal logging of rainforests in Papua New Guinea."</p></blockquote>
<p><!-- Copyright Sign --></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://blog.greens.org.nz/index.php/2007/12/14/melchester-rovers-%e2%80%93-playing-and-trading-fair/</url><title>Melchester Rovers – playing and trading fair</title><date>2007-12-13 19:49:56.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Dunedin football team, the Melchester Rovers is the first team on this side of the world to exclusively use fair trade footballs for training and match play. Dave Peck, the promoter of fair trade sports balls and a Green Party member, plays in goal for Melchester and was interested to discover that fair trade balls cost the same to supply as traditional balls, except for the profit going to the communities that make them rather than the sports stars who promote them.</p>
<p><img src="http://blog.greens.org.nz/wp-content/melchester-photo-jul-07.jpg" alt="Melchester Rovers 07" /></p>
<p>The production of soccer balls has long suffered from the abusive use of child labour in sweatshops.  Children are used by many of the factories that manufacture balls as cheaper, have small hands and eyesight that has not been ruined by stitching.</p>
<p>Peck, the Rovers' British import, says he was given the task of replacing a ball that got lost in the harbour - not an issue that Cristiano Ronaldo faces but common enough in Dunedin.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“I searched for a local supplier of fair trade balls and after not finding one locally, I then discovered a supplier in Australia, to whom I contacted to order some training balls. A conversation eschewed and at the end of it I'd started importing them, with a shipment of a hundred balls heading over!”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.etiko.co.nz/">Etiko</a>, the supplier of the balls, several challenges were posed when developing fair trade balls:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Initially child labour had to be stopped while preventing children from seeking work in other areas.  Another challenge was to maintain the right of women to work.  In strict Islamic society football stitching is one of the few jobs readily available to women, as it can be done from home...</p>
<p>The answer to the problem of child labour is surprisingly simple: pay workers properly! If parents of several children are forced to work for for wages that are so low they cannot support their families, then clearly children will be encouraged to work to bolster the family income... no parent would make their child work if they did not have to.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p align="center"><img src="http://blog.greens.org.nz/wp-content/beckham-flyer-etiko-aug-07.jpg" alt="Etiko Beckham Flyer" /></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/climate-change-time-to-stop-indulging.html</url><title>Climate change: time to stop indulging the US</title><date>2007-12-14 10:30:00.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Negotiators are Currently meeting at the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Bali in an effort to establish the framework for a successor to the Kyoto Protocol.  But as with previous talks on the subject, we're seeing the usual games, with the US (aided and abetted by its reliable stooges Canada and Japan) <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/2/story.cfm?c_id=2&objectid=10482316">attempting to disrupt the talks</a> and prevent them from agreeing to a ballpark target for future emissions reductions by developed nations of 25 - 40%.  They're also objecting to a statementthat emissions must peak and decline within a decade.  Both positions are mainstream scientific opinion, endorsed by the IPCC in its latest report, which makes a mockery of the US's claim to want "science driven" policy.

<p>The US does this at every meeting.  They play no constructive role in negotiations, but attempt to wreck them and prevent others from reaching any positive agreement.  It's time we stopped indulging them, or pandering to their belief in their own relevance.  The US is run by a lame-duck President leading a lame-duck administration, and everyone knows policy will change when he leaves office in January 2009.  If the current US administration will not participate meaningfully in these negotiations, then the rest of the world should simply work around them, reach a strong agreement, and let Bush's successor join up when they enter office.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/americans-love-torture.html</url><title>Americans love torture</title><date>2007-12-13 13:24:11.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Yesterday, in pointing out that <a href="http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/nightmare-is-real.html">the US has already tortured an innocent man</a>, I noted that the US people either do not know or do not care that this has happened.  A reader responded by pointing me at <a href="http://edition.cnn.com/POLLSERVER/results/virtual/36436">yesterday's CNN poll</a>, the results of which speak for themselves:
<blockquote>
<i><b>Are there circumstances in which waterboarding of prisoners is acceptable?</b>

<p><b>Yes:</b> 55% 52,690<br />
<b>No:</b> 44% 42,219 </i>
</blockquote>

It's not just the Bush Adminstration - it's the American people.  So much for the US's claim to be part of the civilised world.

<p>(Oh, and just in case anyone wants to argue ignorance, this was apparently run alongside a poll asking "Do you consider waterboarding to be torture?".  <a href="http://fryska.blogspot.com/2007/12/unbelievable.html">80% of respondents answered "yes"</a>).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/oi-aussie-get-out-of-it-bro.html</url><title>Oi! Aussie – get out of it bro!</title><date>2007-12-14 07:41:26.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2F8xl_qjZI/AAAAAAAACQc/Ty7oO_NItRg/s1600-h/690062.jpg"><img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2F8xl_qjZI/AAAAAAAACQc/Ty7oO_NItRg/s400/690062.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143529440888393106" /></a><br /><b>alt tv/fleet fm breakfast news comment</b><br /><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322766a12.html">Airbus landing Antarctic milestone</a><br /><i>Australia has scored an Antarctic coup by successfully landing a commercial airliner at its polar base. Its success has major implications for the Christchurch based polar operation which each summer despatches military aircraft southward. A statement from the Australian Antarctic Division said the Airbus A319 landed on the purpose-built Wilkins Runway, around 70 kilometres from Casey station, late on Sunday night and returned to Hobart early on Monday.</i> <br /><br />Ummm, why are the bloody Australians opening up Antarctica to Commercial aircraft with specially built runways? Isn’t this type of development the exact opposite of what we should be doing when we look at the effects of global warming? So as a comparison, I wonder what’s happening in the Arctic right now? <br /><br /><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322897a12.html">Arctic ice cap vanishing at record rate</a><br /><i>Arctic ice at the North Pole melted at a record rate in the summer of 2007, the latest sign that climate change has accelerated in recent years, climate scientists said. "In 2007, we had off-the-charts warming," Michael Steele, an oceanographer at the University of Washington, said at the 2007 meeting of the American Geophysical Union, where 15,000 researchers have gathered to discuss earthquakes, water resources, and climate change. It was an ominous summer for the Arctic region, where for the first time in recorded history, ships sailed across the Arctic Ocean in water that had been part of the polar ice cap, said Donald Perovich of the US Army Cold Regions Research and Engineering Laboratory in New Hampshire.<br />While in the summer of 1980 the North Pole was covered by an ice sheath about the size of the continental United States, this summer the ice would not have covered the states west of the Mississippi River, he added.</i> <br /><br />And the Australian reaction to that is to open Antarctica up to commercial aircraft? Great.<br /><a href="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2FqqF_qjXI/AAAAAAAACQM/Oxpmr1NakgA/s1600-h/header04.gif"><img src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2FqqF_qjXI/AAAAAAAACQM/Oxpmr1NakgA/s400/header04.gif" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143509520830074226" /></a>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/tasers-needed-to-safeguard-lives-says.html</url><title>Tasers needed to safeguard lives, says police union</title><date>2007-12-14 07:10:25.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2F1el_qjYI/AAAAAAAACQU/sHS5yifnP40/s1600-h/zappbranigan.jpg"><img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2F1el_qjYI/AAAAAAAACQU/sHS5yifnP40/s400/zappbranigan.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143521417889484162" /></a><br /><b>alt tv/fleet fm breakfast news comment</b><br /><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&objectid=10482166">Tasers needed to safeguard lives, says police union</a><br /><i>As the deadline approaches for police to report the evaluation of their Taser trial to Commissioner Howard Broad, Police Association president Greg O'Connor has made a plea for the adoption of the "less than lethal" device. Opponents to police being issued with Tasers are ignoring the realities of modern policing, Mr O'Connor said. Staff are to report to Mr Broad by today on how their 12-month Taser stun guns trial went, and he will make the final decision on their use. Last month a United Nations report described them as a "form of torture". The UN Committee Against Torture said it was worried by the use of Tasers.</i><br /><br />The issue is do you want the Police to have unchecked access to a weapon that isn’t ‘lethal’ but can be used by Police on whom they like with no independent committee over-seeing Police use. Our slower friends in the community will howl that it’s safer to be shot by a taser than a gun, but those slower friends miss the whole point which is that we don’t have a way of keeping the Police in check if we give them tasers, at this point our slower friends mumble something about you being anti-police and they rock quietly in the corner muttering angrily, typing on kiwiblogh. I’m afraid after the year the Police have had, they are asking for MORE powers? Sorry Greg, give me that independent police complaints authority and you can have your tasers.<br /><a href="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2FqqF_qjXI/AAAAAAAACQM/Oxpmr1NakgA/s1600-h/header04.gif"><img src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2FqqF_qjXI/AAAAAAAACQM/Oxpmr1NakgA/s400/header04.gif" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143509520830074226" /></a>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/were-you-wondering-why-the-democrats-havent-moved-to-impeach-bushcheneyfor-torturing/</url><title>were you wondering why the democrats haven’t moved to impeach bush/cheney..?..for torturing..?</title><date>2007-12-13 20:40:19.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
this could settle your query..
"..US Congressional Candidate Cindy Sheehan today called upon Nancy Pelosi to respond to a story printed in the December 9 Washington Post which claims that the Speaker of the House was present in a 2002 meeting..
..where four members of Congress were given a virtual tour of the CIA's overseas detention sites..and [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/200065292/knol_project_google_experiment.php</url><title>Knols Project: Google Experimenting With User Generated Encyclopedic Pages</title><date>2007-12-14 03:05:45.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><font>
</font>The official <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/12/encouraging-people-to-contribute.html">Google blog</a> has a post tonight about a new project that's in closed, private beta.  The program is called Knols, or "units of knowledge."  Knols participants will write reference pages on any topic, using a Google content creation tool apparently in the works, and those pages will be highlighted in Google search results.  Authors will choose whether they want ads to appear and will receive a "substantial revenue share."
</p><p>I think this is going to be a game changer.  Check out this sample page below.</p><p><center><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/thumb.png" /></center></p><p>
Competing Knols pages on the same topic will be judged by reader votes and the Google Search Quality process.  There will be reader commenting, the ability to add additional information and more social features.  It won't be a walled garden but will live on the open web.  Attribution will be substantial and Google is presumably working with high-profile topic specialists on the Knol project.
</p>

<p>
Somewhere Jason Calacanis, his soul icy as it is, is aglow knowing that his <a href="http://mahalo.com">Mahalo</a> concept has been validated by a company that's arguably the most important in the last 100 years.  Likewise, there's probably some melancholy toasts due at <a href="http://squidoo.com">Squidoo</a> headquarters.  Those companies may or may not survive but the real battle will probably be with Wikipedia.  Google-built pages may be the only pages that have a bigger advantage in search than the widely linked Wikipedia reference pages.</p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=DflMnd"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=DflMnd" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=dAUQYHC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=dAUQYHC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=b50M3uC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=b50M3uC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=o6GuFVc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=o6GuFVc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=9WTT4Qc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=9WTT4Qc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=wlVy4nc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=wlVy4nc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=HNNu0WC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=HNNu0WC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/200065292" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://duckenvy.blogspot.com/2007/12/blair-still-brown-nosing-bush.html</url><title>Blair still brown nosing Bush.</title><date>2007-12-13 13:48:50.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
If you thought Blair's retirement would lead him to extract his nose from Bush's ass somewhat, you would be sadly mistaken. In this embarrassment of a <a href="http://www.tv3.co.nz/VideoBrowseAll/WorldVideo/tabid/313/articleID/41563/cat/55/Default.aspx#video"> video </a> Blair speaks to Barney and Miss Beazley, the Presidents Scottish Terriers. What a sad pathetic little man.<div class="blogger-post-footer">http://digg.com/submit?phase=2&url;= <$BlogItemPermalinkURL$>&title;=<$BlogItemTitle$>

http://del.icio.us/post?v=4&noui;&jump;=close
&url;=<$BlogItemPermalinkURL$>
&title;=<$BlogItemTitle$></div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/abouttown/2007/12/14/celebrity-beauty-and-why-it-matters-at-least-to-them/</url><title>Celebrity beauty and why it matters - at least to them. . .</title><date>2007-12-14 02:42:42.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p> <img width="200" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/britney.jpg" height="241" />  <img width="200" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/posh.jpg" height="241" /></p>
<p>In this flash-trash world, of mindless celebrity the only thing that matters, I hate to say it, but it's the truth - is what you look like.</p>
<p>You can wet your pants (Fergie), you can get wasted (Amy Winehouse), you can steal, (Winona Ryder), you can be violent (Naomi Campbell) you can get drug addicted, (Nicole Richie) you can do porn, (Paris Hilton), you can rape (Erroll Flynn), you can be a pederast (Michael Jackson), and yup, you can kill people too (Phil Spectre).</p>
<p>The only thing you cannot do is look bad (weird is OK) and THAT is Britney Spears' real crime.</p>
<p>"Nooooooo..." I hear you intone into your keyboard: ". . .mmmmwhat about Oprah?"</p>
<p>Yes OK, Oprah is no size 10. But Oprah is in a different category because she is so very, very smart.</p>
<p>If Britney didn't look like such an ordinary, normal, frumpy person, if she was as svelte as Paris, and as cool as Mary Kate, sure she'd get dissed for being a lousy mum but she wouldn't face scorn like she is now.<br />
It's horrible but it's true. The real issue behind her bad press is that she's a hearty s12 and she's got the worst dress sense in the history of Hollywood.</p>
<p>Us human beans have always been visually driven but we are now living in the ultimate appearanc-ist culture and really, it's not so nice.<br />
A variation on this 'appearance crime'-theme is Posh Spice and HER bad press. I feel really sorry for Mrs B. No matter what she does, she gets slammed. It must be frightening picking up the paper because the spin that's put on things is wild. Just recently the reformed Spice Girls appeared for Victoria's Secret with Baby in a dress Britney had worn in 2002 and Geri in a dress Britney had worn in 2004. The girls are dressed by a stylist who would almost definitely have gotten the sack for this "embarrassment" but somehow poor old Mrs B got the blame for having supposedly evilly orchestrated the (ultimately 'who-gives-a-****' ) situation.</p>
<p>I am convinced that:</p>
<p>* If she had nice fake bosoms like everyone else instead of upturned cupcakes on her chest, and . . .</p>
<p>* If she had long hair instead of short hair and</p>
<p>* If she had a smile instead of a stare (she hates her teeth)</p>
<p>she would be loved and lauded. . . .</p>
<p>And she would never have been blamed for that stylist stuff up.</p>
<p>Hell of a shallow world isn't it!</p>
<p><em>(Photos by Reuters)</em></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=860</url><title>National and the wage gap</title><date>2007-12-13 01:24:35.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>I see National's <a href="http://national.org.nz/Article.aspx?ArticleID=11591">complaining</a> <a href="http://national.org.nz/Article.aspx?ArticleID=11592">about</a> the wage gap between New Zealand and Australia again. As usual they have no answers on what to do about it other than to blindly hope that tax cuts for the rich will lead to economic growth and somehow it’ll all trickle down into the ordinary worker's pay packet. Ever feel like someone’s trying to <a href="http://national.org.nz/Article.aspx?ArticleId=4224">sell you a dud</a> for a second time?</p>
<p>Because as anyone who lived through the 90s can tell you, National has a <a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=527">shameful record on wages</a>, as this graph of median wage growth shows:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/nominal-large-revised.jpg"><img src="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/10/nominal-small-revised.jpg" alt="nominal-small-revised.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>The reason for this is simple. When National and its allied employer groups introduced the Employment Contracts Act in 1991 it was deliberately designed to reduce the ability of workers to bargain for better wages through their unions. This was done in a number of ways, but one of the most effective was its restrictions on the ability of unions to negotiate collective agreements across an entire industry.</p>
<p>This meant each collective agreement had to be negotiated on an enterprise (site by site) level, which both moved the balance of power firmly towards the employer and encouraged companies to compete against each other on labour costs. The result was a race to the bottom. Workers lost conditions, wages stagnated or fell for the majority of workers and collective bargaining was largely replaced by the market. Productivity suffered as the low cost of labour made capital investment uneconomical.</p>
<p>So when National talks about the need to lift wages and improve productivity, just remember who it was that slashed Kiwis’ take home pay in the 90s and put us in the position we’re in today. And don't for a second think they wouldn't <a href="http://national.org.nz/Article.aspx?ArticleId=4224">go back there</a> if given half a chance.</p>
<p>The challenge now for Labour is to finish the job they started in 2000 and strengthen the Employment Relations Act to restore effective industry bargaining. Wage growth has improved under the ERA, but it’s not nearly enough if we want to catch up with Australia.</p>
<p>As Council of Trade Unions economist Peter Conway <a href="http://union.org.nz/news/2007/new-years-resolution-fix-low-wages-to-help-stem-migration-to-australia">points out</a>, leaving it to the market alone hasn’t worked:</p>
<blockquote><p>"New Zealand now has a structural problem of low wages, and the 30% wage gap with Australia will only be closed through more widespread industry wide collective bargaining, supported by ongoing improvements in productivity.</p>
<p>“Wages were broadly comparable with Australia until the late 1980s, but then fell to 60% by 2002, according to Treasury analysis.</p>
<p>“Similarly, in 1978 New Zealand and Australian workers had about the same amount of capital per hour worked but by 2002, capital intensity in Australia was over 50 percent greater than in New Zealand.</p>
<p>“The CTU agrees that lifting productivity is essential to lift incomes on a sustainable basis.  However this must be accompanied by effective measures to ensure the benefits are shared, with a strong minimum code and effective industry bargaining.”
 </p></blockquote>
<p>The next election may well be fought on the wage gap between New Zealand and Australia. It’s up to Labour to show the electorate which party’s really looking out for the interests of working New Zealanders.</p>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=860&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_860" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
