<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Nz</title>
<item>
<url>http://lindsaymitchell.blogspot.com/2007/12/inconsistency.html</url><title>Inconsistency</title><date>2007-12-14 06:53:20.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/thepress/4322687a24035.html">Here</a> is a married couple charged with 'P' offences.  Not convicted. The judge says that it will be a long time before the trial takes place. They are remanded in custody and CYFS take their four children aged 4 weeks to 13 years.<br /><br />The thought occurred to me that Sue Bradford has a bill which would allow mothers to keep their very young children in prison. Some already do but this bill wants to extend the period and expand the practice.<br /><br />Here is a mother of a month-old baby being separated from it when she hasn't even been convicted of an offence.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/12/gp-file-2-greenpeace-radicals.html</url><title>GP File 2 Greenpeace Radicals Indoctrinate Schoolkids With "Climate Change" Propaganda</title><date>2007-12-13 22:05:03.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Greenpeace in conjunction with Oxfam and Forest&Bird; is brainwashing schoolkids in "<em>Climate Change</em>" propaganda.<br /><br /><a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_JtTfGekhAhY/R2D0LHFkbTI/AAAAAAAABGI/pWQFg7jws7U/s1600-h/DSC00582.preview.jpg"><img src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_JtTfGekhAhY/R2D0LHFkbTI/AAAAAAAABGI/pWQFg7jws7U/s400/DSC00582.preview.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143379246175251762" /></a><br />For the last month, a bio-fuel powered bus has been <a href="http://www.bethechange.org.nz/bus-tour">touring New Zealand high schools </a>indoctrinating teenagers in Greenpeace's scaremongering "<em>global warming</em>" agenda.<br /><br /><a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_JtTfGekhAhY/R2D0bHFkbUI/AAAAAAAABGQ/bKTt3NnhIiA/s1600-h/6b853f656834433cbafe.jpg"><img src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_JtTfGekhAhY/R2D0bHFkbUI/AAAAAAAABGQ/bKTt3NnhIiA/s400/6b853f656834433cbafe.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143379521053158722" /></a><br />Worse, Greenpeace's <a href="http://www.bethechange.org.nz/">Be the Change </a>project is staffed by radical extremists with ties to some of this countries most militant activists, including the <a href="http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/11/not-so-happy-valley-campers-green-party.html">Save Happy Valley Coalition </a>and the "Urewera 17".<br /><br />Of the three known bus borne activists;<br /><br /><a href="http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/12/gp-file-1-police-affadavit-links.html">Kristin Gillies </a>has been a leading member of the anarchist lead Save Happy Valley Coalition and has allegedly attended at least one "<em>quasi military</em>" training camp in the Ureweras.<br /><br />Jo McVeagh was a founder member of the SHVC in 2004 and has since worked closely with socialist and anarchist organisations.<br /><br />Tia Taurere has close ties to several of those arrested in the October 15 "<em>Urewera 17</em>" anti terror raids and has since been an active campaigner for their cause.<br /><br />These three activists are being paid by Greenpeace to indoctrinate teenagers from Cape Reinga to Bluff.<br /><br />How many parents would allow their children to hear Greenpeace's dodgy propaganda, if they knew the pedigrees of those promoting it?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pacificempire.org.nz/2007/12/14/living-in-a-police-state/</url><title>Living in a police state?</title><date>2007-12-14 04:31:15.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&amp;objectid=10480731">"Cafe fined for allowing smoking," 6th December 2007, NZ Herald</a></li>
</ul>
<blockquote><p>
Popular Wellington cafe Fidel's has been fined $600 for allowing smoking on-site... The<br />
cafe's smoking area at the rear of the cafe did not comply with new<br />
smoking laws because it was not open, the Health Ministry said.<br />
Co-owner Roger Young said the rules were difficult to interpret."We're living in a police state. You can't do anything any more."</p></blockquote>
<p>I have a certain amount of sympathy for Mr. Young - as the owner of a small business, he is no doubt suffers under the many, many regulations, taxes and assorted rules and bylaws of the government and the city council.</p>
<p>But does he seriously not see the irony of complaining about our "police state" when his cafe celebrates and endorses a <em>genuine</em> police state, and takes its name from one of the world's oldest tyrants?</p>
<p>One of the things I hate about Wellington are the myriad of cafes celebrating communist Cuba. Fidel's of course, but also Cubita, Havana (although they have a great selection of NZ craft beers), Ernesto (featuring a shrine to that sadistic killer, Ernesto "Che" Guevara) and so on. I could also name Revolution Coffee and Pravda. No cafes celebrating Mao, Hitler or Pol Pot, of course.</p>
<p>They can't point to the original naming of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuba_Street,_Wellington">Cuba Street </a>as an excuse - the street was actually named for a sailing ship which visited Wellington a century before the Cuban revolution.<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cuba_Street,_Wellington"><br />
</a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://silentrunning.tv/?p=2567</url><title>Gore tells the truth!</title><date>2007-12-13 22:32:04.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Probably completely <a href="http://www.cbsnews.com/stories/2007/12/13/ap/tech/main3613993.shtml">inadvertent</a>.<br />
<blockquote>"We can't afford to wait another five years"</p></blockquote>
<p>And he's absolutely right. If Al and his fellow enviro-cultists can't successfully exploit the chicken little hysteria they've whipped up over the past few years, data utterly refuting their claims of doom <a href="http://silentrunning.tv/?p=2530">may actually come to light</a> exposing how full of crap their entire excuse for insisting upon, ney, <i>demanding</i>, humanity's self-infliction of their socialist agenda. The fact that Gore's been lying is a <a href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/story?id=3719791&#038;page=1">matter of record</a>.<br />
<div align="center"><img src="http://silentrunning.tv/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/SUBMIT.jpg" /><br /><i>Resistance is futile</i></div>
<p>It'll take a while for the complete debunking to take place - primarily because so many people will have to admit they were hornswaggled, bamboozled, conned, gyped, snookered, and just plain suckered by faux moralization wowsers, in concert with an assortment of finger in the wind politicos, <a href="http://epw.senate.gov/public/index.cfm?FuseAction=Minority.Blogs&#038;ContentRecord_id=d5c3c93f-802a-23ad-4f29-fe59494b48a6&#038;Issue_id=">empire building bureaucrats</a>, <a href="http://reason.com/news/show/123869.html">wealth distribution graft-master third worlders</a>, plus sundry 'carbon credit' scheme hucksters, all facilitated by psuedo-sympathetic journalists whose career path was probably determined by their profound failure to grok science and mathematics. </p>
<p>2008 promises to be a very interesting juncture, for this subject about which "the debate is over." I can hardly wait.</p>
<p><b>::Update::</b> Global Warming a Trojan Horse for a Socialist agenda? Sure - and the bigger the Socialist agenda, the <a href="http://hotair.com/archives/2007/12/13/video-teacher-teacher-ill-raise-my-hand-to-global-warming/">more useful it is</a>!
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stephenfranks.co.nz/?p=231</url><title>Wrong result, wrong excuses, but legally mainstream reasoning on McNamara parole.</title><date>2007-12-14 03:50:58.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>The Parole Board has just released a legally defensible, but morally wrong decision to let Peter McNamara out on parole after Christmas. Previously they made a <a target="_blank" href="http://www.paroleboard.govt.nz/media-and-publications/decisions/mcnamara-peter-mana-28-08-07.html" title="Parole Board decision">morally correct but illogical decision</a> to  turn down his application for home detention. They kept him in prison for a 1989 rape until now, when he's served a bit over 2 years 6 months of the 7-year sentence.</p>
<p>The issue was whether they could take into account the outrageousness of gutting a 7 year sentence, to refuse to release him, when he is not a threat to anyone in the community. They faced an impossible task. The government tried to write the law to obscure what they were telling the Board, but the original intention was clear -"<em>it's not your business to worry about justice, you must let them out if you feel they are not a risk. If that makes a mockery of sentencing, and insults the victims, that's not your problem".</em></p>
<p>Select Committee changes confounded that simplicity. For example the Board is told to consider the interests of victims, but Labour and the Greens would not allow those interests to be defined or give them equal weight with the instruction to release. I do not apologise for the resulting confusion.</p>
<p>The Board is bound by the Court of Appeal's decision in Reid et al v New Zealand Parole Board (CA 247/05) ...<em>"although considerations of general deterrence are relevant when setting the nominal sentence and minimum periods of imprisonment and in determining whether to grant leave to apply for home detention, they are not relevant when the Parole Board is considering applications for release on parole or home detention".</em></p>
<p><font size="2">In the decision on home detention the Board raised something called 'personal deterrence' and the victim's views, and even the public concern for victims expressed in the 92% Withers petition for tougher sentencing to justify holding a man that nobody thinks will offend again.</font><font size="2">They were morally right, but the reasoning was crap.</font><font size="2">Now their reasoning is better but the outcome is wrong.</p>
<p>There are arguments to get around the Court of Appeal decision. They could have said "<em>we are not letting you out because it would make a mockery of justice. If people believe that court-ordered sentences are nonsense, they will feel that crime does pay, that honesty is not the best policy, that only mugs obey the law. That loss of confidence in justice, in the basic fairness of the law is very dangerous to everyone in the community."</em></p>
<p>They could have set it out like this (for appeal proofing purposes) " <em>we are not trying to deter bad people, we are trying to reassure good people - to reassure them that it is worth assisting the Police, that it is correct to teach your children that crime will not pay, to show that the long arm of the law will ensure the price of crime is paid".</em></p>
<p>They could have had good academic support. The safety of the community is dictated by the crime rate, not individual release decisions. And there is strong evidence that the crime rate is most affected by what people believe is the prevailing norm. If it is generally not done to break the rules - few do. People on the crime margin are sensitive to what appears to be the prevailing climate. They should be the preoccupation of the system. Every element should be driven by its influence on those who could offend but do not (in low crime societies), or can and do (in high crime societies). Our religious forebears might have expressed it simply - the system should focus on those in temptation, not those who've made the decision to be bad.</p>
<p>Instead ours is all focussed on those who have offended, and the vain task of turning them around once they have crossed the threshold. The international evidence says it is a waste of time.</p>
<p>"Broken windows" is the shorthand name for the theory which underlay New York's dramatic crime turn-around. The police stopped concentrating on serious crime. Instead they enforced all the small laws (like those against shoplifting and begging, and leaping the turnstiles in subways, even jaywalking and littering. They insisted that graffiti be cleaned up immediately because it sent the message that rules do not apply. The result, in short order, was to cut every category of serious crime by more than 70% and the murder rate by 80% (in some years parts of provincial New Zealand now have a higher murder rate).</p>
<p>Even if they could not step outside the NZ establishment orthodoxy enough to raise those arguments I would have respected the Parole Board much more if they'd simply said to the government in the decision- "<em>Change the unjust law. We are going to find every way we can not to apply it the way you want. We are sick of carrying the can for your dishonest criminal statutes. We will not tell the victim who is comforted by a 7 year sentence that sentencing is a calculated lie, a charade to be undone by parole</em>" .</p>
<p>There is nothing unprecedented in a court or judicial body telling the poor litigants not to blame them when a law does not work, and asking Parliament to fix it.</p>
<p>I have often excused the Parole Board for sad cases because the law is bad. But I've been too charitable. They've never called for reform.</p>
<p>At the Graeme Burton enquiry they should have said <em>" We are ashamed of ourselves. There have been too many Graeme Burtons. We have not spoken out about the impossible law we are applying. From now on we will".</em></p>
<p>In this McNamara decision they initially told a few insiders who can understand the code- <em>"this law is hopeless, and we are now going to ignore it". </em> Now I would not let them out of the dock.</p>
<p>I hope this is appealed.</p>
<p></font></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://briefingroom.typepad.com/the_briefing_room/2007/12/when-is-a-const.html</url><title>When is a constitution not a constitution?</title><date>2007-12-13 18:33:40.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div><p>Answer: <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/europe/7141651.stm">When it is a treaty</a>.</p>

<p>The ill fated EU constitution that was resoundedly rejected by European voters&nbsp; has reappeared in a reduced form and been signed into force as a treaty. </p>

<p>The voters who turned out to oppose the &quot;constitution&quot; felt uncomfortable about handing over sovereignty to Brussels. But it will happen anyway.</p>

<blockquote><p>The treaty is a slimmed-down version of the European constitution, with a more modest name and without any reference to EU symbols such as the flag and anthem.</p>

<p>

It is meant to ease decision-making, by scrapping national vetoes in some 50 policy areas, including sensitive ones such as police and judicial co-operation. </p>

<p>There will also be a foreign policy chief, controlling a big budget and thousands of diplomats and officials, and a permanent EU president appointed for up to five years.&nbsp; </p></blockquote><p>&quot;Ease decision making&quot; huh. What that really&nbsp; means is that if the people in a place like Slovakia (say) don't like what the gnomes in Brussels have decided for them tough cookies.</p>

<p>Ironically the actual signing of the treaty which will become known as the Treaty of Lisbon highlights some of the absurdities of EU&nbsp; politics.</p>

<p>Under the Treaty of Nice (2000) all&nbsp; summits of EU leaders must take place in Brussels.&nbsp; Thus after congregating in Lisbon for yesterday's formal signing (Portugal currently holds the rotating EU presidency)&nbsp; all the EU leaders and their foreign ministers decamped and flew to Brussels for the&nbsp; summit scheduled for today. </p>

<p>Which all seems rather hypocritical in these days of angst over mankind's carbon footprint.</p>

<p>Though to be fair the Prime ministers of Belgium, the Netherlands and
Luxembourg did plane-pool as a gesture of social responsibility.</p></div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5483</url><title>Surprise, surprise he did it again</title><date>2007-12-13 20:22:28.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4323146a10.html" rel="nofollow">Man detained at home bashes victim again - New Zealand, world, sport, business <span class="amp">&amp;</span> entertainment news on&nbsp;Stuff.co.nz</a></p>
<p>What sort of a fool judge gives a man convicted of domestic violence home&nbsp;detention?????!!!!</p>
<p><span class="caps">FFS</span> He was convicted of bashing his partner and then gets sentenced to home&nbsp;detention?</p>
<p>That could be considered a cruel and unusual punishment for both of them. The woman for having to have the creep at home in the first place and the man for having to be with someone he think is a punching bag&nbsp;24/7.</p>
<p>I mean really, cases like this show we have lost the plot in Corrections and Justice.....who is the Justice Minister again?...oh that's right Annette "Commonsense"&nbsp;King</p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5480</url><title>Starship reluctant to give back cash</title><date>2007-12-13 19:09:39.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482299&amp;ref=rss" rel="nofollow">Starship reluctant to give back cash</a> - <i>The Starship Foundation won't return the $158,000 given to it by New Zealand First leader Winston Peters unless the gift was unlawful.<br />
And there is no suggestion that that is the case.<br />
Mr Peters gave the hospital a cheque on...</i> [<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/" rel="nofollow"><span class="caps">NZ</span> Politics</a>]
</p>
<p>
Winston needs to come&nbsp;clean.
</p>
<p>
Firstly the word about town is that there has been a little bit of laundering going on. A well known business man in Auckland is known to have paid some money into a certain solicitors trust account that was then paid to another solicitors trust account and then onto <span class="caps">NZ</span> First, which Winston then gace to Starship.  This is almost similar to the same methods by which a certain litigious <span class="caps">MP</span> pays his legal&nbsp;bills.
</p>
<p>
So Winston needs to come&nbsp;clean.
</p>
<ol>
<li>Where did the money come&nbsp;from?</li>
<li>Who was his secret&nbsp;backer/s?</li>
<li>If it came from their supposed term deposits, show us the break&nbsp;certificates?</li>
<li>Who is getting the $60,000 tax break from the&nbsp;donation
	</li>
</ol>
<p>
It is not acceptable that this level of subterfuge is being used by a politician who is at the same time supporting the destruction of our democracy through the rushed passing of the draconian Electoral Finance&nbsp;Bill.
</p>
<p>
It is time you fessed up&nbsp;Winston.
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://blog.greens.org.nz/index.php/2007/12/13/this-summer-monsanto-is-back/</url><title>This summer Monsanto is back</title><date>2007-12-13 01:46:09.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>This summer, once you are bored with the beach, the picnics and the bike rides (and maybe the occasional game of monopoly while you wait for the rain to clear), you might be looking for something else to do, something retro - maybe a little bit 2001/02.  Because one of the international superstars of the time is back; not Eminem or Avril Lavigne, but everybody's favourite corporate food producer, <a href="http://www.truthabouttrade.org/article.asp?id=8615">Monsanto</a>.  So it's time again to start lobbying to stop GE coming into New Zealand.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.foodstandards.govt.nz/newsroom/mediareleases/mediareleases2007/12december2007fsanzw3791.cfm">Food Standards Australia New Zealand</a> (FSANZ) has just invited people to comment on an application by Monsanto to permit the sale and use in Australia and New Zealand of food derived from a new genetically modified variety of corn, MON 89034. </p>
<p>According to <a href="http://www.foodstandards.gov.au/_srcfiles/A595_DAR_MON89034_Corn_FINAL.pdf">FSANZ</a> (links to pdf):</p>
<blockquote><p>MON 89034 corn has been genetically modified to be protected against feeding damage caused by the larvae of certain insect pest species.  Protection is achieved through the expression in the plant of insecticidal proteins derived from Bacillus thuringiensis, a common soil bacterium.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>Corn line MON 89034 is intended to be grown in North America.  However, once commercialised, corn products imported into Australia and New Zealand could contain ingredients derived from MON 89034 corn.  Approval is therefore necessary before these products may enter the Australian and New Zealand markets.</p></blockquote>
<p>FSANZ's application says it can't identify any public health or safety concerns with MON 89034, and that food derived from MON 89034 corn is equivalent to other commercially available corn in terms of its safety for human consumption and nutritional adequacy.</p>
<p>Submissions need to be received by <a href="http://www.foodstandards.govt.nz/">FSANZ</a> by 6 February 2008.  At the moment FSANZ's preferred option is to approve MON 89034 corn for release.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, if you aren't keen to eat MON 89034 then the government's rejection of <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/stuff/4321810a6160.html">country of origin labelling</a> isn't going to make it any easier to distinguish between American corm imports and GM-free New Zealand grown corn products.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://jtc.blogs.com/just_left/2007/12/off-key.html</url><title>Off Key</title><date>2007-12-13 00:42:51.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div><p>This year there have been a succession of stuff ups on John Key's part, topped off at the end of it with the DVD screw up.</p>

<p>What I am interested by is that each time, Mr Key has a fairly standard response. His response is, "this is not up to my standards, we need to do better and it won't happen again."</p>

<p>That is what he said with the DVD. With the changes to health fees which failed to make the discussion document. With the health and education privatisations that were mentioned by accident. With the "War is Over" declaration.... and you remember the others.</p>

<p>It is slightly freaky to consider a man who wants to be PM whose smooth response to errors is that "this is not up to my standard."</p>

<p>The problem is, that is the standard he's living up to: evasions, delays, mistakes.</p>

<p>If he can't live up to his own (declared) standards in opposition, why would the public be reasonably able to expect him to live up to them in government? And why should they vote for a man who can't live up to his own standards, let alone theirs?</p></div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/cant-they-just-join-sca.html</url><title>Can't they just join the SCA?</title><date>2007-12-13 13:48:37.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Kiwiblogblog on <a href="http://kiwiblogblog.wordpress.com/2007/12/13/mumpsimuses-1-monarchists/">monarchists</a>:
<blockquote>
<i>In truth, monarchists are little different from those weird groups of people who form themselves into make-believe nations and call themselves President or King and bestow weighty titles on themselves and their fellow club members (”Kevin, Thane of Multar and Grand Vizier of the Royal Seat”). Monarchists and these other fantasists take all the pomp and circumstance associated with a traditional Head of State </i>very<i> seriously.

<p>A quick glance at your average monarchist site (and believe me, they’re all pretty average) and you quickly come realise they’re the kind of people who love to indulge in the full theatre of The Monarchy and all its ermine-decked foppery. They like to talk about the Liz Windsor as Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II or address themselves with full regalia - “His Excellency The Most Reverend Holiness Professor Dr The Honourable Captain Ima Plonker, KPCGS, MA(Hons) (Oxon), DipGradTechPumpAss, MRIENZ, DL, SC, RNZN(Ret.), Esq”.</i>
</blockquote>

Which is all well and good as <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Society_for_Creative_Anachronism">entertainment</a> (hell, I like to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Live_action_role-playing_game">dress up</a> and play monarchy on occasion) - but its ridiculous to suggest running a <i>government</i> that way.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/hardest-word.html</url><title>The hardest word</title><date>2007-12-13 00:35:17.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Hot on the heels of the <a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/asia-pacific/7124236.stm">ratification of Kyoto</a> and the <a href="http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/end-of-pacific-solution.html">end of the "Pacific Solution"</a> comes the demise of another icon of the Howard-era, with the new Australian government opening talks with Aboriginal leaders on the wording of an <a href="http://www.smh.com.au/news/national/how-to-say-sorry-and-heal-the-wounds/2007/12/11/1197135463459.html">apology for Austrlaia's crimes against its indigenous people</a>.  The actual apology will be delivered next year.

<p>This is a move Australia has to make. But more than that, it also needs to take concrete steps to lift the living standards of its indigenous minority, reduce racism, and enable them to be full participants in Australian society.  That's a long-term project, the work of a generation - but a formal apology is the best way to begin it.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/new-zealand-innocence-project.html</url><title>A New Zealand innocence project</title><date>2007-12-13 00:21:08.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Nine To Noon this morning had a fascinating <a href="http://www.radionz.co.nz/__data/assets/audio_item/0004/1243777/ntn-20071212-0920-Innocent_Project-wmbr.asx">interview</a> [audio, temporary] on the <a href="http://www.victoria.ac.nz/ipnz/">New Zealand Innocence Project</a>, which starts its inaugural conference tomorrow.  For those who don't know, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Innocence_Project">innocence projects</a> work to free those who have been wrongfully convicted from prison.  The movement started in the US, and focused on freeing death row inmates whose innocence could be conclusively proven due to post-trial DNA testing, but has expanded into other crimes as well.  The New Zealand version will deal with any crime where innocence can be proven, but from their <a href="http://www.victoria.ac.nz/ipnz/conference/timetable.aspx">conference timetable</a>, it looks as if Scott Watson and Peter Ellis are likely to be significant clients.

<p>No matter what you think of those individual cases, this is a project you should support.  While our justice system is predicated on the idea that it is better for a dozen guilty people to go free than see an innocent jailed, mistakes are <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arthur_Allan_Thomas">clearly</a> <a href="http://tvnz.co.nz/view/page/423466/22951">made</a>.  Currently, we have no backstop to catch these cases and work to correct the inevitable errors - we must rely on dogged defence lawyers, campaigning media, and wealthy individuals with a sense of conscience.  Having a dedicated group to help those who can make a strong case for their innocence will improve the quality of our justice system, and reduce the likelihood of innocent people serving long terms of imprisonment for crimes they did not commit.  And that is something even members of the "hang 'em high" brigade ought to support.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.philosophyetc.net/2007/12/misfit-is-relative-term.html</url><title>'Misfit' is a relative term</title><date>2007-12-13 00:43:51.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Some commenters <a href="http://feministphilosophers.wordpress.com/2007/11/29/totally-blatant-sexism-in-philosophy/#comment-4141">here</a>  complain about how "Social misfits are really rife in philosophy." It can certainly be discomforting when the people around you do not share your social norms and expectations. But isn't it a bit quick to just assume that it's <i>their</i> fault (and so call them 'jerks', 'boors' and so forth)? Lack of fit is a symmetrical relation, after all. Consider the following complaint:<br /><blockquote>How many times as a female professor have I gone out to dinner parties with visiting speakers where there were several philosopher’s wives present (my other colleagues mostly being males), where the entire dinner table conversation was devoted to philosophical issues that excluded them? As a woman, I or perhaps simply as someone socialized to be more polite and empathetic, I face the choice then: should I try to join in with “the guys” and prove my mettle, thus ignoring half the people present at the table, or should I attempt to be more congenial and polite and talk to the women?</blockquote><br />Now, from my perspective, <i>the whole point</i> of a bunch of philosophers going out to dinner with a visiting speaker is to discuss philosophy. That's what they're there for. To complain that "the entire dinner table conversation was devoted to philosophical issues" seems as bizarre to me as complaining that the entire seminar was dedicated to philosophy when some of the students might rather have discussed the local sports team. The problem does not necessarily lie with the topic of conversation; it could just be that the sports fans are in the wrong place.<br /><br />More generally, it's nice to accommodate people and make them feel comfortable. But given that the lack of fit between 'nerds' and 'normals' is symmetrical, it's not clear why the norms of the latter group should always take precedence. I mean, there's no surer way to make me uncomfortable than to put me in a situation where one is expected to engage in small talk. That's just a fact about me and how I relate to others. Many people (outside of academia) seem to be just the opposite: uncomfortable with serious discussion, comfortable with small talk. That's a fact about them and how they relate to others. Each of these two personality types may find it difficult to relate to the other. Objectively speaking, that's the end of the story. But in practice the <a href="http://www.philosophyetc.net/2006/03/introverts.html">extroverts</a> are socially dominant, so they lay fault on the nerds and introverts for failing to conform to their preferred (arbitrary) norms. What they don't seem to realize is that they are equally failing to conform to <i>our</i> preferred norms.<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?a=gKLwTbC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?i=gKLwTbC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?a=flalwjC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?i=flalwjC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?a=eaBgLjc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?i=eaBgLjc" border="0" /></a>
</div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/cock-up-no3-jim-anderton.html</url><title>COCK-UP No.3: Jim Anderton</title><date>2007-12-13 12:45:03.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Re: the  <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&objectid=10481847&pnum=0">Ombudsman's report</a> on the West Auckland aerial spraying, which:<br /><i>found shortcomings in the actions of both the Ministry of Agriculture and Forestry and the Ministry of Health that he said needed to be recognised so they were not repeated.</i><br /><br />Health and safety was just one issue of a larger picture of mishandling of this operation. It is an example of the tolerance within the Cabinet for the mishandling, and its major cost blow-outs; and it also demonstrates the concern for public inconvenience and even justice itself is non-existent. Putting Jim Anderton in charge of anything is as foolish as his Biosecurity predecessor Maryan Hobbs being still left in charge of anything.  I made this <a href="http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2005/07/labours-home-to-dr-cock-up.html">July 2005 post</a> (with comments from what might or might not be Dr Frampton) on the issue of the other two individuals.  Reproduced below:<br /><br />---------------------------------------------<br /><br /><b>Labour's home to Dr Cock-up</b><br /><br />They both happen to have doctorates, been placed in charge of putting practical matters right by this Labour government after major policy and preventive failure, have done a monumentally incompetent job, and both been quietly moved sideways after achieving next to nothing and squandering millions.  <br /><br />In both cases Government Ministers refused to replace them despite almost universal condemnation of their "work" until they decided it was time to shuffle off to another bureaucratic position.  In all the abstract mutterings about policies, frameworks and procedures no one seems to be apportioning blame squarely on the people responsible for these quite blatant cases of reckless incompetence and gross mismanagement.  Well, I'm sick of this overly polite bullshit where no one is held to account.  The heads of these organisations are responsible - they make the decisions and advise their ministers. It's time to name names:<br /><br /><b>COCK-UP No.1: Dr Lisa Ferguson/Leaky homes</b><br /><b>COST: $52m to date</b><br /><b>INCOMPETENCE: Nov.2002 to resignation July 2005 only resolved 344 out of 3,300 claims whilst staff partied and owners fumed.</b><br /><br />As head of the <a href="http://www.dbh.govt.nz/weathertightness/index.html">Weathertight Homes Resolution Service (WHRS)</a> you think she would be trying to assuage angry home-owners; but MP Nick Smith has <a href="http://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/PA0507/S00569.htm">brought to our attention yesterday</a> that she, instead, thought she was hosting party girl idol for her fellow bureaucrats:<br /><br /><i>WHRS "had a ‘Sound of Music’ theme party in Wellington for its 40 staff on the evening of Thursday June 30. The WHRS paid for all food and alcohol, and funded airfares and accommodation for Auckland staff.  A fortnight earlier, on Friday June 17, a dozen Wellington staff flew to join Auckland staff for a ‘Pacific Islands’ team building extravaganza at the Stanford Plaza Hotel, involving kava drinking and dancing girls. Last December, the WHRS held a ‘Cowboys and Indians’ theme party in which all Auckland staff were flown to Wellington at taxpayer expense. Food and beverages were again paid for by the WHRS. Earlier last year, an ‘Aeroplane’ theme party was held on similar terms."</i><br /><br />How did the damp owners <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?ObjectID=10334582">greet her resignation</a>:<br /><br /><i>John Gray, who represented seven Ponsonby Gardens townhouse owners awarded $700,000 in March after a weathertight service adjudication, was pleased Dr Ferguson was gone. <b>He said she was dismissive of claimants. </b><br /><br />Former service adjudicator David Gatley, who resigned last year in protest at the way the service was failing to help homeowners, said <b>Dr Ferguson was "completely out of her depth and knowledge" as head of the service.</b> He believed other senior staff connected with the service should also resign."</i><br /><br />According to <a href="http://www.tvnz.co.nz/view/page/410940/562362">TVNZ's Sunday programme report</a> she had the nerve to say:<br /><br /><i>"I think we give value for money for what we actually deliver, which is, an alternative dispute resolution service."</i><br /><br />And the boggle-eyed, moron Internal Affairs Minister, George Hawkins - the most shambolic of all ministers - says:<br /><br /><i>"Many people think that we as a government have put out our hand to help these people and these people are getting the solutions."</i><br /><br />The solution?  Throw money at a bureaucracy that does squat!?  What sort of a solution is that? - solving unemployment in Wellington!?  Seeing as how he is also the Minister of local government - who let this crisis develop unchecked - you start to see how chronically and endemically useless our State officials really are.  And this is all after the experience of case No. 2:<br /><br /><b>COCK-UP No.2: Dr Ruth Frampton/Painted Apple Moth</b><br /><b>COST: $50m to date, $50m over next 2 years</b><br /><b>INCOMPETENCE: May 1999 to resignation in May 2002 let moth spread from 1kmsq that would have cost a few million to half of Western Auckland costing $100m and aerial spraying tens of thousands of people.</b><br /><br />As the <a href="http://www.biosecurity.govt.nz/pests-diseases/forests/painted-apple-moth/">MAF official in charge of the Painted Apple Moth eradication programme</a> she botched from the very start as she focussed on monitoring and research but didn't actually bother about the eradication bit, treating the whole thing as an academic-type lab experiment.  In other countries people who make mistakes this big are charged with economic sabotage.  In NZ they just get to quit whenever they want without being pushed and recieve no penalties at all. <br /><br />From the <a href="http://www.oag.govt.nz/HomePageFolders/Publications/Biosecurity/part6.htm">Auditor-General's report 6.122</a><br /><br /><i>"Of the 33 recommendations made in the independent review of the response to the painted apple moth, the only recommendation not to have been accepted and acted upon by MAF was to develop a pest management strategy for the moth."</i><br /><br />In other words they had no plan, got a bollocking for having no plan (instead continuing to "monitor" the moth as it went completely out of control) and then came back <b>and still had no plan!</b> The <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?ObjectID=3048587"> Herald article of 24/12/2002</a>said about Auditor-General's report (dumped, you will note, just before Christmas so no one would notice): <br /><br /><i>"The report found there were <b>"flaws and errors of judgment"</b> by senior MAF staff in response to the painted apple moth incursion.<br />* There were "poor working relationships" between the senior MAF official in charge of the operation and key people in the forestry industry she was charged with protecting.<br />* It was "not acceptable" that minutes of key meetings in the early stages of the moth incursion were not kept, the report says.<br />* <b>An operational plan on how MAF would deal with the pest was finally produced after the eradication attempt had been going for two years.</b>[!!!]...<br /><br />MAF came under fire for the botched painted apple moth campaign, and criticism fell mainly on its former Director of Forest Biosecurity, Dr Ruth Frampton...</i><br /><br />The <a href="http://www.greens.org.nz/searchdocs/PR5254.html"> Greens at the time (May 2002)</a> noted: <br /><br /><i>“Last year the MAF appointed Community Advisory Group called for Dr Frampton to resign, saying the Painted Apple Moth incursion and <b>attempts to control it were a fiasco.</b><br />“Recent developments which have culminated in Dr Frampton’s resignation today further support this view and the people of Auckland deserve a full explanation of what is going on. "</i><br /><br />A <a href="http://onenews.nzoom.com/onenews_detail/0,1227,76935-1-6,00.html">TVNZ report of Jan 2002</a> stated the extent of the madness clearly:<br /><br /><i>""They've caught moths all over the city from Greenlane to Pakuranga to Waitakere, what's the use of spraying this area when when they are simply going to infest from the outside?" says Hana Blackmore of the Community Advisory Group.<br />However, MAF says traps and ground spraying have those areas under control, but the bushes of west Auckland are a different story, and the moth can only be targeted by air.<br /><br />"If it doesn't work, other options may need to be examined," says Dr Ruth Frampton of MAF.<br /><br />"Regardless, if blanket aerial spraying was one of those options - and it has always been an option - then we would have to go back to the government to get their support and funding for that."</i><br /><br />Too little too late, lady. Let's look at what she said when this whole $100m waste was only goiung to cost a few million ( From a <a href="http://www.maf.govt.nz/mafnet/press/archive/1999/120599mth.htm">MAF media release with Frampton's name at the bottom of it dated 19 May <b>1999</b></a><br /><br /><i>"Decisions about on whether or not to try to eradicate unwanted pests are based on an assessment of the probability of success," she said. "The first step in assessing this is to carry out what is known as <b>a delimiting survey to establish the extent of spread of the pest."</b><br /><br />In the case of the painted apple moth, the survey is almost complete, and results indicate that it is confined to a handful of properties clustered together in an industrial area, with another site about 300 metres away. <b>The total area involved in Glendene - including the outlying site - is less than one square kilometre."</b></i><br /><br />"Delimiting survey" - that never ended! Surveyed it as it spread over the city.  Eradication yet?  No, no.  More surveys...  And how did Labour try to disguise this unnecessary catastrophy (from Labour MP David Cunliffe's breezy, congratulatory, <a href="http://www.cunliffe.org.nz/6.news/releases/detail.asp?id=57">May 2002 statement</a><br /><br /><i>"It is important to note that Dr Frampton had a difficult and thankless task and gave it her best effort. <b>We wish her well as she moves to take up a more technical role elsewhere in MAF</b>...<br />I wish to reassure constituents that no decision has been made yet on the future of the project. A great deal of analysis is going into the draft cabinet paper."</i><br /><br />"Wish her," fucking "well"?  She's cost the country 1/10th of a billion dollars, and you wish her well!!!?  Fucking hell, I hate to think what you'd have to do to get a condemnation - losing $5 billion? $10 billion?  What about a mild rebuke - $20 billion? And as for "analysis" - what about this as an analysis: don't use research academics to do pest control.  That simple enough?  Recognise a problem when it occurs and do something about it.  That simple enough? The latest report (<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?ObjectID=3507228">Herald 13/06/2005</a>) is grim reading:<br /><br /><i>"Dr Cullen also revealed that <b>the cost so far of the Government's war against the painted apple moth in West Auckland is almost as much as if the moth had been left to its own devices.</b><br /><br />"In the case of the painted apple moth, the programme is now approaching the bottom-end of the estimated cost of simply allowing the moth to spread," he said.<br /><br />When the decision was made last year to launch an all-out aerial attack on the moth, budgeted at $90 million over three years, Maf said the pest could cause between $58 million and $356 million in damage over 20 years.<br /><br />The estimated cost so far of the current eradication programme is $39 million. That is on top of last year's campaign, which cost between $11 and $13 million."</i>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/millie-holmes-drug-sentence-deferred.html</url><title>Millie Holmes Drug Sentence Deferred</title><date>2007-12-14 00:33:56.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_8vAedvRAitQ/R2HOhJ1nEMI/AAAAAAAAAAw/5qIE4sPx0x0/s1600-h/capri+pool.jpg"><img id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143619318405599426" title="Capri Trust swimming pool" alt="Capri Trust swimming pool" src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_8vAedvRAitQ/R2HOhJ1nEMI/AAAAAAAAAAw/5qIE4sPx0x0/s200/capri+pool.jpg" border="0" /> <div></a></div><a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/search/label/Millie%20Holmes">Millie Holmes</a> nee Millie Elder's sentencing for drug charges (for possession of P, a pipe and allowing her premises to be used for drugs) has been deferred to give her a chance to complete drug rehab. Really, you would think a spell behind bars would be the ultimate rehab, but instead Millie has been given permission to continue with her outpatient treatment at ritzy Capri Trust and is allowed to stay out until midnight each night.<br /><br />Her new sentencing date is in March 2008. No doubt Millie will use her time to <a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/11/millie-holmes-latest-addiction.html">sell the latest instalment of her story</a> to the media.<br /><br />According to <a href="http://capritrust.com/">Capri Trust</a><br /><br /><blockquote>Addiction is a sickness. It can be helped and the Capri Trust has put together a DVD with copies of the presentations, information from reformed addicts and details about what goes on in a rehab clinic and the services that are provided.<br /><br />To receive your copy please <a href="mailto:toml@capritrust.com">email the Clinical Director</a> who will arrange to forward you this stimulating yet shocking full revelation into exactly what the problem is and how to go about fixing it.</blockquote><br />A shocking full revelation, huh? Now there's a story for you Millie...<br /><br /><strong>Related stories:</strong><br /><a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/11/millie-elder-lesbian.html">Millie Holmes a Lesbian?</a>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?a=ZM9vBo"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?i=ZM9vBo" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=x6Zu18C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=x6Zu18C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=i2muoWc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=i2muoWc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=kLbGoMc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=kLbGoMc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=hPvBkoc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=hPvBkoc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NewZealandRealityTv/~4/200013023" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/diane-levys-time-out.html</url><title>Diane Levy's Time Out</title><date>2007-12-13 07:43:31.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_HZlxBZQcoGI/R2DiYrsnMQI/AAAAAAAABUg/C5c6zjSInMI/s320/diane+levy.jpg" alt="Diane Levy" title="Diane Levy" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143359688131686658" border="0" />Diane Levy aka Super Granny is the host of TV3's <em>Demons to Darlings</em>, the reality show that helps tame misbehaving children, and re-educate their parents. She’s also an Auckland based family therapist and the author of three popular parenting books.<br /><br />Diane believes that one of the most important gifts we can give our children is the ability to do as they are told in response to simple, reasonable parenting requests and that this is a vital step on the way to raising self-disciplined, self-motivated, pleasant young adults.<br /><br />In this Close Up interview <a href="http://tvnz.co.nz/view/video_popup_windows_skin/1499964" target="_blank">Diane Levy talks</a> about the subject of her new book <a href="http://www.fishpond.co.nz/product_info.php?ref=797&amp;products_id=11488611&amp;affiliate_banner_id=1">Time Out for Tots Teens and Everyone in Between</a> or How to get your children to do as they're told. In the interview she attempts to differentiate between sending children to the "Naughty Step" to think about where they went wrong, with her approach of emotional distance. The interview is a little confusing as it appears that she is suggesting that Time Out is a bad idea, which is strange when it is the title of her book. Miss Prozac wonders if interviewer Mark Sainsbury actually read the book?<br /><br /><a href="http://www.fishpond.co.nz/product_info.php?ref=797&amp;products_id=11488611&amp;affiliate_banner_id=1"><img src="http://image.fishpond.co.nz/9781869419455-250x250.jpg?cat=1_241_2003_2032" alt="" border="0" /></a>Bottom line is that Diane advocates that you give children time to make up their own mind to behave, saying that you let them know there will be a warm welcome waiting for them when they choose to get dressed or perform the task they have been set. In the meantime, they will be left alone until to wrestle with their own conscience.<br /><br />Miss Prozac couldn’t help thinking it sounded a little like the <a href="http://www.fishpond.co.nz/product_info.php?ref=797&amp;products_id=2755857&amp;affiliate_banner_id=1">Jan Fennell aka the <span>Dog Listener’s</span></a> approach to training. Jan Fennell suggests ignoring a dog that is jumping up or misbehaving, going as far as to suggest you should turn your back on the dog and deprive it of your attention. When it behaves appropriately you greet the dog, hug it or give it a food reward.<br /><br />No doubt there is more information in Diane’s book, and although the TV interview was a little confusing to watch, Miss Prozac is confident that Super Granny knows her stuff and that her book and popular speaking engagements will make it all crystal clear. If not, Super Granny probably has a wonderful second career opportunity as a dog trainer.
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?a=FozD3F"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?i=FozD3F" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=2E6Z7EC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=2E6Z7EC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=pkDuWWc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=pkDuWWc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=q4GVG2c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=q4GVG2c" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=vNCcNSc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=vNCcNSc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NewZealandRealityTv/~4/199611878" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/mintshot-update.html</url><title>Mintshot Update</title><date>2007-12-13 19:27:38.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
As regular readers of this site will be aware I've had a lot of problems with <a href="http://www.mintshot.co.nz/">Mintshot</a> and have been in contact with them to try and resolve the issues.<br /><br />Turns out that when I said I was one of handful of people who had <a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/mintshot-play-people-other-errors.html">problems with yesterday's results</a> on my Play The People bets, that I was <span>literally </span>one of a handful. According to Nick Dalton, one of the directors of Mintshot, you could count the number of people who had that precise problem on one hand.<br /><br /><a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_HZlxBZQcoGI/R08kP1x28oI/AAAAAAAABQQ/lt_0ljjVmfo/s320/mintshot+logo.gif"><img alt="" src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_HZlxBZQcoGI/R08kP1x28oI/AAAAAAAABQQ/lt_0ljjVmfo/s320/mintshot+logo.gif" border="0" /></a><br /><br />Mintshot have been extremely helpful, (not to mention relieved that it hasn't happened again this morning) and are beavering away testing their system to try to identify where the problem might have occurred. I'm not sure we'll ever get to the bottom of it, but I feel satisfied that they're taking the problem seriously and are keen to hear what users have to say about the system. I look forward to the day when I won't feel compelled to take screenshots of every bet!<br /><br />Nick tells me that Mint Tick (the game where you click to reveal ticks or crosses with the highest score winning prizes) is proving very popular, and has increased traffic to the site. I confess I've given it a go, but so far I haven't got anywhere near the number of ticks I need to win a prize.<br /><br />Also in "inside" news from Mintshot, I heard that the blog is currently in test mode and will be up on their site soon. Users will be able to check in to find out what's happening with the site and voice their concerns with interactive comments on the blog. Nick tells me that it's their intention to improve the community feel of the site with more opportunities for members to vote on what's happening. He assures me that Mintshot takes customer feedback seriously, and I believe him.<br /><br />Nick says the team are working closely with users to eliminate any cheats or shortcuts in the system that enable people to watch advertisements multiple times or find other ways to boost their points. Mintshot get daily reports of suspicious activity and act on it. That will be a relief to many, who are casting their eyes in suspicion at people who appear to have large mint dollar balances, have won lots of prizes or are doing well in the mint tick games. It's creating an atmosphere of distrust, as players accuse others of cheating and dob them in to Mintshot.<br /><br />After past problems with cheating, there is still a concern from some users that people are finding ways to cheat. If they are, I haven't heard about it, although I do know a lot of people took advantage of the problems that occurred in Monday's changeover of advertisements that enabled some people to watch advertisements multiple times. One user reported that they took advantage of the loophole and then got banned. He thought that was unfair.<br /><br />It's hard to know what's fair. On the one hand, some people wrote to Mintshot and pointed out the problem. For example, I emailed when I found that a McDonald's advertisement that I had already watched, could be watched a second time after the question changed, giving me an extra 200 mint dollars. Others say that if the system has problems, then it's fair game and they're entitled to take advantage of it. I can see both perspectives but personally I don't think it's worth it.<br /><br />Fingers crossed, this is the end of my hassles with Mintshot, and things go smoothly from now on. If not, you'll definitely be hearing from me...
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?a=6y3Apf"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?i=6y3Apf" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=GO5H1zC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=GO5H1zC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=LhvYLZc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=LhvYLZc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=ieTQRhc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=ieTQRhc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=6jXWZ3c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=6jXWZ3c" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NewZealandRealityTv/~4/199573753" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JDEnAvant/~3/199603781/</url><title>Bah, humbug! Please do something different</title><date>2007-12-13 06:56:36.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img src="http://jimdonovan.net.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/xmas-party.jpg" title="xmas-party.jpg" alt="xmas-party.jpg" align="left" hspace="10" vspace="10" />This isn't meant to sound boastful, but I am inundated in December with invitations to business Christmas functions. Without wishing to sound ungrateful for the well-meant hospitality, I do find this Christmas drinks thing a bit tedious after a while.  There are some do's where I should go, either from a real sense of connection  at a personal level with the  inviting organisation, or because I have a figurehead role to play (these things are important). Otherwise nowadays, I just don't accept - politely, of course.</p>
<p>In theory, a lot of these functions are meant to be a way for organisations to connect with their clients and business associates.  However, they often fail to do so - not because of a lack of goodwill, but from a lack of spontaneity and originality.</p>
<p>A company would have far more impact with its "stakeholder" functions if (a) they were different from the usual canapes and wine format, and  (b) more importantly, they were held at a different time of the year, when I'd be more inclined to attend and to heed any special messages from the organisation.</p>
<p>PS.  Let me add that I'm not at all worried about the issue of stakeholders without a close sectarian or historical link to Christianity being offended by a Christian celebration (not that Christmas these days has much to do with Christianity).  I've been to superb functions in other societies based on their high days and holy  celebrations, and enjoyed the cultural experience. Done well, the reverse is true, I'm sure.</p>
<img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/JDEnAvant/~4/199603781" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://hkham.wordpress.com/2007/12/14/liver-let-die/</url><title>Liver let die</title><date>2007-12-14 00:55:04.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<div class="snap_preview"><p>I've now got the sort of job that's going to require me to be in a situation where free alcoholic beverages are readily on hand and it would be almost rude of me not to partake. In several. Several too many.</p>
<p>My new office is also located in an area that is dangerously close to many of the city's less reputable entertainment establishments. I can see late working nights on Fridays spilling into hungover Saturday mornings.</p>
<p>I guess I can be thankful that I live on Lamma and therefore have to catch the 12:30am ferry home or suffer the consequences of an attempted all-nighter, or fork out for an expensive sampan trip across the bumpy harbour. It's my safety net to protect against complete obliteration of the liver.</p>
<p>So much for my quietly-determined regime of healthy living. I'll still eat lots of sandwiches.</p>
</div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RodDrury/~3/200035538/</url><title>Entreprenuership event 8-9 Jan</title><date>2007-12-14 01:44:21.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>This looks like a useful event early next year ...</p>
<p>As part of PricewaterhouseCoopers Hi-Tech programme for 2007-2008, PwC is hosting Ken Morse, Managing Director of the MIT Entrepreneurship Centre.</p>
<p>Ken's two day workshop will be held in Auckland on 08-09 January 2008 and is aimed at business leaders from hi growth, innovative NZ companies. The two day workshop is based on case studies, lectures, interactive discussions and hands on exercises and is focussed on assisting in the development of growth strategies - covering topics such as reaching global markets, building global networks, sales strategies, and capital raising.</p>
<p>Register here <a href="http://www.entrepreneurshipnewzealand.com/" target="_blank">www.entrepreneurshipnewzealand.com</a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wellingtonista.com/embracing-your-inner-show-mom</url><title>Embracing your inner show-mom</title><date>2007-12-13 03:06:26.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img src="http://filmarchive.org.nz/images/Email-News/Swimsuit.jpg" align="right" />Late notice but tonight at the Film Archive, cnr of Taranaki and Ghuznee Streets, at 6:30pm the Friends of the Film Archive present a special insight into baby contests, beauty competitions and screen tests from yesteryear. It’s free. It’s hilarious. Here’s the blurb:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Contest Films from the silent era and the 1930s are presented afresh. Struggling early New Zealand film makers made a living with their cameras putting the faces of the young, beautiful and talented on the screen to be judged by popular vote.”</p></blockquote>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/national_reopens_selwyn_nominations.html</url><title>National reopens Selwyn nominations</title><date>2007-12-13 23:57:30.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>National announced last night that it has decided to reopen nominations for Selwyn, after <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/thepress/4323181a19720.html">complaints of pressure</a> on some candidates not to stand.</p>
<p>This is not a common occurrence.  I don't think I can recall another selection where this has happened.</p>
<p>I know absolutely nothing about the details, beyond what I have read in the newspaper.   But what I can say is what my personal view is.</p>
<p>I think every seat not currently held by National should have an active selection contest.  Yes it can be challenging for managing parliamentary relationships, but overall the party gains members and supporters when we have contested selections for seats National does not hold.</p>
<p>Another reason I support contested selections, is that on current polling National could gain 55 - 60 MPs.  And with a policy that all but a maximum of five list candidates must also be electorate candidates, it means that even candidates in the most safe Labour seats have a significant chance of becoming MPs through the list.  And a healthy selection process can help ensure that National doesn't end up with "dud" MPs as happened in 1990.</p>
<p>National of course also has a history of selection battles for sitting electorate MPs - John Key, Judith Collins and John Carter all won their seats by challenging for the nomination against an incumbent electorate MP.  And National is far better off for having had them do so.</p>
<p>The issue of List MPs is a bit different.  A List MP doesn't hold a seat, even though they may have stood for it last time or be associated with it.  There isn't the same stigma to stand against a List MP for a seat, as there is to actually challenge an Electorate MP.  For example Annabel Young faced a contested selection for Wellington Central despite being an existing List MP.</p>
<p>So National has a good healthy history of contested selections, and it is good to see the same will happen in Selwyn - safe seats especially should have a vigorous contest.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wellurban.blogspot.com/2007/12/slightly-less-super.html</url><title>Slightly less super</title><date>2007-12-14 13:17:05.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<div class="file-under">File under: <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/urbanism" rel="tag">urbanism</a>, <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/Mt+Cook" rel="tag">Mt Cook</a>, <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/Wellington" rel="tag">Wellington</a></div><br />When you're considering what to submit for <a href="http://wellurban.blogspot.com/2007/11/growing-spine.html">the Adelaide Rd consultation</a> (due in less than 4 hours), it's worth bearing in mind the current state of proposed private developments. There was an article in yesterday's <span>Dominion Post</span> (not online), and a <a href="http://wellington.govt.nz/news/display-item.php?id=3090">media release from the council</a>, stating that a demolition consent has been applied for for the proposed supermarket site that has been <a href="http://wellurban.blogspot.com/2007/08/mt-cook-summit.html">much discussed</a>. While both articles are primarily concerned about the possibility of the site being left vacant for months, there's a small point mentioned in the Dom article that's quite interesting: the proposal has been scaled down somewhat.<br /><br />Instead of a 6000 sq m <span>Pak 'N Save</span> with 60 apartments, <span>Foodstuffs</span> are now proposing "a medium-sized <span>New World</span> supermarket above a car park with space for 157 vehicles, and a couple of four to five-storey blocks, each with 20 apartments". The façade of <a href="http://mtcookmobilised.pbwiki.com/Preserving+heritage+values+-+the+BGI">the old BGI swimming pool</a> will also be retained and incorporated, and while I'm always wary of façadism, this all sounds like some sort of compromise is happening quietly during the pre-application stage of the consent process. If the actual consent process (which <span>Foodstuffs</span> expects to start in March) were able to ensure that the final design incorporates plenty of active edges and maybe even a replacement for the pool, then I think we could go a long way towards balancing the needs of what could be a valuable development with the legitimate concerns of current residents. Fingers crossed.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wellurban.blogspot.com/2007/12/frank-comparisons.html</url><title>Frank comparisons</title><date>2007-12-14 11:54:50.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<div class="file-under">File under: <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/waterfront" rel="tag">waterfront</a>, <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/urbanism" rel="tag">urbanism</a>, <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/landscape+architecture" rel="tag">landscape architecture</a>, <a href="http://technorati.com/tag/Wellington" rel="tag">Wellington</a></div><br />The winner of the Frank Kitts Park design competition has been announced (on page A4 of today's <span>Dominion Post</span> and in <a href="http://www.wellingtonwaterfront.co.nz/media_section/Publications/on_the_waterfront/newsletters.htm?m=65">the latest issue of <span>On the Waterfront</span></a>), and it was the one labelled <a href="http://wellurban.blogspot.com/2007/10/frank-kitts-option-b.html">Option B</a>. As I speculated at the time but couldn't say for sure, it's by Wraight and Associates, who were part of the Waitangi Park design team. Interestingly, the announcement includes a perspective drawing that makes it much easier to grasp the overall layout than the entry itself did.<br /><br /><a href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Y5J8pfNiQA4/R2G31fVLcLI/AAAAAAAAAk4/ZOFUa4uhijw/s1600-h/frank_kitts_proposed_perspective.jpg"><img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_Y5J8pfNiQA4/R2G31fVLcLI/AAAAAAAAAk4/ZOFUa4uhijw/s400/frank_kitts_proposed_perspective.jpg" border="0" alt="Winning design for Frank Kitts Park" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143594379005096114" /></a>In my <a href="http://wellurban.blogspot.com/2007/11/last-chance-feedback.html">summary of the options</a>, I said of this one that it has "Nice clean geometry, with a good tight cluster of buildings, but too much bleakly flat lawn." I think I still stand by that, but that's partly based on my own personal aversion to big open paddocks, and people who want a big flat space for chucking around a ball or frisbee should be very pleased with this. In fact, for all the talk in some quarters of the redesign "destroying open space", it looks like this plan actually has more open green space than the current park:<br /><br /><a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_Y5J8pfNiQA4/R2GsMPVLcKI/AAAAAAAAAkw/tcVOK3NHVqc/s1600-h/frank_kitts_old_vs_proposed.jpg"><img src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_Y5J8pfNiQA4/R2GsMPVLcKI/AAAAAAAAAkw/tcVOK3NHVqc/s400/frank_kitts_old_vs_proposed.jpg" alt="Current Frank Kitts Park layout compared to selected new design" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143581575707586722" border="0" /></a>The most important thing is to compare the new design to the current park. On the plus side, this will finally be a waterfront park from which you can actually see the water. It will be an opportunity to update the physical and design qualities of a park that is looking rather tired and dated. The Chinese Garden, which I think is handled better than in any of the rival designs, should provide a lot of spatial variety, visual interest, shelter and cultural value. The upper lawn will have better access from the promenade and lagoon, and in general movement into and through the park should be easier. Best of all, from my perspective, the cluster of pavilions in and adjacent to the Chinese Garden has the potential to create a node of activity part way along a stretch that can be quite deserted at times.<br /><br />Apart from the exposed nature of the lawn space, there are a few other aspects I'm less happy with. I don't see the need to relocate the Albatross sculpture to the upper lawn: it's very popular where it is, and the current combination of lagoon, fountain and <span>Kaffee Eis</span> works very well. The larger flat green area comes at the expense of the amphitheatre, so while it will be better for some sorts of events it will be less suited to others. There's no attempt to create new connections between the promenade and the water, though the brief suggested that this might be left until later stages for financial reasons. Finally, the improved visual connection between the lawn and the harbour comes at the expense of shelter and seating along the promenade: while the loss of shelter may be an unavoidable trade-off, I hope that some sort of informal or moveable seating could be included without too much effort.<br /><br />The article emphasised that this is not a final, detailed design, and that more development of the design will occur over the next six months. There's a lot to like about this proposal, and I hope that between now and the eventual reconstruction of the park (which is unlikely to start before 2009), there are opportunities to work through any shortcomings and create the best possible space.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5483</url><title>Surprise, surprise he did it again</title><date>2007-12-13 20:22:28.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4323146a10.html" rel="nofollow">Man detained at home bashes victim again - New Zealand, world, sport, business <span class="amp">&amp;</span> entertainment news on&nbsp;Stuff.co.nz</a></p>
<p>What sort of a fool judge gives a man convicted of domestic violence home&nbsp;detention?????!!!!</p>
<p><span class="caps">FFS</span> He was convicted of bashing his partner and then gets sentenced to home&nbsp;detention?</p>
<p>That could be considered a cruel and unusual punishment for both of them. The woman for having to have the creep at home in the first place and the man for having to be with someone he think is a punching bag&nbsp;24/7.</p>
<p>I mean really, cases like this show we have lost the plot in Corrections and Justice.....who is the Justice Minister again?...oh that's right Annette "Commonsense"&nbsp;King</p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5480</url><title>Starship reluctant to give back cash</title><date>2007-12-13 19:09:39.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482299&amp;ref=rss" rel="nofollow">Starship reluctant to give back cash</a> - <i>The Starship Foundation won't return the $158,000 given to it by New Zealand First leader Winston Peters unless the gift was unlawful.<br />
And there is no suggestion that that is the case.<br />
Mr Peters gave the hospital a cheque on...</i> [<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/" rel="nofollow"><span class="caps">NZ</span> Politics</a>]
</p>
<p>
Winston needs to come&nbsp;clean.
</p>
<p>
Firstly the word about town is that there has been a little bit of laundering going on. A well known business man in Auckland is known to have paid some money into a certain solicitors trust account that was then paid to another solicitors trust account and then onto <span class="caps">NZ</span> First, which Winston then gace to Starship.  This is almost similar to the same methods by which a certain litigious <span class="caps">MP</span> pays his legal&nbsp;bills.
</p>
<p>
So Winston needs to come&nbsp;clean.
</p>
<ol>
<li>Where did the money come&nbsp;from?</li>
<li>Who was his secret&nbsp;backer/s?</li>
<li>If it came from their supposed term deposits, show us the break&nbsp;certificates?</li>
<li>Who is getting the $60,000 tax break from the&nbsp;donation
	</li>
</ol>
<p>
It is not acceptable that this level of subterfuge is being used by a politician who is at the same time supporting the destruction of our democracy through the rushed passing of the draconian Electoral Finance&nbsp;Bill.
</p>
<p>
It is time you fessed up&nbsp;Winston.
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/politics/2007/12/14/more-on-the-pms-views-on-the-media/</url><title>More on the PM’s views on the media</title><date>2007-12-14 00:45:23.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Silence has descended over Parliament today. The MPs got through their urgency last night so there will be one final hurrah next Tuesday to hold the third reading of the Electoral Finance Bill, a final Question Time and perhaps one more first reading and then it's up stumps and off for Christmas.</p>
<p>It's been an intriguing week, dominated by the oddest and smallest of stories - the Prime Minister's speech to the Journalism Education Association conference in Wellington. A few throwaway remarks by Helen Clark have got her into trouble with parts of the press gallery - notably the political editors of TV1 and TV3, Guyon Espiner and Duncan Garner.</p>
<p>As is so often the case, it's not what the Prime Minister originally said but what has happened since that is so interesting. </p>
<p>The Prime Minister, who values her relationship with the gallery and has always gone to some lengths to preserve it - now wants to move on. But I'd like a transcript, or better still, a tape of her address to the journalists. Her office has one, but it won't release it. </p>
<p>I know what you're thinking - why wasn't I there? Well, just to get this clear, because the Prime Minister's office thinks this is important, <em>I didn't attend her speech</em>. There has been some comment that this is an important factor - even that it means I don't have the right to blog on the topic. For the record, I would have liked to go but a) I was at home in bed sick and b) I didn't know about it anyway.</p>
<p>Only one press gallery reporter attended. No one has a tape. Most didn't know about the Prime Minister's appearance either. We have been criticised for this. The Prime Minister's office points out that the engagement was in the ministerial diary forwarded to the press gallery each week. That's true. But no advisory was sent out, which is unusual. Normally we are encouraged to attend her speeches, although obviously we can't always do so.</p>
<p>Anyway, now that's clear, I am relying on what was reported by <em>New Zealand Herald</em> journalist Claire Trevett, who did attend, and wrote a story which to the best of my knowledge Clark has not taken issue with. So what follows is based on <a target="_blank" href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/category/story.cfm?c_id=49&amp;objectid=10481591"><strong>what Claire wrote </strong></a>and also speaking to others who were there. </p>
<p>In her presentation to the conference, Clark said many journalists were young, and while this meant that they had "energy and a fresh perspective", most of them had major gaps in their general knowledge.</p>
<p>Clark said "very few" journalists had a comprehensive knowledge of New Zealand's international relations and few media outlets sent journalists to cover her international trips.</p>
<p>"It's a matter of regret that proprietors don't seem to think these things are particularly important either, so they don't encourage the depth of coverage."</p>
<p>She also said media also needed to consider blogging by senior political reporters on the websites of major news outlets. </p>
<p>"Of course, if you commit yourself to instant opinion, then when it comes time to putting in a considered piece, you might think, 'Whoops, that was a rush of judgment,' but it becomes hard to climb back from."</p>
<p>Clark only mentioned one journalist by name, Duncan Garner, who she said was an example of a journalist too willing to confuse scutiny with cynicism, and who recently claimed that all politicians lied.</p>
<p>Garner tells me this was a poor paraphrase of a remark he made recently to a journalism industry event, at which he said, referring to the Benson-Pope saga, that when cornered, a politician's first instinct was to lie.  </p>
<p>I can think of a few MPs this applies to, although Clark has every right to say these things, and they are food for thought. Worthy of debate. I'm intrigued, then, as to why her office won't release the rest of what she said so I can post it here for everyone to read or listen to.</p>
<p>One could draw the conclusion that it is because the Prime Minister realises she went too far in some of her remarks and unfairly denigrated some senior journalists. That she wants the issue closed, because attacking the Fourth Estate is never very productive for a politician. And perhaps, there is more on the tape she'd prefer didn't get reported.</p>
<p>I could be completely wrong. I'm just saying one could come to that conclusion, given the PM's office's peculiar refusal to release the tape.</p>
<p>As regular On the House readers will know, the PM's press secretary Juli Clausen posted an entry for the first time the other day, criticising me for not attending the speech and also making errors in my earlier post. I'm grateful for her post. According to her office the PM didn't actually use the words "too young to remember history", and if that's the case they should not have been in speech marks.</p>
<p>I was unhappy about clarifying this without a transcript of what Clark actually said, which as I said has proven elusive. The PM's office has since dropped its request for a correction, but I've been trying to find out what she did say anyway.</p>
<p>This little media storm in a teacup has been picked up by <em>Media Watch</em>, Radio New Zealand's weekly look at the media, which has interviewed both Clark and Garner. Amongst the remarks the PM makes on the programme are that news organisations don't appear willing to pay the salaries necessary to retain the sorts of senior journalists one would expect to be in high-ranking news jobs in New Zealand.</p>
<p>But Clark denies this is the same thing as saying those who are doing the jobs in New Zealand are too young for their positions. </p>
<p>To my knowledge it's the first time the PM has appeared on <em>Media Watch</em>, and it would be <a target="_blank" href="http://www.radionz.co.nz/nr/programmes/mediawatch"><strong>worth a listen </strong></a>(Sunday 9am and 10pm on RNZ and posted on their website).</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/lifeatwork/2007/12/14/the-dogfighting-employee-an-update/</url><title>The dogfighting employee: an update</title><date>2007-12-14 01:22:16.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/michael_vick1.jpg" title="michael_vick1.jpg"></a><img vspace="5" align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/michael_vick1.jpg" hspace="5" alt="michael_vick1.jpg" title="michael_vick1.jpg" />You may recall that some months ago <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/lifeatwork/2007/07/23/dogfighting-sport-and-work-what-should-an-employer-do/"><strong>I blogged about an unfortunate incident involving one of the most outstanding football players in America, Michael Vick</strong></a> (right).</p>
<p>Vick was accused of involvement in dogfighting - an illegal (and extraordinarily cruel) activity.</p>
<p>At the time I invited you to think about the issues raised by the situation for the employer when an employee is charged with a crime:</p>
<p>- Should the employer immediately charge the worker with misconduct and suspend, awaiting trial? Or (especially as here, where the employee is key to the business), regard the worker as innocent unless and until proven otherwise - and allow them to work on in their job?</p>
<p>Well, in this case I can now offer an update - and tell you about the outcome of this horrible story.</p>
<p>The league suspended Vick from playing - so even if the employer had other ideas, he couldn't play this season (at least while charged).</p>
<p>Vick's team - the Atlanta Falcons - have won only three of their 13 games, and are at the bottom of their division (an outcome which has an undoubted financial consequence for the employer).</p>
<p>Vick has been found guilty of running a dogfighting operation and <a target="_blank" href="http://sports.espn.go.com/nfl/news/story?id=3148549"><strong>was this week sentenced to (wait for it) 23 months in jail</strong></a>. Even with things going his way he won't be back to play football next season - and possibly also the season after.</p>
<p>What counted against him (among other things) was the fact that he initially lied about his involvement - and then tested positive for marijuana use in violation of the terms set for his release.</p>
<p>He has been stripped of a $20 million bonus, will lose about $50 million in endorsements, and $71 million in annual salary (for each year that he will be away from the game).</p>
<p>It is perhaps no surprise that Vick has - according to his lawyer - now been diagnosed as clinically depressed.</p>
<p>Wow. How a mistake in life can cost you your career...and more.</p>
<p>But is there anybody who thinks this penalty unfair?</p>
<p><em>Picture: REUTERS</em></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/abouttown/2007/12/14/sir-terry-mclean-national-sports-journalism-awards/</url><title>Sir Terry McLean National Sports Journalism Awards</title><date>2007-12-14 02:19:51.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>A record 214 entries were received for the 2007 TP McLean Sports Awards on Wednesday the 5th December and the big prize on the night went to The Press reporter Tony Smith, who took out the supreme Air New Zealand Sports Journalist of the Year Award.  Smith also won the Steinlager Award for Newspaper Feature Writing.</p>
<p>Among the throng  were, Grant Fox, Buck Shelford, Steve McDowall, Joe Stanley, John Drake, Coach Sir Brian Lochore, John Hart and Richie Guy, members of the All Blacks team who won the inaugural Rugby World Cup and remain the only All Black team to have won the William Webb Ellis Trophy.  Also at the dinner were members of the 1987 New Zealand Netball team, Julie Coney, Rita Fatialofa-Patolo, Margaret Forsyth, Joan Hodson (Solia), Angela Bell (Pule), Tracy Shortland (Eyrl) and Sandra Gray (Edge), plus Coach Lois Muir DCNZM.OBE., winners of the 1987 World Netball Championships in Glasgow.</p>
<p>The SPARC Lifetime Contribution to Sport through Journalism Award went to radio sport host Brendan Telfer, one of New Zealand’s most respected sports broadcasters.</p>
<p>Two journalists were also made Life Members of the NZSJA – former cricket and rugby commentator, Colin Snedden, and long time Newstalk ZB sports guru, Barry Holland.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/forsyth-edge.JPG" title="Direct link to file"></p>
<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/forsyth-edge.JPG" alt="forsyth-edge.JPG" height="111" width="171" /></p>
<p></a><br />
Margaret Forsyth and Sandra Edge entertain the guests with memories from the 1987</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/muir-edge-coney-shortland.JPG" title="Direct link to file"></p>
<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/muir-edge-coney-shortland.JPG" alt="muir-edge-coney-shortland.JPG" height="115" width="175" /></p>
<p></a>World Netball Championships1987 Coach Lois Muir with Netballers Sandra Edge, Julie Coney and Tracy Shortland.<br />
<a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/shortland-muir-guy.JPG" title="Direct link to file"></p>
<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/shortland-muir-guy.JPG" alt="shortland-muir-guy.JPG" height="111" width="171" /></p>
<p></a></p>
<p>Netballer Tracy Shortland with '87 Netball Coach Lois Muir and '87 All Blacks Manager Richie Guy.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/snedden-mcdowall-becht.JPG" title="Direct link to file"></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/snedden-mcdowall-becht.JPG" alt="snedden-mcdowall-becht.JPG" height="111" width="171" /></p>
<p></a></p>
<p>artin Snedden (Rugby World Cup 2011 CEO), Steve McDowall and Richard Becht (NZSJA Chairman).<br />
<a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/stars-of-87.JPG" title="Direct link to file"></p>
<p><img src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/stars-of-87.JPG" alt="stars-of-87.JPG" height="107" width="171" /></p>
<p></a></p>
<p>The All Blacks and Netball stars of 1987.</p>
<p>The 2007 TP McLean National Sports Journalism Awards winners, by award category, were:</p>
<p>Orca Award for Sports News Print<br />
Paul Lewis (Herald on Sunday)<br />
Orca Award for Sports News Broadcast<br />
Andrew Saville (TVNZ)<br />
Wilson Award for Sports Radio<br />
Brian Kelly (Radio Network)<br />
Telecom Award for Sports Television<br />
Hamish Clark (TV3)<br />
Millennium Hotels Award for Best Sports Column/Opinion<br />
Dylan Cleaver (Herald on Sunday)<br />
Steinlager Award for Feature Writing – Newspapers<br />
Tony Smith (The Press)<br />
Steinlager Award for Feature Writing – Magazines<br />
Peter Malcouronne (Metro)<br />
New Zealand Herald DJ Cameron Young Writer Award<br />
Logan Savory (Southland Times)<br />
SPARC Award for Recreation/Adventure/Lifestyle Reporting<br />
Peter Cronshaw (TVNZ)<br />
SPARC Award for Recreation/Adventure/Lifestyle Photography<br />
Peter Meecham (The Press)<br />
SPARC Award for Best Photography Portfolio<br />
Michael Bradley (Freelance)<br />
SPARC Award for Best Single Photo<br />
Marty Melville (Getty Images)</p>
<p>Special Awards:</p>
<p>Air New Zealand Sports Journalist of the Year<br />
Tony Smith (The Press)<br />
Fairfax Media Best Provincial Writer Award<br />
Jamie Troughton (Bay of Plenty Times)<br />
Fairfax Media Best Provincial Photographer Award<br />
John Borren (Bay of Plenty Times)<br />
Garry Frew Memorial for Outstanding Contribution to Provincial Sports Journalism<br />
Phil Quinney (Newstalk ZB, Taranaki)<br />
SPARC Lifetime Contribution to Sport through Journalism<br />
Brendan Telfer (Radio Sport)</p>
<p>For more information please contact:<br />
Armin Lindenberg<br />
520 4427</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/shelflife/2007/12/13/a-parallel-judging-universe/</url><title>A parallel judging universe</title><date>2007-12-13 03:57:58.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Inspired by the announcement that <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://books.guardian.co.uk/news/articles/0,,2225751,00.html" title="'Passionate reader' Lily Allen joins Orange prize judges">Lily Allen is to be one of the judges for Britain's Orange Prize</a></strong>, the organisers of next year's Montana New Zealand Book Awards are poised to announce Hayley Westenra as a member of an expanded judging panel that will also include All Black Dan Carter and Radio New Zealand National's Wayne Mowat. (Jim Mora was, apparently, unavailable.)</p>
<p>My source in the Montana camp tells me the committee that selects the judges for the awards had already approached Carter and Mowat when it caught wind of Allen's appointment and decided "bugger it, let's go the whole hog and finally get some interest in these damned awards".</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/hayley-westenra.jpg" title="Hayley Westenra"><img border="0" vspace="10" align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/hayley-westenra.jpg" hspace="10" alt="Hayley Westenra" /></a>There was a little wariness on the part of some factions of the committee, and at one point the compromise candidate of Anika Moa looked likely to win through. But eventually Westenra's supporters prevailed, arguing: "Moa may put a dozen or more so sales on to a Reference and Anthology winner like William Cottrell's <em>Furniture of the New Zealand Colonial Era</em>, but with Hayley we are talking hundreds, maybe even thousands, more copies. Assuming, of course, Hayley opts for a book like <em>Furniture of the New Zealand Colonial Era</em>. I think with Hayley, and with Dan and Wayne, we can all look forward to some <em>very</em> different winners in 2008."</p>
<p>Previous judging panels have consisted of three members: this year it was academic Paul Millar, writer and reviewer David Larsen and broadcaster Morrin Rout; last year it was academic Lawrence Jones, writer and <em>Dominion Post</em> television critic Linda Burgess and publisher Bob Ross.</p>
<p>"Serious souls, bless," said my Montana mole, "and, yes, readers, but really, when was the last time you saw any of <em>them</em> in the Bridget Saunders column? What does your average New Zealander care about what <em>they</em> think?"</p>
<p>Joining Westenra, Carter and Mowat on what is now a five-strong panel will be bestselling novelist Sarah-Kate Lynch and - the selection committee's concession to concerned literary advisers back at Creative New Zealand - University of Canterbury associate professor <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.engl.canterbury.ac.nz/people/evans.shtml" title="Patrick Evans">Patrick Evans</a></strong>, author of the recently released <em>The Long Forgetting: Post-Colonial Literary Culture in New Zealand</em>.</p>
<p>Evans is also to be the convenor, telling me: "I've already had some lovely chats with Hayley, who has been telling me about this great new Pony Club Secrets series of books by the fashion writer Stacy Gregg. She says <em>Mystic and the Midnight Ride</em> and <em>Blaze and the Dark Rider</em> are to die for. I can't wait to read them."</p>
<p>"It's true," says Westenra. "I'm a judge! Imagine! But I can't talk now - Patrick is just insisting I get back to him as soon as possible with what I think of <em>Waimarino County &amp; Other Excursions</em> by Martin Edmond..."</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/mousedroppings/2007/12/14/classics-never-go-out-of-fashion/</url><title>Classics never go out of fashion</title><date>2007-12-14 02:07:22.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/650-skyhawk.jpg" title="Taking precautions"></p>
<p><img border="1" vspace="5" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/650-skyhawk.jpg" hspace="5" alt="Taking precautions" title="Taking precautions" /></p>
<p></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/650-skyhawk.jpg" title="Taking precautions"></a>Seeing the shrink-wrapped <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322648a11.html"><strong>Skyhawks</strong></a> reminded me of the all but obsolete technology I have squirrelled away in my bedroom.</p>
<p>There's an Apple Powermac G4, circa 2000; it's still a good machine, albeit not a slowish one, but with very little resale value.</p>
<p>I've also got my old digital camera; it takes fine pictures, but doesn't have the sort of megapixel specs that people are so hung up on these days.</p>
<p>Under my bed are several Walkmen in various states of repair, but who plays tapes these days?</p>
<p>I also have a mountain of CDs that I'm unlikely to ever play again and a wardrobe full of clothes that will only see daylight if fashions and my body shape revert to the way things were in 1987.</p>
<p>Okay, fashion is heading that way, but short of me contacting a nasty illness I can't see myself taking part in any kind of retro revolution.</p>
<p>Actually it's the same with the Skyhawks.</p>
<p>The only way they'll be useful in warfare again is if the UN bans all weapons designed after 1970.</p>
<p>Perhaps they'll be dusted off if someone remakes <a target="_blank" href="http://www.moria.co.nz/sf/sleepingdogs.htm"><strong><em>Sleeping Dogs</em></strong></a>.</p>
<p>Oh well, they look kind of cool bagged up in their skin-tight latex sheaths, in a postmodern art/bondage way.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/catwalktalk/2007/12/14/looking-back-on-fashion-for-2007/</url><title>Looking back on fashion for 2007</title><date>2007-12-14 01:51:48.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Its not all done and dusted yet - but since the year of 2007 is almost over, it's probably a good time to reminisce on the events past.</p>
<p>For the fashion world, no one could've expected what events and trends came to be. The trends varied from structured, flowing, masculine, hobo (yet again), rave (thanks to Jeremy Scott), punk, and preppy. Oh and billboard Tees. Cheers House of Holland.</p>
<p>There were <em>Star Wars-</em>style C-3PO Balenciaga leggings designed by the ridiculously talented Nicolas Ghesquière for the Spring 2007 collection, retailing for a cool $159,000 - which brings back the nice and (usually forgotten) idea that money is not an object when it comes to style, and that not everybody needs to blow money on "vintage" pieces to call themselves unique.</p>
<p><img vspace="5" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/10m.jpg" hspace="5" alt="10m.jpg" title="10m.jpg" /></p>
<p>There was Hermes, who created their classic Birkin with Crocodile skin and diamonds retailing for $148,000, and artist Damien Hirst, who made a <strong>life-size human skull</strong> encrusted with 8601 diamonds which sold for a reported $122 million.</p>
<p><img vspace="5" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/1724248531_d87fba7bae_o.jpg" hspace="5" alt="1724248531_d87fba7bae_o.jpg" title="1724248531_d87fba7bae_o.jpg" /></p>
<p>As for fashion shows, Fendi took the cake with their $10,000,000 show, which was situated on none other than the <strong>Great Wall of China</strong>. Designer Karl Lagerfeld was also quick to point out: "The wall is built to be a runway, huh? They don't have to use it for fighting Mongolians anymore; now they can use it for fashion."As for NZ, who could forget our fashion week? I know. Me too.</p>
<p><img vspace="5" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/1112912177_a9fe12a1aa.jpg" hspace="5" alt="1112912177_a9fe12a1aa.jpg" title="1112912177_a9fe12a1aa.jpg" /></p>
<p>It was also interesting to see the emerging trend of designers using the run-down dregs of celebrities as muses for campaigns, collections and media - and I'm not talking Lorraine Downes for Petrena Miller. I'm thinking more along the lines of <strong>Karl Lagerfeld and Courtney Love</strong>. The woman was so high she couldn't even tell she was wearing a fake! And now the legendary designer finds inspiration in the woman? See this is what I'm talking about when I say that this year has been highly unpredictable.</p>
<p>Then there was the "Skinny Debate". C'mon people! Do you think models are paid to sit on fat asses? No. They're paid to be skinny. They always have been and they always will be. If ads looked better shot with average-sized people - then chances are the models would all be out of work.</p>
<p>The year 2007 also lost one of the most fashion-forward people in the business: Isabella Blow. Her signature style was the inspiration for the exhibition which came to our part of the world with "When Phillip met Isabella" at the NewDowse in Wellington.</p>
<p>And for 2008? Well after this year all I can really say "who knows"? But out with the old and in with the new!</p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/1112912177_a9fe12a1aa.jpg" title="1112912177_a9fe12a1aa.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/1724248531_d87fba7bae_o.jpg" title="1724248531_d87fba7bae_o.jpg"></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/10m.jpg" title="10m.jpg"></a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.dropkicks.co.nz/mlb/thats_huge_mitch</url><title>That's a Huge Mitch</title><date>2007-12-13 21:38:06.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img width="275" height="235" align="right" src="http://www.dropkicks.co.nz/modules/htmlarea/Xinha/plugins/ImageManager/image_uploads/_2007_12/V7hcVBAH.jpg" alt="V7hcVBAH.jpg" />The <a href="http://mlb.mlb.com/news/article.jsp?ymd=20071213&amp;content_id=2324860&amp;vkey=news_mlb&amp;fext=.jsp&amp;c_id=mlb">Mitchell Report</a> is out.</p>
<p>I know you’re thinking, “the what?”, but the Mitchell Report may end up being a giant kick in the nutsack to Major League Baseball (or not depending on how much lying happens).</p>
<p>Several high-profile, superstar-caliber players were among those named in­ of former Sen. George Mitchell's report concerning use of performance-enhancing drugs in Major League Baseball. The report was the product of a 21-month, multimillion dollar investigation that could shape decisions, prompt punitive actions against active players, and usher in the next era of the sport.</p>
<p>Free agent Roger Clemens, Andy Pettitte of the New York Yankees, Miguel Tejada of the Houston Astros, Eric Gagne of the Milwaukee Brewers and Paul Lo Duca of the Washington Nationals were among the most prominent former and current All-Stars to be mentioned in the lengthy report, (and by lengthy I mean 409 pages!). The report also contains multiple exhibits, including evidence of signed checks, handwritten notes and shipping receipts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.theonion.com/content/news/destruction_of_national_pastime"><img width="222" height="319" align="left" src="http://www.dropkicks.co.nz/modules/htmlarea/Xinha/plugins/ImageManager/image_uploads/_2007_12/Barry_Bonds_3.jpg" alt="Barry_Bonds_3.jpg" />­</a>The report was delivered with the backdrop of Barry Bonds having just pleaded not guilty last week in a San Francisco federal court on four counts of perjury and one count of obstruction of justice. This is conjunction with BALCO and we know how well that ended for <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/topNews/idUSL1220829120071212">Marion Jones</a>.</p>
<p>But the report is not all doom and horse juice. It also contains a number of recommendations for MLB to move forward.</p>
<p>Have I read it yet? Did I mention 409 pages? I have just got to the end of the list of contents.</p>
<p>But for your reading pleasure the MLB have <a href="http://files.mlb.com/mitchrpt.pdf">uploaded the pdf</a> (6.47Mb) so you can download and read at your leisure (apprently they are working on an easy clickable version too).</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=869</url><title>Two drunk backbenchers</title><date>2007-12-13 23:57:37.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>A mate of mine had a rather interesting run-in last night with a couple of drunken Tory backbenchers. Here's what happened:</p>
<blockquote><p>Last night I was at the Malthouse in Courtenay Place having a few beers with some mates when who should walk into the bar but a couple of National Party backbenchers. We struck up a conversation, and an enlightening one it was. Both Nats had clearly had a few and the rookie’s tongue was looser than I would have thought wise (I noticed his more experienced colleague was far more reserved).</p>
<p>He readily agreed that John Key comes across as ‘a bit smug but he’s a tough bugger and he works us like dogs, as he should’.  We were assured that ‘she’ (Clark, presumably) would ‘knock that smugness out of him in the campaign’. </p>
<p>We were then told that ‘John doesn’t really know what he wants to do if (when, hah!) he becomes Prime Minister and he certainly hasn’t told us!’ But, then ‘He’s new to politics; he shouldn’t know what he wants. He’s just got to hit the right notes with the public’. I gained a striking impression that power was being sought for its own sake, not to make a better New Zealand.  </p>
<p>Searching for some glimmer of a vision, the Nats were asked about where they thought the country should head. ‘Singapore’ was the answer: we should be looking to a city-state on the world’s busiest shipping strait that is run as a mix of autocracy and plutocracy as the model.  Every mention of vision or policy was solely limited to economics: people appeared in the frame merely as commodities and factors of production.</p>
<p>So, maintain and fortify privilege for those who have it, that’s name of the game, and do so by ‘hitting the right notes’.</p>
<p>‘John’, we were informed, ‘could hit the right notes about 85% of the time’ much better than ‘English, who only gets it right 65% of the time’ (note who gets first names, the faction this backbencher sat in was clear).</p>
<p>At this point the slightly nervous-looking, more experienced politician decided it was time they extracted themselves before his friend started telling us intimate details of caucus sessions. We were left amused but more than a little concerned that this is the true face of the National party behind Key’s grinning façade.</p></blockquote>
<p>I imagine the rookie had more than his hangover to worry about this morning.</p>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=869&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_869" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=870</url><title>Turning attention inward: looking at the media</title><date>2007-12-13 23:30:09.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Some <a href="http://www.medialawjournal.co.nz/?p=35">interesting observations</a> from Steven Price on DomPost editor Tim Pankhurst’s keynote address at the <a href="http://communication.massey.ac.nz/index.php?id=887">Jeanz conference</a> called “The Power of Print”.</p>
<p>His speech included this interpretation on the NZ Herald’s Electoral Finance Bill campaign: “He was a bit bemused. “Good on them,” was his attitude. But he thought it would be boring the Herald’s readers to tears.”</p>
<p>Btw I’d missed the <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/category/story.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482002">NZ Herald editorial</a> criticising National on their handling of the EFB including this of Mr Key’s handling: “His attempts have been too low-brow, too detailed and too open to argument.”</p>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=870&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_870" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=868</url><title>National reopens Selwyn race</title><date>2007-12-13 22:53:45.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Local Nats don't want David Carter as their candidate for Selwyn.</p>
<p>Looks like the threats, intimidation and bullying tactics used to get him the candidacy have backfired for him. Carter (himself a three time loser to Labour's Ruth Dyson in Banks Peninsula) has a history of bagging other candidates within his party.</p>
<p>He said of Brian Connell, when selected for Rakaia in 2002, that National "didn't get a hell of a good line-up of candidates... they weren't bad but there was nobody who was a stunner" (Chch Press, 3 Oct 2006).</p>
<p>Well the local party people didn't toss Brian Connell back quite as fast as they're trying to bin David Carter - they're right to of course because in his own words - he isn't a stunner either.</p>
<p>My bet is that John Key will still want him to win the selection and that Carter will be forced on the electorate against the wishes of the local Nats. Democracy - National style.</p>
<p>From the <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/thepress/4323181a19720.html">Press</a> this morning:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>National reopens Selwyn race</strong></p>
<p>National MP David Carter will battle up to 12 rival candidates for the Selwyn seat after the party's board agreed to an embarrassing selection rerun.</p>
<p>Nominations for electorates across the country have closed, but National president Judy Kirk said yesterday the board had decided to reopen the Selwyn contest in February after 35 party members lodged a formal complaint...</p>
<p>It is understood the candidates were warned several front-bench National MPs would publicly campaign for Carter to get the nod if they put their names forward.</p>
<p>Carter's colleagues felt such a senior MP should not have to face a selection battle against newcomers...</p>
<p>In its complaint to the board, the disgruntled group of party members said Carter should have known the selection process was flawed. "His future as a Cabinet minister will often put him under the spotlight and, if this is a sign of his true judgment, then we may be headed for turbulent times with him as a minister of the Crown," the letter says...</p></blockquote>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=868&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_868" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=865</url><title>No democracy for the Selwyn National Party?</title><date>2007-12-13 04:20:09.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Colin Espiner has a story in yesterday's Press saying that the heads of three National Party branches in the Canterbury district supported by 35 other party members have made a <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/thepress/4320472a24035.html">formal complaint to National President Judy Kirk alleging breaches of rules</a> by the selection committee for the Selwyn candidate for  National. List MP David Carter's was the only name placed before the pre-selection committee. One other candidate is reported as saying that he had been "notified by the preselection committee that he would not be going further in the process".</p>
<p>Regina Christey, a former electorate secretary, in a letter in the paper on the same day, said the process was "disgusting"; with "not one meet-the-candidates meeting of party members, no confirmation of who sat on the selection panel, attempts to bully candidates into withdrawing, no open delegate selection.'</p>
<p>She raises some important points in her letter, published on page A19 - "Did any meeting waive the right of members in the electorate to select the candidate, or was it a case of the National Party board assuming the right to choose for the people of this district? Why did the selection process differ from that in the party's rules?"</p>
<p>If the process was different from the rules the National Party is in breach of the Electoral Act. Clause 71 of the Act sets out a legal requirement for registered parties to follow democratic procedures in candidate selection. Provision must be made for participation in the selection of candidates by current financial members of the party who are entitled to vote, or by delegates who have been elected by current financial members. The party's rules governing the selection of candidates must be filed with the Electoral Commission.</p>
<p>Judy Kirk said she was looking into  the concerns and would deal with them "in the appropriate way." It will be interesting to see if that does provide for a more democratic process; or perhaps the National Party this time around wants to hang on to its dead wood?</p>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=865&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_865" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
