<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Politics</title>
<item>
<url>http://lindsaymitchell.blogspot.com/2007/12/wrong-motivation.html</url><title>The wrong motivation</title><date>2007-12-13 09:37:01.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
I came across this on another blog. It's a Left blog that appears to have attacking David Farrar and others as its reason for being. It is even styled after the very popular Kiwiblog. Naturally its contributors are anonymous.<br /><br /> <span>Linking whoring to Lindsay Mitchell is not going to help you, Ms Mitchell’s barely numerate.....I’ve read Mitchell’s commentary before and she struggles to make out coherent argument and doesn’t deal with stats well. Her problem of course may not be numeracy, it may be that her arguments don’t stack up with you look for data…</span><br /><br />Wouldn't it be better if the poster had simply questioned my arguments here? If I get things wrong - and I do - I'm not going to get it right without somebody pointing out the error. But what this comment really brings home is the propensity of some (many?) on the Left to malign people rather than their ideas. Trevor Mallard leaps to mind.<br /><br />And I question the motivation of these types. Their interest in politics seems to stem largely from the pleasure they take in fighting and hating. That's a shame because they give politics a bad name and ward off others who might have a worthy contribution to make. We mustn't let that happen.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/12/green-party-hypocrites-justify-support.html</url><title>Green Party Hypocrites Justify Support for Electoral Finance Bill</title><date>2007-12-14 08:08:58.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
The Green Party is worried. Stung by recent low polling, they've figured out that its probably related to their support for Labour's hugely unpopular Electoral Finance Bill.<br /><br />Here's some extracts from a mass email sent out in the name of their <a href="http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/05/is-russel-norman-being-little.html">formerly?Trotskyist co-leader Russel Norman </a>and their <a href="http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/11/not-so-happy-valley-campers-green-party.html">anarchist MP, Metiria Turei</a>.<br /><br />Some comment from me in bold.<br /><br /><em>Protecting free speech and fairer elections<br />  <br />Please forward this email to as many people as you can to get the truth out there.<br />  <br />Many of you will have seen media reports and even paid advertising about the Electoral Finance Bill. Given the controversy around this Bill, we thought it was important that we wrote to you directly to explain the Green position.<br /> <br />The Electoral Finance Bill deals with one of the most important issues in our democracy - controls on the financing of election campaigns to protect the integrity of the ballot from the inequality of the wallet.</em><br /> <br /><em>The Greens have had many concerns about this Bill but we have chosen to work constructively with all parties. Our aim has been to improve the laws around campaign finance so that we<br />- have a fairer election system,<br />- ensure a more level playing field, and<br />- limit the corrupting influence of large secret donations on political parties.<br /> <br />The opponents of campaign finance reform<br /> <br />However, much of the publicity that has surrounded this Bill has been one-sided and, in fact, some has even been funded by wealthy donors who want the law to stay the same. They are trying to frighten New Zealanders by saying the Bill impacts on freedom of speech – this is not true.</em><br /><br /><strong>A little dig at private individual John Boscawen, who has funded the anti EFB campaign largely out of his own pocket.</strong><br /> <br /><em>Some media organisations have also been running an active and misleading campaign against the Bill. Journalists have contacted us to tell us that they oppose the misleading editorial line of their papers, but it is very difficult for them to get their views across.</em> <br /><br /><strong>Paranoia runs deep.</strong><br /><br /><em>So what does the Bill do (and what doesn't it do)?<br /> <br />* The Bill does not restrict freedom of speech – it just caps election campaign spending.<br />* Any person or group can purchase as much issue advertising as they want at any time.<br />* The Bill only places limits on how much election advertising political parties and others can purchase in an election year. That limit is $2.4m for political parties and $120,000 for any other group or individual.<br />* Any group or individual who purchases more than $12,000 in election ads must register with the Electoral Commission so there is transparency about who is involved in the election campaign.</em><br /><br /><strong>All this clearly inhibits free speech. One point the Greens fail to address is the real reasons donors should be able to remain anonymous-political revenge.<br /><br />We have anonymous voting, so that no voter need feel intimidated by a potentially vindictive victor. <br /><br />Many businesses in mixed economy New Zealand rely on government contracts for at least part of their income. Some business people already feel too intimidated to overtly support anti government parties. This bill will make that worse, potentially reducing funding for pro-business parties-a point I'm sure that was not overlooked by the bill's leftist framers.</strong><br /><br /><em>The spending caps exist to stop parties spending millions on campaigning and then needing to raise those millions in donations. Once parties rely on millions in donations they become heavily influenced by those who provide the money. The caps on political parties only work if there are caps on spending by other groups, otherwise the money goes into parallel campaigns.</em><br /><br /><strong>Having to raise money from donors-large or small, makes parties more responsive to the public. It engenders some humility. The alternative is open or covert state funding of political parties. This makes parties even less connected to the public and even more arrogant than they are now. </strong> <br /><br /><em>Closing the loopholes<br /> <br />Those who are most strongly opposed to the Bill took advantage of two major loopholes in our electoral financing regime in 2005.<br /> <br />- The first loophole enabled an organisation to work with a political party to run an almost identical campaign - known as parallel campaigning. This meant that the spending of the organisation was not capped even though it was a planned party election campaign.</em><br /><br /><strong>A clear dig at the Exclusive Brethren. Why should private individuals not be able to support anyone they like with their own tax paid cash?</strong><br /><br /><strong>Greenpeace has been supporting Green Party campaigns for years-using tax deductible donations, even though Greenpeace is a clearly political organisation and has openly advised against voting National in the past.</strong><br /> <br /><em>- The second loophole allowed for millions of dollars to be given to political parties without the public knowing who gave that money. Both the USA and Australian electoral systems have suffered from the corruption that arises from the secret funding of political parties.</em><br /><br /><strong>All paranoid speculation stated as fact. The New Zealand left has enjoyed huge financial and "volunteer" labour contributions from unions, Greenpeace etc, over many years. </strong> <br /><br /><em>The Greens are proud to assist in the closing of those two loopholes. This work will protect our electoral system from the threats of corruption that other similar democracies face.<br /> <br />It's far from perfect<br /> <br />However, we still have some outstanding issues with the Bill and with the process for these electoral law reforms. We are still pursing the option of a citizens' assembly which would allow for a number of randomly selected citizens to consider the issues of electoral finance and to find the best system for New Zealand. This system has been used successfully in Canada and we believe that the people of New Zealand should be able to make these decisions.<br /> <br />We have not achieved the ban on anonymous donations over $1000 that is our policy. However we have severely restricted the anonymous donations that can be received by both a third party and a political party. This is a major change in the law and goes someway towards a system that is open about who is funding political campaigns.<br /> <br />Changes the Greens achieved in the Bill<br /> <br />In summary, the Greens have made the following amendments:<br /> <br />Amendments to protect freedom of speech<br /> <br />1. Alter the definition of election advertising to protect issues advertising. This means that individuals and groups will be free to campaign on the issues that are important to them, regardless of whether one or more parties is also campaigning on the same issue. The Greens come from a campaigning background and we were determined to protect the right of groups to continue to campaign. For example, Greenpeace can continue to campaign against whaling, even though it is a campaign the Green Party has a profile on.</em><br /><br /><strong>Has Greenpeace, which has been extremely worried about this bill had a word in the Green Party's ear. No that couldn't possibly be. The Green Party is completely opposed to any covert influence on the electoral system.</strong><br /> <br /><em>2. Remove the requirement for a statutory declaration for spending less than the threshold. This means that people or groups don't have to sign a statutory declaration every time they spend money under the threshold for listing as a third party. It was an unnecessary burden that performed no useful function.<br /> <br />3. Lift the cap on election spending by non-party groups from $60,000 to $120,000. Many groups and individuals engage in election advertising during campaign year. This advertising encourages voters to support parties that adopt certain policy positions. The Bill as introduced limited this spending to $60,000. The Greens have supported amendments that increase this limit to $120,000, 5% of the $2.4m party limit and twice that originally proposed.<br /> <br />4. Lift the spending limit at which a group must list as a third party from $5000 to $12,000. This was important because many groups and people engage in election advertising through pamphlets, newsletters or community newspaper adverts. These ordinary election activities should not require a person or group to have to list as a third party where the spending is under $12,000.<br /> <br />5. Enable under 18 year olds and permanent residents to be able to list as a third party. We fought for the inclusion of this because it is a breach of the rights of a citizen to be prevented from engaging in election advertising activities simply because they are not old enough to vote. This change also means that groups will not be excluded from listing as a third party simply because one member is under 18 years old.<br /> <br />6. Protect donations to groups that are not for election purposes. This means that groups that register as third party participants in the election will not have to declare any donations that are not specifically for election purposes.<br />Groups are entitled to raise and collect money for their regular activities without interference. Only donations given specifically for electioneering will need to be disclosed.<br /> <br />Amendment to restrict anonymous donations<br /> <br />7. Severely restrict anonymous donations to political and third parties. The Greens insisted on an anonymous donations regime that will restrict Labour and National's ability to raise money through anonymous donations. Our policy is that all donations over $1000 should be identified as to the true source – they shouldn't be listed as anonymous nor should they be hidden behind secret trusts.<br /> <br />In negotiations over this bill we have made progress towards achieving our policy by introducing a system that will limit political parties to a total anonymous donations income, for donations over $1000, of 10% of their spending cap over the three year electoral cycle – this would cut Labour's anonymous donations income by at least half and National's secret trust income by about 90%. Labour and National don't like it but we make no apologies for this.</em><br /><br /><strong>Labour will make up the shortfall by giving more money to the unions, (which will launder it back to Labour) and by milking the state tit. National will be forced to support state funding of political parties. Any parties, like ACT, that are vehemently opposed to state funding will be disadvantaged.</strong> <br /><br /><em>In addition the money must be passed via the Electoral Commission to distance the parties from the process and donors must identify themselves to the Electoral Commission and give an assurance that they are not telling the parties about the donation on the sly. There is a limit of $36,000 on how much any one donor can give to a political party via this mechanism.<br /> <br />Best wishes<br /> <br />Metiria and Russel<br /> <br />Metiria is the Green MP responsible for the Bill in the House; Russel is Spokesperson on Electoral Matters.</em><br /><br /><strong>No doubt Greenpeace will be very happy about all their friends, the Green Party has done for them.</strong>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2007/12/will-aussie-communists-greens-push-for.html</url><title>Will Aussie Communists, Greens Push for Proportional Representation?</title><date>2007-12-13 08:08:15.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
The Communist Party of Australia backed the Greens in the recent election. The Greens increased their vote but gained no seats.<br /><br />From an editorial in the Communist Party of Australia's latest <a href="http://www.cpa.org.au/garchve07/1349edit.html">Guardian</a><br /><br /><em>Overall votes for The Greens increased. They won over one million first preference votes in the House of Representatives but did not win a single seat. This again raises the need to change the voting system to one of proportional representation if Parliament is to be reflective of the political opinions of major sections of the community and bring an end to the discrimination against smaller parties.<br /><br />Although a system of proportional representation remains the policy of the ALP as well as The Greens, the Communist Party and others, it remains to be seen whether the ALP will change the voting laws in this respect without a major popular campaign in the future.</em><br /><br />In New Zealand the retrograde shift to proportional representation (MMP) was <a href="http://newzeal.blogspot.com/2006/01/mmp-more-marxists-in-parliament-part-1.html">driven by the Greens and the pro-Soviet, Socialist Unity Party</a>.<br /><br />Look for a similar campaign from the Australian Greens, the Communist Party of Australia and the left wing unions in the near future.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5481</url><title>Herald Editorial says "Give it back"</title><date>2007-12-13 19:17:55.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/466/story.cfm?c_id=466&amp;objectid=10482229" rel="nofollow">Editorial: Starship should give money back - 14 Dec 2007 - Opinion, Editorial and reader comments from New Zealand and around the World -&nbsp;nzherald</a></p>
<p><div class="quote-msg"><div class="quote-author">Quote:</div>The Starship children's hospital should immediately return the cheque it has received from the New Zealand First Party. This money is public&nbsp;property.</p>
<p>Winston Peters has given the $158,000 due the taxpayer to a charity of his choosing. If any other taxpayer did this the Inland Revenue would pursue him for the&nbsp;debt.</p>
<p>Mr Peters has not technically broken the law but only because he has used his party's votes in Parliament to help legalise the spending at the last election that the Auditor-General believes to be wrong. He has always disagreed with the Auditor-General's ruling and had wanted to contest it in the courts. But he has dropped this action, he says, because he could not have gotten a decision before the election next year and did not want to face the election accused of refusing to pay back "stolen&nbsp;money".</p>
<p>So he has given it to the Starship. It is extraordinary that the hospital has accepted the money in these circumstances. It perhaps has not given enough thought to the&nbsp;implications.</p>
<p>Advertisement<br />&nbsp;Advertisement</p>
<p>It is letting itself be used for a petty political purpose. Mr Peters is using public sympathy for sick children to avoid a payment he believes his party should not have to make. Rather than accept the ruling against him and return the money to the public purse he has put the amount in a place he calculates to be beyond public&nbsp;reproach.</p>
<p>The Starship is being cynically used and must know it. The hospital is part of the public health service. By accepting a donation that properly belongs to the public revenue it is complicit in an act of political manipulation and potentially depriving parts of the health service that may be less well endowed of&nbsp;funds.</p>
<p>If the hospital means to keep this money it is obliged to explain to taxpayers why it believes the <span class="caps">NZ</span> First Party was entitled to dispose of the misspent election funds as it wished. This is not a political-legal dispute a public hospital would be wise to enter. The Starship would be well advised to return the cheque or, even better, pay it into the public accounts where it&nbsp;belongs.</p>
<p>As for Mr Peters, the public doesn't seem surprised. Stunts of transparent nonsense have long been his preferred mode of operation. Most people have ceased to take him too seriously. He is excused for impish behaviour that would not be accepted from anyone else in public&nbsp;office.</p>
<p>Seldom, though, has he displayed such contempt for public opinion and public finance as he has on this occasion. He freely admitted yesterday that the misuse of party allowances at the 2005 election was an issue "on which the court of public opinion had already made its final&nbsp;ruling".</p>
<p>Since his party could not get a contrary declaration from the courts before the end of next year, he said, it proceeded to raise the amount the Auditor-General ruled that it owed but it was not willing to see the money disappear into the Government coffers.</div></p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5479</url><title>National tactics bring House back next week</title><date>2007-12-13 19:03:09.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482259&amp;ref=rss" rel="nofollow">National tactics bring House back next week</a> - <i>National's delaying tactics in Parliament have forced MPs to return to work next Tuesday to pass the contentious Electoral Finance Bill, instead of starting their Christmas holidays.<br />
Deputy Prime Minister and Leader of the House...</i> [<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/" rel="nofollow"><span class="caps">NZ</span> Politics</a>]
</p>
<p>
National has rather cleverly used the House rules to delay the passing of the Electoral Finance Bill until next&nbsp;Tuesday.
</p>
<p>
Cullen, of course, is sniffy about it all. He had organised a little rorting of the rules himself so that they could drop the Urgency pretense for a short while and pass the bill, then resume urgency....just so they can say they didn't pass the law under&nbsp;urgency.
</p>
<p>
National should now ask 500 questions on Tuesday and try to get these corrupt bastards into urgency. Fight till the&nbsp;last. 
</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://blog.greens.org.nz/index.php/2007/12/13/canada-japan-and-us-must-commit-to-binding-targets/</url><title>Canada, Japan and US must commit to binding targets</title><date>2007-12-13 02:27:05.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>There's an expression that goes something like ‘this is where the rubber hits the road'.  Well, that's probably the opposite of the outcome we want from Bali. But the time has definitely come to find whether our global representatives can commit to doing something before they leave the Indonesian island.</p>
<p>The UN is clearly worried that things sit in the balance:</p>
<blockquote><p>"The situation is so desperately serious that any delay could push us past the <a href="http://www.theglobeandmail.com/servlet/story/LAC.20071212.BALIMAIN12/TPStory/TPInternational/Asia/">tipping point</a>, beyond which the ecological, financial and human costs would increase dramatically," United Nations Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon.</p></blockquote>
<blockquote><p>"We are at a crossroad," he said. "One path leads to a comprehensive climate-change agreement, the other to oblivion. The choice is clear."</p></blockquote>
<p>But it appears three nations are failing to rise to the challenge.  The USA, Japan and Canada are blocking a global plan for a binding agreement on targets for reducing greenhouse gas emissions.</p>
<p>Jeanette Fitzsimons is calling on New Zealanders to <a href="http://www.greens.org.nz/searchdocs/PR11482.html">email the embassies</a> of these countries and plead with them to join the global consensus:</p>
<blockquote><p>"The opposition from these three countries is likely to scuttle any hope of including binding emission reduction targets into any road map for future talks on climate change.</p>
<p>Climate change is not something that will affect just a few countries. It will affect us all and we all have to pull together, put aside politics, and get on with doing everything we can to reduce its impact."</p></blockquote>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/devil-you-know-or-devil-who-was.html</url><title>The Devil you know, or the Devil who was acquitted</title><date>2007-12-14 17:29:30.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_Yu6lJst3lkM/R2HZpvLRmnI/AAAAAAAAAF8/tLlwLWT8RWg/s1600-h/zuma_jacob_cp_9967240.jpg"><img src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_Yu6lJst3lkM/R2HZpvLRmnI/AAAAAAAAAF8/tLlwLWT8RWg/s400/zuma_jacob_cp_9967240.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143631560495438450" /></a><a href="http://www.mg.co.za/articlePage.aspx?articleid=327583&area=/breaking_news/breaking_news__national/">ANC on knife edge</a>:<br /><i>A total of 4 075 voting delegates are expected [...] for a five-yearly conference which will be dominated by the contest between Mbeki and Zuma.<br />While no one is writing Mbeki off, Zuma is the frontrunner having secured around 60% of votes in the nine provincial branches as well as the full backing of the youth and women's leagues, all of which send voting delegates [...]<br />He also has the support of the ANC's two powerful leftist allies -- the Congress of South African Trade Unions and South African Communist Party.</i><br /><br />Zuma has the backing of the Women's League even after his rape trial - that must tell you what they think of Mbeki.  The corruption allegations were thrown out on a technicality, but there could be arms charges...<br /><br /><a href="http://www.thestar.co.za/?fSectionId=&fArticleId=vn20071212045007208C558999">The Star reports</a> a bleak assessment for combating the HIV/AIDS epidemic:<br /><i>The Treatment Action Campaign (TAC) says it can tolerate Jacob Zuma's previous strange views on Aids more than President Thabo Mbeki's denialist stance.<br />This is despite Zuma's eccentric comments during his rape trial that a shower minimised the chances of contracting the HI virus. <br />Zuma was acquitted and later apologised for his comments.<br /></i>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/im-sorry-you-did-what-with-money-you.html</url><title>I'm sorry - you did what with the money you took out of the public purse?</title><date>2007-12-13 14:04:18.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2CDVV_qjWI/AAAAAAAACQE/EzpeitO1bYU/s1600-h/peters.jpg"><img src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_Qy4iftwk5JM/R2CDVV_qjWI/AAAAAAAACQE/EzpeitO1bYU/s400/peters.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143255177161772386" /></a><br /><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&objectid=10482118">NZ First debt for Starship</a><br /><i>New Zealand First has paid $158,000 to Starship hospital - the amount Auditor General Kevin Brady found it spent unlawfully in the 2005 election. Leader Winston Peters made the announcement in Parliament yesterday, saying that while the party had done nothing wrong, it accepted it had lost the argument in the court of public opinion. But he immediately drew taunts of "pay it back" from the National benches.</i><br /><br />Ummmmmmmmmmmmmm - what? NZ First took $158 000 from the public purse when they shouldn't have, all parties have paid the money back to the public purse - for NZ First to simply state they have 'paid' the $158 000 to Starship hospital and that's that is jaw dropping in it's totally irrational decision making - NZ First owes the money back to the public coffers, they can't take $158 000 and then 'pay' it back to a charity and claim the bill has been paid - what sort of scotch drenched bullshit is this?]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/hive_mentality_in_nbr.html</url><title>Hive Mentality in NBR</title><date>2007-12-14 00:16:24.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>A mention of blogs in the <a href="http://www.nbr.co.nz">National Business Review</a>'s Hive Mentality column:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>4. Don't sniff the potatoes<br />
</em></p>
<p><em> Technology promised to make every citizen with a cellphone a journalist. Instead, everyone is a potential stalker. As America gears up for its "YouTube election," the combination of online and cellphone video is making its presence felt here too. </em></p>
<p><em>The left has scrambled, but made ground quickly in these tabloid stakes. The Standard, a Labour Party mouthpiece blog, has uploaded sly video footage of John Key sniffing vegetables in an unwieldy fashion at a market - the left-wing sequel to the Exclusive Brethren's tasteless rubbish-rummaging of minister's last year. The Standard also led the "John Key illegal downloads" story. </em></p>
<p><em>On the right, the National Party's David Farrar made the early running online with careful analytical posts; Farrar's talent is summarising complex issues for journalists simply but comprehensively, but not so much so that readers could come to a different conclusion to him.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>It's a pity I can't post the whole column - it's very good.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/disclosure-2.html</url><title>Disclosure</title><date>2007-12-13 23:43:51.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Some commenters on the left are always going on about the important of disclosure, and go into a fury if a Richard Long column (for example) doesn't appear with a disclaimer that he used to work for Don Brash (as indeed did I).</p>
<p>And I noticed yesterday The Standard also finally managed to <a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=859#comment-9812">find a column</a> in a newspaper in favour of the Electoral Finance Bill.</p>
<p>It is written by Simon Cunliffe, a senior ODT journalist.</p>
<p>Strangely though, they did not think it necessary to mention that Mr Cunliffe was just two months ago a press secretary to a Labour Minister.</p>
<p>Now I don't think this in anyway diminishes the legitimacy of Simon Cunliffe's opinion.  He has every right to write his honest opinion of the Electoral Finance Bill.</p>
<p>I just thought there was a double standard for those insisting every Richard Long column mention his previous job (which now was over two years ago) and not applying the same standard to someone who had a political role much more recently.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/nz_first_on_electoral_reform.html</url><title>NZ First on Electoral Reform</title><date>2007-12-13 19:09:34.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>A commenter yesterday pointed out a clause in <a href="http://www.nzfirst.org.nz/principles/index.php">NZ First's 15 fundamental principles</a>, which highlights their hypocrisy on the Electoral Finance Bill:</p>
<blockquote><p><em><strong>Electoral Reform</strong></em></p>
<p><em>Electoral reform will be determined by the electors. The Government's duty will be to ensure the fair representation of all views and the holding of appropriate referenda. </em></p></blockquote>
<p>So consider this:</p>
<ol>
<li>The public had no notice before the last election of electoral law changes</li>
<li>NZ First negotiated in secret with Labour on electoral law changes</li>
<li>There was no public policy process to allow policy to be set on which the law was based</li>
<li>Opinion polls (Colmar Brunton) have shown the majority against further third party restrictions</li>
<li>The Human Rights Commission called for a second round of public submissions, which NZ First ignored</li>
<li>The public will be restrained from criticising those who voted for the law, by the law.</li>
</ol>
<p>So is that what NZ First calls having electoral reform determined by the electors?</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/herald_calls_on_starship_to_give_the_money_back.html</url><title>Herald calls on Starship to give the money back</title><date>2007-12-13 18:54:58.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Winston's stunt may be backfiring. The <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/story.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482229">Herald editorial</a> is blunt:</p>
<p>The Starship children's hospital should immediately return the cheque it has received from the New Zealand First Party. This money is public property.</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Mr Peters has not technically broken the law but only because he has used his party's votes in Parliament to help legalise the spending at the last election that the Auditor-General believes to be wrong. He has always disagreed with the Auditor-General's ruling and had wanted to contest it in the courts. But he has dropped this action, he says, because he could not have gotten a decision before the election next year and did not want to face the election accused of refusing to pay back "stolen money".</em></p></blockquote>
<p>This claim that they could not have got a hearing in time is one media should treat with suspicion.  The Auditor-General ruled in the latter half of 2006.  I have not seen anything to suggest that one could not have got a court hearing within two years.  For example the lawsuit against the Electoral Finance Bill only has a six month wait for a hearing.</p>
<p>The other point to remember is that there was a lawsuit which would have tested whether the Auditor-General was correct.  Darnton vs Clark.  With regards to the Labour pledge card at least, this would have resulted in a court ruling whether or not the expenditure was legal.</p>
<p>NZ First voted to kill off the lawsuit, voting against an amendment that would have stopped the validating legislation retrospectively killing off the lawsuit.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5481</url><title>Herald Editorial says "Give it back"</title><date>2007-12-13 19:17:55.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/466/story.cfm?c_id=466&amp;objectid=10482229" rel="nofollow">Editorial: Starship should give money back - 14 Dec 2007 - Opinion, Editorial and reader comments from New Zealand and around the World -&nbsp;nzherald</a></p>
<p><div class="quote-msg"><div class="quote-author">Quote:</div>The Starship children's hospital should immediately return the cheque it has received from the New Zealand First Party. This money is public&nbsp;property.</p>
<p>Winston Peters has given the $158,000 due the taxpayer to a charity of his choosing. If any other taxpayer did this the Inland Revenue would pursue him for the&nbsp;debt.</p>
<p>Mr Peters has not technically broken the law but only because he has used his party's votes in Parliament to help legalise the spending at the last election that the Auditor-General believes to be wrong. He has always disagreed with the Auditor-General's ruling and had wanted to contest it in the courts. But he has dropped this action, he says, because he could not have gotten a decision before the election next year and did not want to face the election accused of refusing to pay back "stolen&nbsp;money".</p>
<p>So he has given it to the Starship. It is extraordinary that the hospital has accepted the money in these circumstances. It perhaps has not given enough thought to the&nbsp;implications.</p>
<p>Advertisement<br />&nbsp;Advertisement</p>
<p>It is letting itself be used for a petty political purpose. Mr Peters is using public sympathy for sick children to avoid a payment he believes his party should not have to make. Rather than accept the ruling against him and return the money to the public purse he has put the amount in a place he calculates to be beyond public&nbsp;reproach.</p>
<p>The Starship is being cynically used and must know it. The hospital is part of the public health service. By accepting a donation that properly belongs to the public revenue it is complicit in an act of political manipulation and potentially depriving parts of the health service that may be less well endowed of&nbsp;funds.</p>
<p>If the hospital means to keep this money it is obliged to explain to taxpayers why it believes the <span class="caps">NZ</span> First Party was entitled to dispose of the misspent election funds as it wished. This is not a political-legal dispute a public hospital would be wise to enter. The Starship would be well advised to return the cheque or, even better, pay it into the public accounts where it&nbsp;belongs.</p>
<p>As for Mr Peters, the public doesn't seem surprised. Stunts of transparent nonsense have long been his preferred mode of operation. Most people have ceased to take him too seriously. He is excused for impish behaviour that would not be accepted from anyone else in public&nbsp;office.</p>
<p>Seldom, though, has he displayed such contempt for public opinion and public finance as he has on this occasion. He freely admitted yesterday that the misuse of party allowances at the 2005 election was an issue "on which the court of public opinion had already made its final&nbsp;ruling".</p>
<p>Since his party could not get a contrary declaration from the courts before the end of next year, he said, it proceeded to raise the amount the Auditor-General ruled that it owed but it was not willing to see the money disappear into the Government coffers.</div></p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5479</url><title>National tactics bring House back next week</title><date>2007-12-13 19:03:09.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482259&amp;ref=rss" rel="nofollow">National tactics bring House back next week</a> - <i>National's delaying tactics in Parliament have forced MPs to return to work next Tuesday to pass the contentious Electoral Finance Bill, instead of starting their Christmas holidays.<br />
Deputy Prime Minister and Leader of the House...</i> [<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/" rel="nofollow"><span class="caps">NZ</span> Politics</a>]
</p>
<p>
National has rather cleverly used the House rules to delay the passing of the Electoral Finance Bill until next&nbsp;Tuesday.
</p>
<p>
Cullen, of course, is sniffy about it all. He had organised a little rorting of the rules himself so that they could drop the Urgency pretense for a short while and pass the bill, then resume urgency....just so they can say they didn't pass the law under&nbsp;urgency.
</p>
<p>
National should now ask 500 questions on Tuesday and try to get these corrupt bastards into urgency. Fight till the&nbsp;last. 
</p>
<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=866</url><title>NZ leads the world on climate change in Bali</title><date>2007-12-13 21:05:29.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Here's a clip that aired last night on TV3.</p>
<p>It shows NZ leading the world in our response to climate change in Bali. To quote the reporter, New Zealand is "...putting words into action... [announcing] ambitious plans to go carbon neutral".</p>



<p>
<p>National on the other hand has no credibility on climate change. They don't have any real answers. Many of them, including John Key, are climate-change deniers.</p>
<p>As Phil Goff put it in this <a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=F7k9LUV7szY">YouTube clip</a> four months ago, "There are two big issues facing the world. In terms of conflict - Iraq. In terms of wider issues it's about global warming. In both cases, John Key has got it wrong."</p>
<p>Evidently Key's personal ambition doesn't stretch as far as helping to save the planet.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/28_large1.thumbnail.jpg" title="28_large1.jpg" alt="28_large1.jpg" height="72" hspace="5" width="50" /></p>
<p><strong>“[Climate change] is a complete and utter hoax.”</strong><br />
<em> (Hansard, 10 May 2005)</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/billenglish.thumbnail.jpg" title="billenglish.jpg" alt="billenglish.jpg" height="71" hspace="5" width="50" /></p>
<p><strong>“[I’m] quite worried that policies are going to be driven by this Armageddon mentality that the world has… far too much carbon.”</strong><br />
<em> (Investigate, Feb 2007)</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/44_large.thumbnail.jpg" title="44_large.jpg" alt="44_large.jpg" height="68" hspace="5" width="50" /></p>
<p><strong>“I am a climate change sceptic. There I’ve said it.”</strong><br />
<em> (Ashburton Guardian, 10 Nov 2006 )</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/61_large.thumbnail.jpg" title="61_large.jpg" alt="61_large.jpg" height="72" hspace="5" width="50" /></p>
<p><strong>“I am not inclined to agree with the Government’s view that there is a scientific consensus on climate change.”</strong><br />
<em> (Wairarapa News, 16 Aug 2006)</em></p>
<p><img src="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/09/26_large.thumbnail.jpg" title="26_large.jpg" alt="26_large.jpg" height="72" hspace="5" width="50" /></p>
<p><strong>“As a politician I am not sure about this climate change story.”</strong><br />
<em> (Hansard, 17 Feb 2004)</em></p>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=866&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_866" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
