<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Sport</title>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~3/198348769/2007-days-of-christmas.html</url><title>The 2007 'Days Of Christmas'</title><date>2007-12-13 11:58:08.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/wales/christmas/"><img src="http://www.bbc.co.uk/wales/christmas/images/main_promos/index_promo02.jpg" /></a><br /></div><br />As is becoming something of a <a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2006/12/days-of-christmas-postings-and-other.html">tradition</a> here at MiramarMike, this is my Yuletide posting about all that you should know for Christmas. But let's just take a moment in the busy day to remember what it's all about - the people you love. I'm thinking of the people you love right now ... are you thinking of mine?<br /><br />Of course, it's not just about family and friends (if that's who I was thinking of) but also presents, alcohol and oodles of sitting around in the sun (hardy har har Northern Hempishpereans!)<br /><br />If Jesus is you thing, I mean, if he's your bag, what you're into man then do the religious thing as well. Just don't get all "God" over Christmas and try to remember that it was originally a pagan festival around the longest day, certainly don't want you Christians foisting your ideas on people and trying to subvert the real message!<br /><br />Fun. that's the real message. Believe in Father Christmas (who shats all over Santa) and have too much laughter with the people you love. I'm thinking of laughing at the people you love right this moment, are you?<br /><br />The Christmas collection of articles starts with my outline of the perfect Christmas Day - <a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2005/12/tis-season-to-be-jolly.html">'Tis the season to be jolly</a> - which needs some serious updating; these however do not:<br /><ul><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/12/ballyhoo-game-for-christmas.html">Ballyhoo - a game for Christmas</a></li><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/10/and-cry-from-children-was.html">And the cry from the children was, "Is it Christmas yet?"</a></li><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/10/christmas-is-coming-and-so-is-last.html">Christmas is coming ...</a> (best Yuletide and all year shopping in Wellington)<br /></li><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2005/12/christmas-in-wales-according-to-bbc.html">Christmas in Wales (according to the BBC) / Mrs Beeton</a></li><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/12/google-joins-norad-in-its-traditional.html" title="Permanent link to 'Google joins NORAD in it's traditional Santa Tracking'">Google joins NORAD in it's traditional Santa Tracking</a></li></ul><br /><a href="http://flickr.com/search/?q=christmas%20cartoon&amp;w=97387245%40N00&amp;m=tags" title="Flickr: Christmas cartoons"><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/54/132091317_2bea4d3786_m.jpg" alt="Flickr: Christmas cartoons" align="right" /></a>Some Christmas humour to warm the bits of your cockles ...<br /><ul><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2005/12/scientific-analysis-of-santa-claus.html">A scientific analysis of Santa Claus</a></li><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2005/12/joke-for-christmas.html">Joke for Christmas</a> + <a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2004/12/lunchtime-meanderings.html">here</a><br /></li><li><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2004/12/update-from-north-pole-famous-reindeer.html">Update from the North Pole: <span>Famous Reindeer Terminated</span></a></li><li><a href="http://flickr.com/search/?q=christmas%20cartoon&amp;w=97387245%40N00&amp;m=tags">My Christmas cartoon collection</a><span></span><br /></li></ul><br /><div><span class="itemshown" id="b110383359794397298"><strong><span>M<span>e</span>rry C<span>h</span>ristmas a<span>n</span>d H<span>a</span>ppy N<span>e</span>w Y<span>e</span>ar</span></strong></span><br /></div><div class="blogger-post-footer"><hr />
<small>
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/search/label/enterprise%202.0" title="Subscribe to MirmarMike's Enterprise 2.0 postings">Enterprise 2.0 New Zealand style</a> since 2001<br />
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html" title="Subscribe to MiramarMike">Subscribe to other parts of MiramarMike</a> (Wellington, New Zealand)<br />
</small></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~4/198348769" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://sportreviewnz.blogspot.com/2007/12/links-on-friday_14.html</url><title>Links on Friday</title><date>2007-12-14 08:09:49.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<hr width="100%" size="1" color="#C0C0C0" /><br />- Fabio Capello will soon be sitting on England's bench. Hope they gave it a good clean after Sven. Still, if he gets them <a href="http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=pTOXrd2rwi8">playing like this</a> everyone'll go home happy. Check out the second goal, it's a thing of true beauty<br />- Liverpool's Jan Molby scored a screamer in the 80s against Man U that no-one ever saw thanks to a TV strike. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_tANyC2tjj8">So some nerd re-created it on their XBox</a>. Bless<br />- The NRL has everything - <a href="http://uk.youtube.com/watch?v=AEZUc__B9kQ&feature=related"> fisticuffs, witty banter and no nonsense refereeing</a>. I may have to watch a game next season<br />- Christmas wish list #1: <a href="http://www.wired.com/gadgets/gadgetreviews/magazine/15-12/wl_legos_imperial_walker">Lego Imperial Walker.</a> Now if you could hook it up to bring beer to the couch...]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.rugbyheaven.co.nz/4324132a22363.html?source=RSSrugbyheaven/headlines_20071214</url><title>Deans named new Wallabies coach</title><date>2007-12-13 17:00:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
LATEST: New Zealand's Robbie Deans has become the first foreigner to be appointed Wallabies coach, with the Australian Rugby Union today confirming a four-year deal for the man the All Blacks didn't want. Bledisloe to sort out who's best Lam asked to assist Robbie How the Aussies got their man View Deans slideshow]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/handofgod/2007/12/14/make-em-sweat-fabio/</url><title>Make ‘em sweat, Fabio</title><date>2007-12-13 20:54:54.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Times could be about to get tougher for England's dismal band of underachieving footballers. If there's one thing <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4323930a18075.html"><strong>Fabio Capello</strong> </a>believes in, it's the value of hard work. Just ask Ronaldo, Alessandro del Piero and Francesco Totti, who have all found themselves dropped by Capello for daring not to work hard enough.</p>
<p>When Capello left Juventus, del Piero is reported to have said: "Now I can return to playing football with the love I have for it. The era of terror in training has now gone." Ruud van Nistelrooy said he has never worked as hard as he did under Capello at Real Madrid.</p>
<p>The good news for England is that the common factor here is not the whining of highly paid prima donnas: it's that Juventus and Madrid - and Totti's Roma - won things during those days of supposedly forced labour. If Peter Crouch ends up even skinnier but with a World Cup winners' medal round his neck, I for one won't be complaining.</p>
<p>His critics - including some on this site - have pointed out that Capello's teams don't always play what Ruud Gullit would call “sheckshy futbol”. But they certainly play winning football, and right now most England fans would find that pretty sexy. His great strength for the England job is not so much his impeccable record as his frequently proven ability to confront players who aren't performing.</p>
<p>Sven-Goran Eriksson and Steve McClaren both seemed to believe that it was enough to pick the best players and let them take it from there. But footballers are simple souls and, just like the rest of us, respond to good management. Of course the players must take their share of the blame for England's poor recent performances, but if they're not playing well it's up to their manager to change things.</p>
<p>Capello himself has said recently: "How can players of the level of Beckham or Owen have performances so different when they play for their national team? It's clear the shirt is very heavy even for those great champions. The manager has a fundamental role to play in this situation. He has to be more of a psychologist than a tactician or a technician.”</p>
<p>And maybe sometimes he needs to be just plain scary. Something has to be done to translate the club form of England's leading players to the international arena, and if that something turns out to be sheer hard work, then make 'em sweat, Fabio.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/hitlist/2007/12/14/time-to-waste-some-time/</url><title>Time to waste some time</title><date>2007-12-13 21:41:20.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/gta1.jpg" title="fsda"></a><img border="3" vspace="6" align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/gta1.jpg" hspace="6" alt="fsda" />A new <strong>Jay-Z</strong> mash-up, brand spanking Portishead songs, a ditzy blonde, new videos from <strong>Radiohead</strong> and <strong>The Killers</strong>, and trailers for <em>Sex and the City</em>, <em>Grand Theft Auto IV</em> and, erm, <em>American Gladiators</em>.</p>
<p>It's all here in the <strong>Best Links of the Week:</strong></p>
<p><strong>1. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rockstargames.com/IV/">GTA IV trailers</a>:</strong> Three trailers have been released for <strong>Grand Theft Auto IV</strong>, which is due for release sometime between February and April next year. That's not very exact, but it looks awesome.</p>
<p><strong>2. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zU-Aa_nXV0U">Slusho commercial</a>:</strong> Who knows what it all means, but <strong>JJ Abrams</strong> is taking this interactive internet promotion thing to new highs. And <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/hitlist/2007/12/12/an-open-letter-to-jj-abrams/">lows</a></strong>. Or he's taken way too much acid. </p>
<p><strong>3.<em> <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TKtaogEfppU">A Great Big Sled</a></em></strong><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TKtaogEfppU"><strong> - The Killers</strong></a><strong>:</strong> <strong>The Killers</strong> have recorded a Christmas song with accompanying festive video. A B-sides album, and now this? The only question is: Why, Brandon, why?</p>
<p><strong>4. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Py-cf0Ktj3k"><em>American Gladiators</em> trailer</a>:</strong> Remember that stupid mid-90s show in which normal people like you and me would try and knock ex-wrestlers off benches with padded sticks? Yeah, it's back.</p>
<p><strong>5. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VwnQO9Du19Q">American Zeppelin mash-up</a>:</strong> <strong>DJ Doc Rok</strong> has done a <em>Grey Album</em>, mixing <strong>Jay-Z's</strong> <em>American Gangster</em> with a smattering of <strong>Led Zeppelin's</strong> biggest and best. Download the full album <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.sendspace.com/pro/dl/jre9v3">here</a></strong>.</p>
<p><strong>6. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kk2-ntNyZaY"><em>Sex and the City: The Movie</em> trailer</a>:</strong> Okay girls, here you go. It's all there: <strong>Carrie</strong> and the girls, New York, a wedding, crazy outfits and <strong>Mr Big</strong>. Save your new shoe-buying expedition though - it's not out till May.</p>
<p><strong>7. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_lmgNqFuXwc">Is Europe a Country</a>:</strong> <strong>Kellie Pickler</strong> gives blondes a bad name when she says 'I thought Europe was a country' then goes on to ask 'Is France a country?' on game show <em>Are You Smarter Than A 10-Year-Old</em>? It turns out she's not.</p>
<p><strong>8. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UKrsBVFsfIQ"><em>Jigsaw Falling Into Place</em> - Radiohead</a>:</strong> A nifty video recorded on helmet cam from <strong>Radiohead's</strong> fantastic album <em>In Rainbows</em>. Get your orders in for the CD release, out December 31.</p>
<p><strong>9. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9oYDBtCN-hk"><em>Crank That</em> - Kosha Boy</a>:</strong> The jury is out on whether this is just another Soulja Boy pisstake or a hilarious Jewish version. You can make your own mind up.</p>
<p><strong>10. <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tVaJErZ2xAE"><em>Machine Gun</em> - Portishead</a>:</strong> The best new track unveiled by much-loved British trip-hop band Portishead during a recent concert. They also played four other newbies: <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ISBUaMymjj0">Mystic</a></strong>, <strong><em><a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CWNslMS3eEI">Hunter</a></em></strong>, <a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MhMVjJyg71M"><strong><em>Wicca</em></strong> </a>and <strong><em><a target="_blank" href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1TIphtLZLw4">Peaches</a></em></strong>. Welcome back, Beth and co.</p>
<p>Got any you'd like to add to the list?</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/checkraise/2007/12/14/ha-ha-nelson-makes-his-move/</url><title>Ha ha! Nelson makes his move</title><date>2007-12-14 01:04:17.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Great to see Lee Nelson advance to day two at the APPT finale in Sydney yesterday.</p>
<p>However, Waikato's James Honeybone went to the rail early on day 1b on a day of some spectacular hands at the PokerStars-sponsored tournament.</p>
<p>Lee ended the day with $93,500 in chips - good enough for 25th spot among the 72 players remaining after two days, with day 1c on the cards today.</p>
<p>Among the chip leaders, baby, was his fellow Team PokerStars member Scotty Nguyen with $250,400.<br />
Lee was all in with the remainder of his chips yesterday with Qd-Qh against Julian Powell, who made the call with As-Qs.</p>
<p>That made the Kiwi a 65% fave and the board of Js-9c-8c 6h 4d meant that held up.</p>
<p>Soon after doubling up, Lee picked up another big pot when he moved with Ad-Qs on a queen-high flop. His opponent tabled Ks-Qc and the 2006 Aussie Millions winner was off and running.<br />
 <br />
James perished when he entered a battle of the blinds with Kenny Ng.</p>
<p>Ng raised from the BB to $1000 and James called to see an intriguing flop of Ad-Kh-Qs.</p>
<p>James checked, Ng fbet $1200 and James made the call. The turn was the 4s and Ng fired again, this time for $5000 and James again flat-called.</p>
<p>The river fell 10s and James pushed all in for his remaining $10,000. Ng made the crying call and when James revealed Kd-8s, Ng's set was good for the big pot.</p>
<p>So for knocking out Waikato's finest, and for committing a monster crime against humanity for being seen at the table with a Manchester United cap on, Ng is in danger of surpassing Shawn Sheikahn at the bottom of the CROPPs.</p>
<p>Both Lee and James were interviewed early in the day - the clips are on the page <a href="http://www.pokernews.com/live-reporting/video-gallery/" title="video">here</a>.</p>
<p>There were a number of exciting hands played out yesterday.</p>
<p>Aussie Billy Sukkar, a cousin of Joe and Tony Hachem who featured at the Aussie Millions won by Nelson, had his aces cracked by 7d-3d and sent to the rail.</p>
<p>After two players limped into the pot, one from the small blind, Sukkar made it $900 to go from the big blind and got two callers.</p>
<p>The flop came Qd-8d-6d and both the small blind and Sukkar checked to the initial limper, who led out with $3000. The small blind got out of the way and Sukkar called.</p>
<p>The turn brought the As, giving Sukkar the top set, and he checked to his opponent who moved all in, having Sukkar covered.</p>
<p>Sukkar called and his opponent revealed his made flush and the 2s on the river didn't help the young Aussie who left the tourney with a set of aces.</p>
<p>The following was a personal highlight that I'm sure all home game players will love - we call it "A Short Smack moment".</p>
<p>In a multi-way raised pot, a short-stack came over the top and pushed the rest of his stack in pre-flop. It was folded around quickly to an unknown internet qualifier who appeared to be giving the decision much deliberation.</p>
<p>The player was not aware that the previous players had already folded and didn't realize the action was on him. After close to five minutes of apparent deep thought, the dealer called a tournament director over and called "time" on the player, giving him 60 seconds to act on his hand. The internet qualifier suddenly realised that "time" was being called on himself and apologetically threw his card into the muck.</p>
<p>That's just too funny... I can just picture the net noob sitting there thinking "Man, no wonder I play on the net, these dudes take yonks!"<br />
 </p>
<p>Van Marcus rode a mid-day rollercoaster when he had pocket Qs cracked by two players who made runner-runner straights.</p>
<p>The very next hand Marcus raised from the small blind and was not surprisingly adjudged by most at the table to be nearing full tilt.</p>
<p>The Aussie fired three barrels on a board of 8s-7s-3d Kh 4s and got action from one other player, who mucked when Marcus flipped over pocket aces.</p>
<p>Later in the day, an uknown player with pocket rockets hit a flop of As-5s-10c when up against the pocket queens of Sol Bergren.</p>
<p>But he became the second "Sukkar" to leave with a set of aces when the turn fell Kh and the river was a Jc.</p>
<p>In another highlighted hand, Francisicus Dekkers was all in pre-flop with 6h6s against AsQc, makig him a slight fave (54% v 45%).</p>
<p>The flop of Jh-8s-10s basically switched those numbers around and when a Js came on the turn, Dekkers' rival had a mahoosive pile of outs.</p>
<p>Aussie pro Mark Vos reckoned Dekkers' opponent had an amazing 25 outs heading into the river but Dekkers escaped a bullet on the river for his sixes to hold.</p>
<p>Last night's home game saw a reduced field as a number of the usual suspects chose other pursuits.</p>
<p>Monty, aka The Big Unit, has a black mark against his name and will never win a major if he doesn't bring his clubs. The Mentor also chose intoxication instead of mixing it with poker like he normally does while Poochie continued his Lord Lucan impersonation and Short Smack was doing his own Gaylord Focker impersonation in a home game of Meet the Parents.</p>
<p>I played like a donk in the first of two four-handed games between me, The Gladiator, Matski and Prem.</p>
<p>Getting way too cute and trying to trap with good hands, I simply gave free cards to my opponents and fell into the hole myself before being first out. Matski eventually took the cash after going heads-up with Glad.</p>
<p>I turned things around in the second game though, playing a game more suited to four-handed poker but did trap nicely when it fit myhand and the board.</p>
<p>After a fun period of all ins and calls with Blind Prem-on, I took a monster pot from Matski with a straight made on the turn and ended heads-up with our host again.</p>
<p>Made an aggressive call to end it all when I held 4d-2d in the big blind and Glad limped in. The flop fell 9d-5c-2s, I bet out with bottom pair about half the pot and got called.</p>
<p>The turn was a Kd and I bet out about two-thirds the pot, only to be re-raised all in. Time to make a read.</p>
<p>I didn't put him on a king and felt his push was designed to move me off as I'd been taking down pots with raises since starting heads-up. I had a 2-1 chip advantage and if I made the call I'd still have enough left behind to play with if beaten.</p>
<p>While I wasn't getting the right pot odds, I did have the nine outs with the flush draw (if he had two diamonds, so be it, I'm not laying down a flush heads-up), another two with the ducks and possibly three more with the fours.</p>
<p>Not only that, but I thought there was probably a 25/30% chance that Glad was making a move with nothing, maybe Q or J high so that had to be factored in with the outs.</p>
<p>I decided to gamble and take a chance to collect the cash there and then - right ....... there. I made the call and the river was a lovely four as Glad revealed 9-7 and I'd finally won one after what seemed like a long barren spell.</p>
<p>Enjoy the weekend<br />
Shuffle up and deal</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.dropkicks.co.nz/robbie_deans/doms_deans_rant</url><title>Dom's Deans Rant</title><date>2007-12-13 00:37:32.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img width="232" height="199" align="left" src="http://www.dropkicks.co.nz/modules/htmlarea/Xinha/plugins/ImageManager/image_uploads/_2007_12/Robbie_Just_Jeans_Deans.JPG" alt="Robbie_Just_Jeans_Deans.JPG" />I had the misfortune to listen to Radio Sport’s Willie Lose yesterday afternoon.</p>
<p>He was ranting and raving about how disappointing the New Zealand rugby season had been. He then began spouting on about how we had been mislead by the rugby union, some conspiracy theory that Henry had been appointed long before the announcement (wooooooooooo). He then went on to continue the media’s appalling deification of Robbie Deans. </p>
<p>Firstly Willie, when you say ‘we’, stop grouping yourself (as a representative for the media) in with the rest of us in the rugby following public. You don’t speak for us, and you might find that your misguided belief that we all share the same sentiments as you is just that. It’s your job to comment fairly. Sure, you’re allowed your opinion, but make sure your listeners get both sides of the story and not the one eyed rantings of a journo clearly upset that Henry &amp; co repeatedly refused to bow to your intrusive and frankly bi-polar questioning over the last four years.</p>
<p>Your puzzling claims of a disastrous year for NZ rugby have never been explained. By my count we lost only the two rugby tests this year. We won the tri-nations (again), defended the bledisloe (again), won the sevens series (again), and the NPC was entertaining, if a little long. You complain about the rotation policy but I believe you would be the first to have a wee cry about how Henry had been ignoring building depth if we had taken an injury and been forced to field a green replacement.</p>
<p>You seem to be applauding those highly un-New Zealand Deans’ zealots who have stated they will be cheering the Aussies (if Deans is appointed) when they take on the All Blacks. Shame on you. Did you call for people to cheer Henry’s Wales when they played John Hart’s All Blacks? I’m embarrassed to hear you support such ideas as a supposed “spokesman” for NZ rugby supporters. </p>
<p>On the subject of your Deans-love and the apparent “snubbing” of NZs “best” coach by the NZRU board, might I remind you that Henry and Deans have already clashed as coaches on the rugby. In 2003, Deans at the head of his “mighty” Crusaders team, was given a lesson in rugby by the tactically astute Henry as technical advisor for the Blues. Had he continued in that role instead of taking on the All Blacks job its questionable whether the Crusaders would have been as successful in intervening years. Also when tested in this year's Super 14, Deans was found wanting as his Crusaders looked rudderless against a pretty poor Brumbies outfit, and were thumped soundly by the Bulls in Pretoria, both games played with his full compliment of All Blacks. &nbsp;</p>
<p>True, Deans, has probably learnt a thing or two since that loss. But with the embarrassment of riches in Canterbury and the appalling manipulation of the transfer market, they have managed to import even better players and managed to stay under Air NZ Cup salary cap, its hard to see anyone butchering another title run with the Crusaders, who is at the helm. But Henry has also learnt a thing or two. Probably much in the same vein as Clive Woodward who led England to a humbling world cup performance in 1999 but returned to thoroughly deserve the title in 2003.</p>
<p>One of the things Henry may have learnt is that Richie McCaw is sadly not up to scratch as an All Black captain. In a move probably forced upon him by a stroppy media contingent determined to have some say in how the national team was being run, he bowed to “public opinion” and installed the Canterbury head honcho as the All Black captain. He probably didn’t think too much of it at the time, as Richie was showing good leadership but I think you must admit that the writing was on the wall for Richie as captain during the tri-nations. </p>
<p>Devoid of ideas, clearly a graduate of the Rueben Thorne School of Indecision, Richie’s All Blacks ran out of ideas against the only team who could have sucked those ideas from them entirely, France. Deans’ poisoned brush has tainted the careers of two All Black captains, both exceptional players, but fumbling, bumbling leaders of men. I think Henry has learnt that lesson. </p>
<p>I say let Deans go. If he’s truly the man for the job, and truly wants it, he’ll be back. He’s young, why the hurry? I’m prepared to eat humble pie, while you dance your little jig, proudly display your “I was right” medal that you made yourself with some snips and the help of a grown up, laugh and point and say I told you so. Bring it on. But some how, I don’t think I will be. 
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/sidelineslogger/2007/12/14/friday-miscellany-sloon-murali-and-hamilton/</url><title>Friday Miscellany: Sloon, Murali and Hamilton</title><date>2007-12-14 01:14:15.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img border="5" vspace="5" align="right" width="257" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/images/689826.jpg?w=300&amp;h=308" hspace="5" height="261" />Right, I am getting off the fence - I was initially wondering what we were playing at firing up the thunderbolt thrower <strong>Shaun "</strong>Sloon"<strong> Tait</strong> but after <a target="_blank" href="http://content-sl.cricinfo.com/slc/content/image/269003.html"><strong>looking here</strong></a> there's no doubt his "bowling" action is questionable.</p>
<p>A wonderful irony with a Sri Lankan, <strong>Roshan Mahanama </strong>at the top table as match referee in Adelaide for tonight's clash. Mahanama is no fan of Australian pace bowling, and one person not on his Christmas card list is caravan-lover Glenn McGrath. In his autobiography, the Sri Lankan <a target="_blank" href="http://www.rediff.com/cricket/2001/jul/31maha.htm"><strong>accused</strong></a> the Australian paceman of calling Sanath Jayasuriya a "black monkey" in the 1995/96 World Series. McGrath, predictably, denied the accusation.</p>
<p>Speaking of alleged chuckers and Sri Lankans, <strong>Muttiah Muralitharan </strong>has been honoured with a (dreadful) song by Aussie-based Lankan Alston Koch. Brace yourself when you download <em>Murali</em> from <a target="_blank" href="http://mcricket.mobi/download_song.jsp?id=18D8136CAAB5E00A455AAE2042086666"><strong>here</strong></a>. We will also be reviewing it on The BYC <a target="_blank" href="http://beigebrigade.co.nz/loop/byc/"><strong>podcast</strong></a> this week. According to World Music Central, Alston has been "a leading Sri Lankan musician since the 1960s...Koch performed at all the well-known night clubs in Ceylon including the Coconut Grove in Colombo". Sounds a bit like <strong>John Rowles</strong>.</p>
<p>A <em>Sideline Slogger </em>reader with impeccable credentials has done the economic analysis and reckons <strong>Dan Vettori</strong>, <strong>Jacob Oram </strong>and <strong>Jeetan Patel </strong>are our best bets for bowling at the death after running the numbers over recent efforts in the last 10 overs. According to <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/sidelineslogger/2007/12/06/the-underarm-wker-series/"><strong>The Economist</strong></a>, X-Box fan Mark Gillespie's record is not as good as any of these three and he's more expensive than other contenders, Scotty Styris and Kyle Mills.</p>
<p><img border="5" vspace="5" align="right" width="351" src="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a9/Fonterra_Facility_Near_Hamilton.jpg/800px-Fonterra_Facility_Near_Hamilton.jpg" hspace="5" height="253" />Quote of the week is from <em>The Daily Star </em>in Bangladesh: "The team bus took the Tigers to <strong>Hamilton</strong> to their Novotel Tainui Hotel...past breathtaking greenery, lovely single storey houses and livestock grazing the valleys on both sides of the road like you find in picture books. Adding to the atmosphere was the absence of a siren blowing police or security escort which just would not have fitted with the level of tranquility around."</p>
<p>Finally, here is an <strong>In-form New Zealand XI</strong>, selected solely from those playing in the State Championship domestic competition. The <em>Sideline Slogger </em>joins them in banging on the selectors' doors and yelling: "Come on!" The XI is: Matthew Bell, Aaron Redmond, Peter Fulton, Greg Hay, Greg Todd, Neal Parlane, Reece Young, Andre Adams, Brandon Hiini, Bradley Scott, Andy McKay. Honourable mention: Charlie Shreck (England). Bell and Adams are stitching together increasingly compelling cases to be selected ahead of incumbents Michael Papps and Iain O'Brien.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/sidelineslogger/2007/12/13/begone-technophobes/</url><title>Begone, technophobes…</title><date>2007-12-13 01:17:28.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img border="5" vspace="5" align="right" width="369" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/689737.jpg" hspace="5" height="249" />Anyone who watched that WACA Twenty20 match on Tuesday night would need to have their funny bone removed to not enjoy the banter provided by the on-field microphones taped to the ears of <strong>Andrew Symonds</strong>, <strong>Adam Gilchrist </strong>and <strong>Dan Vettori</strong>. The trio could all hear each other and chat with the Channel 9 boys in the box.</p>
<p>An initial exchange had Gilchrist exposing his team's plan to take more quick singles and "Dan can believe as much of that as he likes". Vettori was later addressed by the Channel 9 team in the aftermath of his spin twin Jeetan Patel's left-handed screamer snare from a fierce cut shot from Gilchrist's bat. With a wry smile, Vettori confirmed that he never thought Patel was going to miss it and that it was all part of the Kiwi plan.</p>
<p>Other classic player commentary moments included:<br />
- <strong>Michael Clarke</strong> (he of the shaved arms - check them out, quite a strange metrosexual option) asking Symonds to just "pull his head in" for a few overs while the two went about steadying the Australian innings. Symonds said he had agreed to but only for "an over or two".<br />
- <strong>Ian Smith </strong>striving unsuccessfully to have a serious discussion with Vettori about the importance of the match. Vettori, who was setting the field, said he would listen out to hear when he was "getting slagged off". Note to Stockley - it's T20 and the players are still struggling to take it seriously.<br />
- <strong>Symonds </strong>asking for some peace and quiet while he bowled to "this bastard", meaning the facing New Zealand batsman. He followed that up with a question to Gilchrist: "What time do you reckon James Sutherland [CEO of Cricket Australia]  will ring me tomorrow morning, Gilly? It could be my wake-up call, I reckon."</p>
<p>Gilchrist is a veteran of having the microphone taped to his lid, having provided a wonderful stream of comments when playing in the Ashes Twenty20 at Sydney, along with the captains that evening. In that match he was facing <strong>Andrew Flintoff </strong>and said: "How about that? The bloke who's terrorised me in my sleep for 12 months and I get to face him in Twenty20."</p>
<p>That murderous night he also revealed the origins of his nickname, Church, earned on the 1997 Ashes tour. He was standing with Steve Waugh and Glenn McGrath when they were approached by a young boy, who said: "You're Steve Waugh aren't you? And you're Glenn McGrath? And are you <strong>Eric Gilchurch</strong>?" Even <strong>Michael Vaughan </strong>came up with a ripper as the Australians slaughtered the English attack mercilessly with a sequence of towering sixes. When asked how his knee was, he replied: "The knee's OK, but I've got a sore neck."</p>
<p><img border="5" vspace="5" align="right" width="300" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/images/689736.jpg" hspace="5" height="360" />Elsewhere on Tuesday, <strong>Ian Healy</strong> was interviewing players waiting to bat in their sideline hutch at the edge of the WACA oval, including words with <a target="_blank" href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4321250a10133.html"><strong>carpark recruit</strong></a> Luke Pomersbach and a ridiculously zinc-lipped Andrew Symonds. A comment was made that this was normally not possible in any other form of international cricket. So good on the players and the administrators for agreeing to this sort of guerilla coverage but it also begs the question: Why the hell can't this sort of thing be done in one-day and Test cricket?</p>
<p>The answer, of course, is no reason at all. Sport needs to move with the times and hearing directly from the players out representing their country in the heat of the battle provides a terrific insight into mindsets, tactics, and personalities. It is about engagement - coverage that puts the viewer inside the player's spiky boots.</p>
<p>Aside from the so-called gimmicks that are only rolled out for Twenty20, cricket's longer forms of the game are missing the boat here: rugby league has the dressing room camera, NFL has in-game interviews, basketball coaches' expletive-laden team talks are in our lounges, the A-League football has a coach interview at half-time, the V8 coverage is down and dirty in the pits... The upshot of this fly-on-the-wall coverage is an affinity with the combatants as it portrays what they are really like without that veil of spin and media interpretation.</p>
<p>As Channel 9's man in charge of sport (and ao-author of grim rugby league coach Wayne Bennett's biography) Steve Crawley said: "Reality TV is a big part of the world now, and that's what we're doing with cricket. We don't tell those blokes what to say, it's off the cuff, and that's why it works." It also plays a hand in terms of eyes on screens - the Perth match's Aussie TV audience was <a target="_blank" href="http://www.news.com.au/dailytelegraph/story/0,22049,22915661-5006069,00.html"><strong>more than triple</strong></a> that of the recent Australia v Sri Lanka Test match.</p>
<p>The technology and the talent is available - unleash it! </p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
