<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Tech</title>
<item>
<url>http://oswaldbastable.blogspot.com/2007/12/make-punishment-fit-crime.html</url><title>Make the punishment fit the crime</title><date>2007-12-13 20:09:57.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322768a28.html">This</a><br /><br />Is not trivial- the cost of spam is enormous<br /><br /><p>"...About 95 per cent of emails this year - up from 70 per cent in 2006 - were classified as junk messages, according to a report from US security firm Barracuda, Agence France Presse reported.</p> <p>Most of this is deleted by email filters run by Internet providers before it hits inboxes..."</p><br />I believe the punishment should fit the crime- thus all spammers are to be reduced to- Spam!<br /><br />Put through an industrial-grade mincer, rendered down, seasoned and sold for dog tucker. (which is all Spam is fit for!)<br /><br />If it won't sell as dog tucker, at least they won't take up much cell space!<br /><p><br /></p><p><br /></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.geekzone.co.nz/freitasm/4246</url><title>Telecom New Zealand: BlackBerry and more Windows Mobile to come in 2008</title><date>2007-12-13 03:59:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
I am just now back from a media lunch with Telecom New Zealand's Greg McAlister (GM Business Solutions), David Craig (GM Consumer Marketing), Rebecca Earl and Katherine Murphy (both from their PR team).<br /><br />Before lunch (at the Wellington's famous <a href="http://www.loganbrown.co.nz/" target="_blank">Logan Brown</a>) we had a brief review of Telecom's performance during 2007. Then we had a few bits of news (and I will quote from my notes):<br /><br />- The Okta Touch is the fastest selling Windows Mobile device on Telecom ever - with about three times more sales than originally expected.<br /><br />- The voicemail migration should be completed by January 2008 - a long project, which I remember being involved during early planning stages while working for Unisys New Zealand, until now provider of the Telecom VSP (voice platform).<br /><br />- The Worldmode service will have some new handsets. If you don't know, &quot;worldmode&quot; are those handsets that can be used on the existing CDMA network and on overseas GSM/3G networks (and by the end of 2008 on the new Telecom network replacing the CDMA EVDO technology).<br /><br />- Data roaming is coming for Worldmode so that you don't have to use CDMA only - and stuck in countries where there's no CDMA providers.<br /><br />- The Okta Mondo should be announced next week, the second Worldmode handset from Telecom New Zealand.<br /><br />- The LG Groove is coming next month - a media-oriented handset with special media keys (it reminds me of those MP3 players) and built-in FM transmitter.<br /><br />- Telecom New Zealand is working on launching a Worldmode BlackBerry handset. Initially they are working on testing internally at Gen-i, but soon with external clients.<br /><br />- They are working on a Samsung Blackjack Windows Mobile device codenamed Albero, also to be a Worldmode handset, due to release sometime near the end of Q1 2008.<br /><br />- A free security software is coming for Yahoo!Xtra (Bubble) users.<br /><br />- More broadband business plans are coming in addition to currently existing residential plans.<br /><br />- Telecom New Zealand will move into the business services during 2008 including hosted applications.<br /><br />In summary, as Greg McAlister said:<br /><br /><blockquote><br />Embracing the new opportunities and looking forward to operating as a service provider in the new environment<br /></blockquote><br /><br />It seems everyone there is quite happy with Telecom's new CEO, Paul Reynolds. Good luck in 2008...
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/gzfreitasm?a=9lTXDU"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/gzfreitasm?i=9lTXDU" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=vBsY93C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=vBsY93C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=SyHpoyC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=SyHpoyC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=7CRLHoc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=7CRLHoc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=W4OZzkc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=W4OZzkc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/gzfreitasm/~4/199551446" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/200020894/omnidrive_heading_for_deadpool.php</url><title>Omnidrive Heading for Deadpool?</title><date>2007-12-14 00:42:57.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/omnidrive_logo.gif" vspace="5" hspace="5" align="left" />A tipster informed us today that online storage solution <a href="http://www.omnidrive.com/">Omnidrive</a> has been having technical difficulties; and that the CTO has just left the company. Omnidrive's forums, both <a href="http://forum.omnidrive.com/topic/370#post-1740">the official one</a> and <a href="http://www.tangler.com/group/omnidrive-talk">the Tangler one</a>, are filled with messages complaining that the service is up and down - messages which the company doesn't appear to be responding to. The <a href="http://www.omnidrive.com/blog/2007/08/31/all-technical-difficulties-have-been-resolved/">last post</a> on the company's blog is dated August 31st and is entitled 'All technical difficulties have been resolved!'. There's also no recent postings on CEO <a href="http://www.nik.com.au/">Nik Cubrilovic's blog</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/windows_live_skydrive_launched_online_storage.php">As we wrote in August</a>, the online storage space is very crowded - and there are a few monster players in the form of Microsoft, Google and Amazon. But Omnidrive was doing some great work in the space, <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/zoho_omnidrive_data_standards.php">driving for open standards</a> and partnering with other Web Office companies like Zoho.</p>
<p>We've put in an email to Nik to clarify. I know him personally and it would be very sad if Omnidrive fell into the deadpool, particularly given the recent 'deaths' of Blognation and edgeio - two other web 2.0 startup collapses. As of now we're not ready to call Omnidrive as in the deadpool, but there seem to be major issues with the site judging by the forums.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/omnidrive_forum.jpg" /></p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=Ahb9FD"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=Ahb9FD" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=DJXsEfC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=DJXsEfC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=TCUpZ0C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=TCUpZ0C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=kQrph6c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=kQrph6c" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=1FXOpac"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=1FXOpac" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=TT2yZgc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=TT2yZgc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=wOY2oWC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=wOY2oWC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/200020894" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199946129/best_web_littleco_of_2007_twitter.php</url><title>Best Web LittleCo of 2007: Twitter</title><date>2007-12-13 21:29:59.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Earlier this week we announced our <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/best_web_bigco_of_2007.php">Best BigCo of 2007</a>, Facebook. In this post we're announcing our pick for Best LittleCo. We're also asking for your nominations for Most Promising Web Company for 2008. These picks are something we do every year, this being the 4th year. <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/best_web_littleco_2006.php">Last year's Best LittleCo</a> was <strong>YouTube</strong>, with <strong>Sharpcast</strong> selected as Most Promising. <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/best_web_compan.php">In 2005</a><strong> 37Signals</strong> was Best LittleCo and <strong>Memeorandum</strong> (now Techmeme) and <strong>Digg</strong> were joint Most Promising. <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/best_web_20_com.php">In 2004</a> <strong>Ludicorp</strong>, creators of Flickr, was Best LittleCo and <strong>Feedburner</strong> was named Most Promising. </p>
<p>As you can see, most of our picks have gone on to enjoy more widespread success - YouTube, Ludicorp, Feedburner have all been acquired; while 37Signals, Techmeme, Digg and Sharpcast have all ramped up and enjoyed success. So to 2007, a year in which trends such as Mobile Web, social networking and micro-blogging have increased in popularity. It's been another bumper year of startup activity, so which among the hundreds of startups has impressed the most in 2007?</p>
<h2>And the Winner is...</h2>
<p><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/twitter_logo.png" vspace="5" hspace="5" align="right" />As with the BigCo selection, the Read/WriteWeb authors were unanimous in our decision. <strong>The Best LittleCo of 2007 is <a href="http://twitter.com/help/aboutus">Twitter, Inc</a>.</strong> Already this week there has been a lot of analysis about <a href="http://www.twitter.com">Twitter</a>, with some people <a href="http://www.bubblegeneration.com/2007/12/whats-interesting-about-twitter-isnt.cfm">embracing</a> it and others <a href="http://publishing2.com/2007/12/11/why-i-stopped-using-twitter/">critical</a>. Our own Alex Iskold summed it up well in his post entitled <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/the_evolution_of_personal_publ.php">The Evolution of Personal Publishing</a>, when he described Twitter as a kind of mix between social networks and chat. The term for this has come to be know as <em>microblogging</em>. Here is how Alex described it:</p>
<blockquote>
  <p>&quot;Social network publishing is very terse, blog publishing is verbose. Is there a form of publishing which is on one hand as easy as social networking, but as sequential as regular blogs? Twitter and Tumblr have recently emerged to define this new category of microblogging.&quot;</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/twitterlogo2.jpg" align="left" hspace="5px" vspace="5px" />The simple idea of Twitter is to express what you are doing right now, in 140 characters or less. Admittedly Twitter is still very much a niche, geek activity. Earlier this year I witnessed a fellow Web 2.0 Expo attendee twittering on a mobile phone while walking down a busy San Francisco road with a group of us - and she tripped up and fell. Which kind of sums up Twitter for the early adopter, geek crowd: it is addictive, distracting, and not really necessary. </p>
<p>However RWW did highlight some real-world uses this year - e.g. <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/amazon_comes_to_twitter.php">Amazon uses it</a> to promote its products; and <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/lone_remaining_burmese_blogger.php">Burmese bloggers used a similar product</a> to Twitter, a lightweight messaging service called CBox, to post very short updates from inside the country. </p>
<p>Twitter is undoubtedly <strong>new and disruptive</strong>. In a year in which you can count on one hand the number of disruptive Web products (iPhone would be another), Twitter stands out as being something that has captured the imagination and become a new hybrid of chat, social networking and blogging. </p>

<p>One of the most important things Twitter has done is open up an API to outside developers (this is an argument that co-founder Biz Stone <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/twitter_open_platform_advantage.php">made to us</a> in September).  According to Twitter, the API has seen such incredible growth, that just months after it was released it is already getting 10 times the traffic of the Twitter web site. For examples, check out our <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/top_10_twitter_apps.php">Top 10 Twitter Apps</a> from July; and Marshall Kirkpatrick's comprehensive <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/the_rww_guide_to_the_worlds_mo.php">RWW Guide to the World's Most Popular Twitter Clients</a>.</p>
<p>One of Twitter's cheif rivals, <a href="http://www.jaiku.com/">Jaiku</a>, was <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/google_acquires_jaiku.php">acquired by Google</a> in October. Other similar products that impressed us this year included (but not limited to): Tumblr, <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/kyte_its_like_t_1.php">Kyte</a> (a video twitter), <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/soup_tumble_blogging_with_friends.php">Soup</a>, <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/pownce_send_stuff_to_friends.php">Pownce</a>, and the <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/10_micro-blogging_tools_compared.php">10 microblogging tools</a> we reviewed in September.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/content-pipe.jpg" /></p>
<p>See Also: <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/evolution_of_communication.php">Evolution of Communication: From Email to Twitter and Beyond</a></p>
<h2>Nominations? Most Promising Web Company for 2008</h2>
<p>So there you have it, Twitter is our Best LittleCo this year. Now we turn our attention to what is the most promising Web product or company for 2008 - and we need your help! Let us know in the comments what is most promising for you, and why. We'll announce this very soon!</p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=qvZMI6"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=qvZMI6" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=uVv0ZeC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=uVv0ZeC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=CX5x9eC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=CX5x9eC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=fX27ifc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=fX27ifc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=7D8Swnc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=7D8Swnc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=RJEIHoc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=RJEIHoc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=pzdNd5C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=pzdNd5C" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199946129" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199878931/flickr_introduces_traffic_stats.php</url><title>Flickr Introduces Traffic Stats for Pro Users</title><date>2007-12-13 18:55:23.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><font>
</font><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/flickr_jan07.jpg" align="left" hspace="5px" vspace="5px" />Users with a pro account at <a href="http://flickr.com">Flickr</a> are now able to view a variety of interesting statistics about the viewers of their photos.  Heather Champ said in a post on the <a href="http://blog.flickr.com/en/2007/12/13/stats-stats-baby/">Flickr blog</a> this morning that the stats are intended to "give you all sorts of insight into how people arrive at your photos."
</p><p>
Viewer numbers are a big deal for many Flickr users and Champ says this is one of their most requested features.  <strong>In a world increasingly full of user generated content platforms, offering users basic traffic stats like referring URLs ought to be standard practice.</strong> Offering these numbers to premium subscribers makes a lot of sense.  I expect this will be one more practice that Flickr blazes the trail on, only to be followed by others in a wide variety of markets.</p>
<p>The stats feature needs to be activated by the user.  Large screenshots of the process can be found on <a href="http://blog.extraface.com/2007/12/13/flickr-stats-new-flickr-feature-on-the-way/">the blog of consultant Dave Coustan</a>, where I learned about the news myself.</p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=B2By1Z"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=B2By1Z" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=T90GeAC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=T90GeAC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=ob6mPhC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=ob6mPhC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=xyEDJ9c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=xyEDJ9c" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=7ee0yQc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=7ee0yQc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=u80uXCc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=u80uXCc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=D5PLoZC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=D5PLoZC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199878931" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199862810/mobile_myspace_on_sprint_do_ca.php</url><title>Mobile MySpace On Sprint: Do Carrier Deals Make Sense?</title><date>2007-12-13 17:25:32.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/myspace-logo.jpg" align="right" hspace="5px" vspace="5px" />Fox Interactive announced today that it has a deal with Sprint to offer one-click access to the new MySpace Mobile portal when it launches early next year.  Sprint and Fox have had a mobile relationship since before mobile meant much, in fact.  This could be a sneeze turned into a press release, but it's also a good opportunity to examine carrier-based mobile content deals vs. open social networking on mobile.</p>

<p> <a href="http://money.cnn.com/news/newsfeeds/articles/djf500/200712130938DOWJONESDJONLINE000793_FORTUNE5.htm">Early press on the deal</a> says Sprint will be first but it does not say that it will be an exclusive deal.    It was around this same time last year that MySpace announced a deal with Cingular that would let that carrier's customers use a Java app for MySpace for $3 per month.  Helio, a high-profile handset that operates on the Sprint network, has allowed access to MySpace since last year as well.  This week Helio launched a mobile YouTube interface that <a href="http://www.hollywoodreporter.com/hr/content_display/business/news/e3icf7a9c3d15e7be1ce9172be6b3938e16">the company says</a> is the first to allow YouTube users access to their accounts and social features.
</p><p>
<strong>The primary question this raises, though, is this:</strong>  why not just open a free, universally accessible mobile MySpace like Facebook offers?  Facebook Mobile is excellent and would provide as good a model for MySpace as the Facebook Newsfeed did for the new MySpace friend feed.  (See our coverage of <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/social_networks_study_fabernovel.php">MySpace vs. Facebook in general</a>.) Just add some adds and superfluous pageviews and you've got MySpace Mobile. Perhaps MySpace felt it was not capable of monetizing mobile access except through carrier deals.  That would be interesting news for the rest of the industry.
</p><p>
Mobile access could be a key step in MySpace regaining growth momentum, but that seems more likely if the company were to open mobile access to all.  It's an interesting trade-off and I wish I was a fly on the wall at the meetings where these decisions were being made.
</p><h2>Tracking the Mobile Content World</h2><p>
Thanks to Forrester's <a href="http://web-stragist.com">Jeremiah Owyang</a>, who called attention to the news first in my world, on <a href="http://twitter.com/jowyang">Twitter</a>.  We're looking to increase our coverage of mobile news and issues here at ReadWriteWeb.  If you're interested in this space as well, you can download an OPML file (a bundle of RSS feeds for importing into your feed reader) that contains some of my favorite mobile content sources and mobile news from our blogs ReadWriteWeb and <a href="http://last100.com">Last100</a>, filtered via <a href="http://feedrinse.com">FeedRinse</a>: <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/files/rwwmobilefeeds.opml">RWWMobileFeeds.opml</a>.  Save the file behind that link, import it into your feed reader and you'll be up to date on the fast emerging world of mobile content.  You can preview the live contents of this collection below, using <a href="http://grazr.com">Grazr</a>.</p><p><center><div><a href="http://grazr.com/gzpanel.html?file=http://grazr.com/opml/marshallrww" target="gz"><img src="http://grazr.com/images/grazrbadge.png" border="0" /></a></div></center></p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=I2SKhw"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=I2SKhw" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=9h29B1C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=9h29B1C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=QGrkrnC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=QGrkrnC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=vW7mrnc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=vW7mrnc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=Y1DKxAc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=Y1DKxAc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=cnwqpEc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=cnwqpEc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=69V1XPC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=69V1XPC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199862810" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199779377/yahoo_releases_shortcuts_wordpress_plugin.php</url><title>Yahoo! Releases Shortcuts Wordpress Plugin</title><date>2007-12-13 15:25:37.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img border="0" src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/yahooshortcuts-logo.jpg" align="left" hspace="5" vspace="5" width="140" height="53" />Yahoo! has released a <a href="http://shortcuts.yahoo.com/">new plugin</a> for Wordpress that adds its "Shortcuts" search popups to blog content.  Shortcuts are informational popups that operate similarly to Snap's <a href="http://www.snap.com/">SnapShots</a> and AdaptiveBlue's <a href="http://www.adaptiveblue.com/">SmartLinks</a>.  The key difference is that Yahoo!'s implementation is seeded with Yahoo! content.</p>

<p>The Wordpress plugin route may limit the potential user base of Yahoo! Shortcuts, but it provides bloggers with more control over how the popups are implemented in each post.  Rather than Shortcuts being added to every post, bloggers using the plugin are given the opportunity to decide which popups, if any, are added on a post by post basis.</p>

<p><img border="0" src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/shortcuts-control.jpg" align="right" hspace="5" vspace="5" width="194" height="125" />The plugin automatically scans the text of a post before publishing and alerts the blogger to how many Shortcuts have been located.  Users can then decide which Shortcuts are used before pushing the post live.  Shortcuts can also be made into "badges," which place the content of the Shortcut directly into the post (i.e., if you're posting about Google, you can put a stock quote badge directly into the content).</p>

<p>The Shortcuts plugin currently supports maps, financial info, products, autos, news, and web search.  Yahoo! has a whole mess of other Shortcuts, such as sports, gas prices, movies, and music, that it can add to the plugin in the future.</p>

<p>The plugin also ties in another Yahoo! service, Flickr, by searching the photo sharing site for Creative Commons-licensed photos relevant to the content of each post and suggesting images that can be included in the post.  That's a convenient way for bloggers to easily dress up posts, and for that feature alone the plugin might be worth it, even if you never actually publish a Shortcut.</p>

<p><img border="0" src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/shortcuts-screen.jpg" width="517" height="324" /></p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=1pfTlb"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=1pfTlb" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=CdkJUqC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=CdkJUqC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=1iPNvCC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=1iPNvCC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=Megxodc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=Megxodc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=dtGbwJc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=dtGbwJc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=BNZsyvc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=BNZsyvc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=XOQGqKC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=XOQGqKC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199779377" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199746907/opera_vs_ie_round_one_fight.php</url><title>Opera vs. IE: Round One, Fight!</title><date>2007-12-13 14:15:44.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><font>
</font><img border="0" src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/tyson-opera-ie.jpg" align="left" hspace="5" vspace="5" width="200" height="158" />I'm getting this feeling of deja vu... haven't we been through all this before?  Today <a href="http://www.opera.com/">Opera</a> filed an <a href="http://www.opera.com/pressreleases/en/2007/12/13/">antitrust complaint</a> with the European Union against Microsoft.  According to Opera, the makers of an alternative web browser, Microsoft is using its dominant position to unfairly influence the web browser market by bundling Internet Explorer with Windows and by "not following accepted Web standards," which Opera says causes developers to create web pages specifically for IE that break in other browsers -- and thus lowers the incentive for users to switch.</p>

<p>The solution?  Opera wants the EU to force Microsoft to stop bundling IE, or to bundle other browsers with the OS (i.e., Opera).  They also request that the EU make Microsoft follow "fundamental and open Web standards accepted by the Web-authoring communities."</p>

<p>This is not an unfamiliar argument to Microsoft -- that tiff with the Justice Department was about much the same thing.  But, as Larry Dignan <a href="http://blogs.zdnet.com/BTL/?p=7332">points out</a>, Opera might find a more receptive audience in the European Union than Netscape found in the US DoJ.  The European Union has already ruled that bundling Windows Media Player with Windows was illegal, so a precedent in Opera's favor appears to exist (note: I am not a lawyer).</p>

<p>"Our complaint is necessary to get Microsoft to amend its practices," said Jason Hoida, Deputy General Counsel for Opera, in a press release."The European Court of First Instance confirmed in September that Microsoft has illegally tied Windows Media Player to Windows. We are simply asking the Commission to apply these same, clear principles to the Internet Explorer tie, a tie that has even more profound effects on consumers and innovation."</p>

<p>Hold on to your hats.  This one is just getting started...</p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=k1XV3b"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=k1XV3b" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=w8bpSWC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=w8bpSWC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=G61YaLC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=G61YaLC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=Ah8OsXc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=Ah8OsXc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=Ua14klc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=Ua14klc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=JStmjCc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=JStmjCc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=3ABb0TC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=3ABb0TC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199746907" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199587813/adobe_blazeds.php</url><title>Adobe to Open Source LiveCycle Data Services as BlazeDS</title><date>2007-12-13 05:00:01.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img border="0" src="http://www.readwriteweb.com/images/adobe-logo.jpg" align="left" hspace="5" vspace="5" width="60" height="83" /><a href="http://www.adobe.com/">Adobe</a> is announcing today the release of <a href="http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/blazeds/">BlazeDS</a>, an open source version of their server side remoting and messaging
technologies that were previously only available in the LifeCycle Data Services ES package.  Adobe is also publishing the Action Message Format (AMF) protocol specification.</p>

<p>Right now, the technologies included in BlazeDS are targeted at enterprises using Java via the LifeCycle product family.  Adobe hopes that by opening the source code with BlazeDS and by publishing the AMF spec, developers will be able to use Adobe's remoting and messaging technologies with non-Java backends, such as PHP and Ruby.</p>

<p>"The combination of BlazeDS with Flex and AIR helps reduce the time it takes for developers to build
responsive and highly innovative RIAs that deliver rich, dynamic, branded content and applications across
all major browsers and operating systems," said David Mendels, senior vice president, Business
Productivity Business Unit at Adobe in a press release. "Contributing these technologies, including the AMF specification, to
the open source community opens them up for other non-Java backends, helping to rapidly advance this
important RIA feature set."</p>

<p>I spoke with Christophe Coenraets, who is the product evangelist for Adobeâ€™s Business Productivity Business Unit, who told me that one of the main reasons to use Adobe's remoting and messaging technology is that it is much faster than traditional XML over HTTP or web services.  According to internal Adobe benchmarks, data delivery using AMF is up to 10 times faster than traditional methods.  Because XML is written so that it can be understood by humans, translating it back to machine code on the other end slows it down.  AMF, on the other hand, uses a binary format, which makes it much faster.</p>

<p>Coenraets said that by open sourcing the BlazeDS technologies, not only will they be available to more Java developers, but also, Adobe hopes, they will be able to be used by developers working with other back end technologies.  That, said Coenraets, is something that many of Adobe's enterprise customers have wanted: a larger pool of developers working with these technologies.</p>

<p>In fact, Adobe is already working with leaders in the open source community who have been attempting to bring Flash remoting to other programming languages, such as <a href="http://amfphp.org/">AMFPHP</a>.  "Working with Adobe, we can create a common programming model that enables RIA developers to extend the reach of their applications across different server technologies in a compatible and consistent approach," said Wade Arnold, from AMFPHP, expressing excitement at the opportunity to work directly with Adobe to bring AMF to PHP developers.</p>

<p>For businesses interested in BlazeDS but hesitant to adopt an unsupported technology, Adobe will offer the "Live Cycle Data Services Community Edition" which will package Adobe certified versions of BlazeDS with support from the company.  No word yet on pricing.</p>

<p>Adobe is also releasing beta 3 versions of both Flex and AIR today -- two technologies that are designed to play nice with BlazeDS.  A public beta of BlazeDS is available now on the <a href="http://labs.adobe.com/technologies/blazeds/">Adobe Labs</a> site, and a full release under the LGPL is expected in 2008.</p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=5qb7dD"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=5qb7dD" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=1injY5C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=1injY5C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=42XM8ZC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=42XM8ZC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=Fp36DQc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=Fp36DQc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=unoGvdc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=unoGvdc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=a9C3Uwc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=a9C3Uwc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=WUUyxwC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=WUUyxwC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199587813" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~3/199466976/leweb3_conference_2007.php</url><title>LeWeb3 Conference Report</title><date>2007-12-13 00:18:24.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><i>David Lenehan was at LeWeb3 in Paris, on behalf of Read/WriteWeb. Here is his overview.</i></p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.leweb3.com/">LeWeb3
Conference</a> kicked off yesterday morning in Paris and has just finished up
this evening. Our host Loic Le Meur of
<a href="http://www.seesmic.com/">Seesmic</a> opened the
event with much fanfare, flashing lights and European techno music. He
acknowledged the criticisms of last years event, and promised that they 
learned from the feedback they received. The conference was split between 3
large buildings covering the keynotes and panels in one, a startup stage in
another one, and a large comfortable networking space in another. This is one of
the better conferences I have been to in recent years. Wifi worked for the most
part, there was very healthy amount of new startups demoing, the VCs and angels
were out in force, and the keynotes - although too relaxed and light at times -
were mostly interesting and engaging. Pretty much 100% of the conference is
going to be available for free to watch online soon
<a href="http://leweb3.vpod.tv/">here</a>, so check out the
videos if there is anything you would like to have seen. Here are a few of the
highlights...</p>
<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2222/2105447019_a1c9fda7c4.jpg?v=0" /><br />
  <em>Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cwmac/">cwmac</a></em></p>

<h2>Janus Friis - Joost</h2>
<p>Janus Friis is a founder of Kazaa, Skype, Joost and Atomico Investments.
He is not someone who regularly talks at these events so it was a rare treat to
listen to someone of his caliber and experience. He talked about Kazaa's quick
rise to fame and the years of litigation that followed. From there they went on
to build Skype, an organization that quickly had hundreds of employees and
eventually sold to ebay for $2.6b. With his new venture Joost just passing the 4
million user mark, he recalled a time when he was going to talk to TV stations
about distributing their content and being told "Are you the guy from Kazaa? we
have some people in our legal team that would like to talk to you first!" He is
also now involved with a new investment firm called
<a href="http://atomicoinvestments.com/">Atomico</a>
ventures. He is a master at building disruptive technologies and a very
interesting person to listen to.</p>

<h2>Evan Williams - Twitter</h2>
<p>Evan's talk was one that I found to be particularly interesting. He asked
the crowd to think about what new things could be created by stripping down and
simplifying existing products, as opposed to building more feature rich ones.
<a href="http://twitter.com/">Twitter</a> being the perfect
example of this idea. A blogging platform with pretty much every useful feature
removed! It is an interesting alternative approach for product development and
one that I think is worth exploring for anyone building web apps today.</p>
<h2>Marc Canter bringing social to software</h2>
<p>Unfortunatly I missed this panel with Patrick Chanezon (Google), Tariq
Krim (Netvibes), Hans Peter Brondmo (Plum), Susan Kish (European Energy Forum)
and Marc Canter (Broadband Mechanics). But most people I talked to today said
that it was one of the best discussions that happened. You can see a video of it
<a href="http://leweb3.vpod.tv/">here</a> when they have it
uploaded.</p>
<h2>Interface design and user experience</h2>
<p>I found Shadram Izadi's (from Microsoft) talk on interface design fascinating.
He showed some videos of
<a href="http://www.microsoft.com/surface/">Microsoft
Surface</a> and a new product called
<a href="http://research.microsoft.com/%7Eshahrami/">Thinsight</a>
in action. These computers are focused on having more than one person using them
at a time, and using your fingers and hands to interact with them. The Thinsight
screen is so sensitive that you can use a fine paint brush to draw on it and it
will pick up every stroke. You can see some videos of them in action
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rP5y7yp06n0">here</a>.</p>
<h2>Startup Competition</h2>
<p>This year at LeWeb3 there was a separate building dedicated to startup pitches.
Over 30 startups went head to head in 7 minute presentations in front of a panel
of judges. The winners were:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://goojet.com/">Goojet</a> - A mobile app that allows you to organize
your phones pictures, RSS feeds, notes etc. through their website.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.plymedia.com/">PlyMedia</a> - A cool
widget for adding media layers on top of web video.</li>
<li><a href="http://g.ho.st">g.ho.st</a> - A web OS app.</li>
</ul>
<p>Other startups of note that demoed their wares were: <a href="http://erepublik.com/">Erepublik</a>,
<a href="http://www.splitgames.fr/">Split Games</a>
and <a href="http://www.holistis.com/">Holistis</a>. Saul
Klein also brought along some of the
<a href="http://www.seedcamp.com/">seedcamp</a> winners to
demo (<a href="http://www.kublax.com/">Kublax</a>,
<a href="http://www.buildersite.co.uk/">BuilderSite</a>).</p>
<p><img src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2352/2106153290_e2a315f5f8.jpg?v=0" /><br />
  <em>Image: <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/cwmac/2106153290/">cwmac</a></em></p>
<h2>NineMillion.org</h2>
<p>Towards the end of today we had a short presentation from the childrens charity
<a href="http://www.ninemillion.org">NineMillion.org</a>.
To raise awareness they are hoping to get 9 million small actions from people on
the web. To help out you can just link to their site, create a video, or
basically make any small action you can on your website or blog, to point back to
their site. Just add the tag 'ninemillion' to any content you create. Its a
worthy cause and you can find out more about
<a href="http://www.ninemillion.org/ninemillion/ninemillion.cfm">here</a>.</p>
<h2>Conclusion</h2>
<p>There were a lot more interesting discussions happening that I have not
covered here. There was so much good stuff going on between the 3 buildings it
was hard to sit down and focus on any one thing. Loic and Geraldine have turned
LeWeb3 into a really great conference, possibly the best web conference of the
year. Some of the keynotes and panels were a little too light and relaxed at times,
but the startup action and networking really made up for it. </p>
<p>A good time was had
  by all at the Netvibes and Shopping.com party. Pretty much all of the web 2
  'glitterati' were here in force <em>[<strong>Ed:</strong> except for me of course]</em>. I will definitely be coming back here
  next year. If you are interested in seeing some of the keynotes and panels, you will be
  able to get all of the video from
  <a href="http://leweb3.vpod.tv/">here</a> once it is published.</p>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?a=MonVrZ"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/readwriteweb?i=MonVrZ" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=VQQCY5C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=VQQCY5C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=g7UCD8C"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=g7UCD8C" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=1JWVIqc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=1JWVIqc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=AxEfIYc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=AxEfIYc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=dFMiJtc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=dFMiJtc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?a=MaYB7KC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/readwriteweb?i=MaYB7KC" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/readwriteweb/~4/199466976" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~3/199920301/1-easy-service-to-keep-track-of.html</url><title>1 easy service to keep a track of EVERYTHING</title><date>2007-12-14 09:25:41.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Most of my online friends (that happily are becoming actual friends) rarely limit themselves to one online presence for a many reasons - one service rarely does it all, you need to <a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/11/5-easy-ways-to-protect-your-online.html">protect your online presence from ID theft</a> and we are generally early adopters and try a gazillion services before settling on one.<br /><br />I'll use myself as an example - you can find me actively online at:<br /><ul><li>this blog</li><li>Flickr for my photos</li><li>delicious for my bookmarks</li><li>YouTube for uploaded videos</li><li>Wellingtonista for my Wellington blogging</li><li>Facebook for my "this is me status"</li></ul>And that's just the day-to-day active ones - <a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2006/12/about-miramarmike.html">I'm 'at' a lot more places</a>.<br /><br />Whilst I've <a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html">set-up a few RSS feeds</a> for some of the more useful ones wouldn't it be grand just to subscribe to one feed and it all comes through? And that's the same for nearly everyone I know.<br /><br /><div><a href="http://friendfeed.com/" title="FriendFeed"><img src="http://i6.photobucket.com/albums/y211/miramarmike/logo-1.png" alt="FriendFeed" border="0" /></a><br /></div>FriendFeed is such a service that I have been running with for a month or so.<br />After you sign-up* it is extremely easy to click and add the services you use - click to add your delicious bookmarks feed, click and you've added your Flickr photo feed ...<br /><br />And then it's one feed to give to people - mine is <a href="http://friendfeed.com/miramarmike?format=atom">http://friendfeed.com/miramarmike?format=atom</a> - and have everything fed through.<br />No more having to worry about letting your friends know, "Oh, I've just started using X for tracking my movie going adventures and I think you'd love to know when I've seen a film"<br /><br />FriendFeed feeds out using:<br /><ul><li><a href="http://friendfeed.com/miramarmike?format=atom">Into your feed reader</a></li><li><a href="http://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=654055951">Facebook app</a></li><li><a href="http://friendfeed.com/embed?user=miramarmike">Embed into a website</a></li><li><a href="http://www.google.com/ig/add?url=http://friendfeed.com/embed/googlegadget/spec">iGoogle</a><br /></li></ul><br />Aaaaand, you can manage who is using FriendFeed to subscribe to you ... if you want.<br /><br /><span>* I know, you do have to sign-up - I can't wait for the growing adoption of OpenID</span><div class="blogger-post-footer"><hr />
<small>
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/search/label/enterprise%202.0" title="Subscribe to MirmarMike's Enterprise 2.0 postings">Enterprise 2.0 New Zealand style</a> since 2001<br />
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html" title="Subscribe to MiramarMike">Subscribe to other parts of MiramarMike</a> (Wellington, New Zealand)<br />
</small></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~4/199920301" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~3/199615600/watch-out-xero-here-comes-google.html</url><title>Watch out Xero, here comes Google</title><date>2007-12-14 09:59:26.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/online_accounting_google_apps.php"><img src="http://farm1.static.flickr.com/115/302869132_610ed22246.jpg?v=0" align="right" /></a>Of course, saying that <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/online_accounting_google_apps.php">Google would, could or should enter the sparse online accounting app arena</a> is mere speculation on the part of Read/Write Web columnist but I have to say they make a good case.<br /><br />It's either online accounting OR boosting their health stuff ... that's my prediction.<br /><br />And if it is accounting then <a href="http://www.xero.com/">Xero</a> is either sitting on the money (!) or they're about to welcome a very smart, determined and integrated player into their sandpit.<br /><br />Oh, one more prediction - I suspect Google is focusing on completely ripping the heart out of Microsoft's expensive and v average Sharepoint ("intranet"/CMS/"portal") offering sometime around mid-2008.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><hr />
<small>
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/search/label/enterprise%202.0" title="Subscribe to MirmarMike's Enterprise 2.0 postings">Enterprise 2.0 New Zealand style</a> since 2001<br />
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html" title="Subscribe to MiramarMike">Subscribe to other parts of MiramarMike</a> (Wellington, New Zealand)<br />
</small></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~4/199615600" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~3/199433153/google-maps-is-fully-here-in-new.html</url><title>Google Maps is fully here in New Zealand / Aotearoa</title><date>2007-12-13 11:49:41.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
What more can I say apart from, about time!<br />It will also be interesting to see how local (and very cool) competitor <a href="http://zoomin.co.nz/">ZoomIn</a> copes:<br /><br />From the <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/12/haere-mai-google-maps-lands-in-new.html">Official Google Blog posting</a>:<br /><blockquote>Today we're pleased to announce the full launch of <a title="http://maps.google.co.nz/ Google Maps in New Zealand" href="http://maps.google.co.nz/" target="_blank">Google Maps in New Zealand</a>. Although we've offered basic mapping in New Zealand for some time, today we're unveiling a localised and customised site for our users in New Zealand. We've added full local business search capabilities, plus the <a href="http://www.google.com/local/add/lookup?hl=en-AU&amp;gl=NZ" target="_blank">Local Business Centre</a>, so that any Kiwi business can get a free listing.<br /><br />While we know New Zealanders care about a lot more than rugby, racing and beer, we're pleased that now Google Maps can help you find the nearest place to do any of those things. Plus, you can find a <a title="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=cafe+ponsonby&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;z=15&amp;om=1 cafe in Ponsonby" href="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=cafe+ponsonby&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;z=15&amp;om=1" target="_blank">cafe in Ponsonby</a>, an <a title="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=indian+restaurant+wellington&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;z=9&amp;om=1 Indian restaurant in Wellington" href="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=indian+restaurant+wellington&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;z=9&amp;om=1" target="_blank">Indian restaurant in Wellington </a>, a <a title="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=plumber+dunedin&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;z=13&amp;om=1 plumber in Dunedin" href="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=plumber+dunedin&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;z=13&amp;om=1" target="_blank">plumber in Dunedin</a>, or a great <a title="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=queenstown+hotel&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;t=h&amp;z=11&amp;om=1 hotel for your next holiday" href="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=queenstown+hotel&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;t=h&amp;z=11&amp;om=1" target="_blank">hotel for your next holiday</a>.  All available on a PC or <a title="http://www.google.co.nz/gmm/index.html mobile phone" href="http://www.google.co.nz/gmm/index.html" target="_blank">mobile phone</a>  near you!<br /><br />And of course, Kiwis can also use Google Maps to look up an address, get <a title="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=auckland+to+rotorua&amp;sll=-45.031104,168.662731&amp;sspn=0.33435,0.6427&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;t=h&amp;z=9&amp;om=1 driving directions" href="http://maps.google.co.nz/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=auckland+to+rotorua&amp;sll=-45.031104,168.662731&amp;sspn=0.33435,0.6427&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;t=h&amp;z=9&amp;om=1" target="_blank">driving directions</a> (and the ability to drag them around), browse our satellite imagery, and even create custom maps that you can share with friends, all using the simple interface.</blockquote><div class="blogger-post-footer"><hr />
<small>
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/search/label/enterprise%202.0" title="Subscribe to MirmarMike's Enterprise 2.0 postings">Enterprise 2.0 New Zealand style</a> since 2001<br />
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html" title="Subscribe to MiramarMike">Subscribe to other parts of MiramarMike</a> (Wellington, New Zealand)<br />
</small></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~4/199433153" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RodDrury/~3/199632599/</url><title>Entourage and Time Machine</title><date>2007-12-13 08:35:50.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>The problem:  Entourage has one big store for it's local mail cache (pst file). So how does that work with Time Machine?</p>
<p>It doesn't.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.msdn.com/macmojo/archive/2007/12/12/it-s-about-the-data.aspx" target="_blank">http://blogs.msdn.com/macmojo/archive/2007/12/12/it-s-about-the-data.aspx</a></p>
<blockquote><p> Compatibility with Appleâ€™s Time Machine backup feature in Leopard is a database area that has received a lot of attention recently. Because Entourage uses a single file database, over time it can become large (sometimes really large). In those cases, Entourage data will not work optimally with Time Machine. Our recommendation is to exclude your Entourage Identity folder(s) in the Time Machine preferences</p></blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote><p> ... we understand that our Exchange customers want â€œan Exchange client on the Mac with features, performance, documentation, and reliability on par with Outlook.â€ This is a goal that will be achieved in stages, through Entourage 2008, its updates, and beyond.</p></blockquote>
<p>Hopefully not another 5 year wait.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://zenbu.wordpress.com/2007/12/13/the-google-local-business-centre-nz/</url><title>The Google Local Business Centre NZ</title><date>2007-12-13 00:12:32.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div class="snap_preview"><p>So <a href="http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2007/12/haere-mai-google-maps-lands-in-new.html">Google has finally launched a localised version of New Zealand Google Maps</a>.<br />
<a href="http://maps.google.co.nz/">http://maps.google.co.nz/</a></p>
<p>They have licensed 225,000 business listings from <a href="http://www.finda.co.nz">APN Finda</a> to seed the local information. It's an interesting play from Finda who is trying to beat <a href="http://www.yellow.co.nz">Yellow Pages</a> online. <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/3/story.cfm?c_id=3&amp;objectid=10481990">According to the NZ Herald</a>, it is a "data share" arrangement in exchange for links back to the finda.co.nz website but I only see one link at the very bottom of the page below the listings.<em> Business listings provided by <a href="http://www.finda.co.nz/">Finda</a>â„¢. </em>I don't imagine any user will be associating the Finda brand with their search experience, surely there is a data licensing fee as well???</p>
<p>As you would expect the Google search experience is pretty good. They combine results from the wider world web with the Finda data so pretty much any search will get some sort of answer. The obvious simple searches like hotels or restaurants are well covered. And of course, powered by Google servers, the results are snappy.</p>
<p>Google Australia and New Zealand executive Carl Sjogreen says "We have this set of features which we tend to roll-out as we get them ready. But when we get the full package - and the <strong>crown jewel</strong> of that is <strong>local search</strong> - we launch a domain for the local market."<br />
The emphasis is mine, I've thought for a long time that local search is a massive opportunity because of the high relevance of advertising to both the consumer and advertiser, obviously Google agrees.</p>
<p>Google also encourages businesses to list themselves in their Google Local Business Centre. A series of simple forms with a nifty phone-back validation system, even sporting a kiwi accent! I was a bit amazed by the statement that it would take <strong>4 weeks </strong>for the listing to appear on Google Maps though, that seems ridulously long.</p>
<p>You're probably thinking (I certainly am) ; how can Zenbu compete with Google?</p>
<ul>
<li>Zenbu data is available under a <a href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution license</a>. Openness counts, maybe only to geeks right now, but maybe more and more to the masses too.</li>
<li>Zenbu edits are instantly available online.</li>
<li>Zenbu's Find Nearest functionality is still unseen elsewhere.</li>
<li>With your support! <a href="http://www.zenbu.co.nz/get-involved.html">Get involved</a>.</li>
</ul>
<p>One thing is guaranteed, the local search space in NZ just got even more interesting.</p>
</div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/techsploder/2007/12/13/is-it-just-me-or-is-uba-broadband-expensive-and-slow-to-come/</url><title>Is it just me or is UBA broadband expensive and slow to come?</title><date>2007-12-13 01:04:07.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>The Commerce Commission has issued its final determination for "Unbundled Bitstream Access", which removes the ban on providing so-called real-time services (basically any application that's latency-sensitive, like gaming, VoIP and VPNs) over DSL that was mysteriously enough inserted into the previous legislation.</p>
<p>Having some sort of Quality of Service standards for DSL is great. This is something that customers in other countries have had for years and New Zealanders will get it by... the last half of next year.</p>
<p>Why does the implementation have to be so slow?</p>
<p>The wholesale pricing seems steep too - remember that ISPs have to add some margin on top of what Telecom charges them.</p>
<p>Does the determination cover faster ADSL2+ lines? Can we have faster than 180kbit/s guaranteed bandwidth by then?</p>
<p>Media release from ComCom below.</p>
<blockquote><p>The Commerce Commission has issued its final determination on the price and non-price terms on which Telecom must make the unbundled bitstream access (UBA) service available to other telecommunications providers.The UBA service is a wholesale service that allows telecommunications companies to supply a range of broadband services to retail customers.</p>
<p>"The UBA suite of services will allow telecommunications companies to supply a diverse range of new retail services over broadband, and will stimulate competition for retail customers," Telecommunications Commissioner Dr Ross Patterson said today.</p>
<p>"Telecommunications companies will now be able to offer high-quality Voice over IP (VoIP) services, and consumers will no longer be required to purchase a standard telephone service to have access to a broadband connection," Dr Patterson said.</p>
<p>"This heralds a fundamental change to the way that telecommunications services can and will be provided to consumers and, along with the Unbundled Copper Local Loop (UCLL) and Co-location services, will promote nationwide competition for the long-term benefit of consumers," Dr Patterson said.</p>
<p>The Commission has set prices for a Basic UBA service, and three Enhanced UBA services with different settings for quality of service. The Enhanced UBA services allow telecommunications companies to provide good quality VoIP and other real-time services over broadband.</p>
<p>Telecommunications companies may now choose to supply UBA-based services without a traditional phone service (Naked DSL). Where Naked DSL is acquired, the telecommunication company must also meet the costs of Telecom's local loop network. The Commission has adopted the same price for the local loop as in the draft determination for the UCLL service issued in July. This results in geographically de-averaged pricing for the naked UBA services, consistent with the approach in the earlier local loop determination. The pricing for UBA services is as follows:</p>
<p><em>With POTS</em><br />
Basic UBA service $27.44<br />
40 kbps Enhanced UBA service $33.06<br />
90 kbps Enhanced UBA service $41.11<br />
180 kbps Enhanced UBA service $47.99</p>
<p><em>Monthly charge without POTS - Urban</em><br />
Basic UBA service $47.28</p>
<p>40 kbps Enhanced UBA service $52.90<br />
90 kbps Enhanced UBA service $60.95<br />
180 kbps Enhanced UBA service $67.83</p>
<p><em>Monthly charge without POTS - Non-Urban</em><br />
Basic UBA service $64.07<br />
40 kbps Enhanced UBA service $69.69<br />
90 kbps Enhanced UBA service $77.74<br />
180 kbps Enhanced UBA service $84.62</p>
<p><em><strong>The Basic UBA service is due to be delivered on 8 July 2008. The 40 kbps and 90 kbps Enhanced UBA services are due to be delivered on 23 September 2008, with the implementation of the 180 enhanced service to occur 90 days after the 40 and 90 kbps Enhanced UBA services have been delivered.</strong></em></p>
<p>The Commission's UBA determination and related documents can be found on its website at <a target="_blank" href="http://www.comcom.govt.nz/"><strong>www.comcom.govt.nz </strong></a>under Industry Regulation/Telecommunications/Standard Terms Determinations/Unbundled bitstream access</p>
<p><strong>Background</strong><br />
Plain old telephone service, or POTS, is a term which describes the voice-grade telephone service that remains the basic form of residential and small business service connection to the telephone network in most parts of the world.</p>
<p>Unbundled bitstream access. The unbundled bitstream access refers to the wholesale broadband service provided by Telecom from the end-user to the first data switch, or equivalent facility, other than a Digital Subscriber Line Access Multiplexer (DSLAM). It allows telecommunications companies to supply a range of broadband services to retail customers.</p>
<p>Standard Terms Determination process under amended Telecommunications Act. On 22 December 2006, the Telecommunications Act was amended to incorporate a process for the Commission to make a standard terms determination on which a designated access or specified service must be supplied by Telecom to all access seekers requesting the service. A standard terms determination includes non-price terms proposed by Telecom, usually in consultation with access seekers, and price terms for access to the service set by the Commission.</p>
<p>Amended Telecommunications Act. In December 2006 an amended Telecommunications Act was passed that provides for, amongst other things, the unbundling of the local loop, and the implementation of local loop unbundling by way of standard terms determinations. The determination process was initiated for these unbundled services in early 2007. A draft determination was released on 31 July 2007. Interested parties then had the opportunity to provide submissions on the draft determination. The Commission held a conference in September 2007 to seek additional information on particular aspects of the submissions.</p></blockquote>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
