<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Travel</title>
<item>
<url>http://asianinvasion2006.blogspot.com/2007/12/fashion-challenge-for-gilda-k.html</url><title>Fashion Challenge for Gilda K. ©</title><date>2007-12-13 04:47:22.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div><a href="http://shoeblogs.com/2007/10/04/prada-spring-summer-2008/">Dare you.</a><br /><br />While glowing through the shops in Hong Kong recently looking for a suit in black, shoes in black or skirts in black, I came across some marketing literature for the 2008 Spring Prada collection.<br /><br />Among the more challenging fashion items were these, and I am SO glad I could find them on the internet.  UnPC Lesbian and Idle Vice will be excited:<br /></div><br /><img alt="The image “http://shoeblogs.com/wordpress/images/prada08a.jpg” cannot be displayed, because it contains errors." src="http://shoeblogs.com/wordpress/images/prada08a.jpg" /><img alt="The image “http://www.style.com/slideshows/fashionshows/S2008RTW/PRADA/DETAILS/00520m.jpg” cannot be displayed, because it contains errors." src="http://www.style.com/slideshows/fashionshows/S2008RTW/PRADA/DETAILS/00520m.jpg" /><br /><br /><div>I have yet to see the shoes in person but I think they would go fabulously with this outfit of Gilda K's © (courtesy Idle Vice, Noz from A-List).<br /></div><br /><a href="http://bp3.blogger.com/_IJIlXaij0EQ/Rx0EDg4CiuI/AAAAAAAAAUo/RuUkBk5gacM/s1600-h/gilda.jpg"><img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_IJIlXaij0EQ/Rx0EDg4CiuI/AAAAAAAAAUo/RuUkBk5gacM/s320/gilda.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5124256409428593378" border="0" /></a><br /><div>Of course as the Queen of Friggin' Fashion that I am, I think either a black dress or designer jeans, a tight vintage t-shirt, Prada sneakers, hang-over sunnies and L.A. Lakers fitted cap will get you in anywhere.<br /><br />But it <span>would </span>be fun if as the most outrageous dresser in Auckland, Gilda K. © could fit them into her wardrobe somewhere.<br /><br />They are outfrigginrageous and would accentuate the lines in the maroon pants far better than the boring black shoes there in the picture.<br /></div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://silentrunning.tv/?p=2566</url><title>Antarctic Story</title><date>2007-12-13 21:19:45.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>If New Zealand is a dagger thrusting at the heart of Antarctica then Christchurch is that knife-point. This is the base-camp for everyone going on down to mix it with the penguins. Always has been. From Falcon Scott and Amundson, and on. Not for nothing we have Scott's statue in town, nor that we've got the International Antarctic Center.</p>
<p>And now we're base-camp for another great civilising venture.</p>
<p align="center"><img id="image2565" title="airbus.jpg" alt="airbus.jpg" src="http://silentrunning.tv/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/airbus.jpg" /></p>
<p align="center"><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322766a12.html">http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322766a12.html</a></p>
<p>Just one problem...</p>
<blockquote><p>Australia has scored an Antarctic coup by successfully landing a commercial airliner at its polar base.</p>
<p>Its success has major implications for the Christchurch based polar operation which each summer despatches military aircraft southward.</p></blockquote>
<p>Yes. Those bloody Australians are doing it! Not us! This is worse than that time they stuck an Australian flag on that huge break-away ice burg off the coast of Otago!</p>
<p>Christchurch is still the penultimate lilly pad. Flippin' dingo-owners have dropped a crikey in the tucker bag and nailed the goanna, but!</p>
<p>Why aren't Kiwis leading the way on this one!!? I'll tell you why: Erebus. We crashed into it.</p>
<p>A great big Mountain, an active volcano, and on the subcontinent to end all subcontinents. Something to see. As a great achievement of civilisation and man's grasp of nature, Air New Zealand used to fly tourists to Erebus for a look, then home again. Used to.</p>
<p>In 1979 one such flight went horribly wrong. The crash scarred Erebus a little, but New Zealand a lot. All died. I had dinner with a bloke the other day and it came up that he was mates with one of those sent down to collect the corpses- he was severely effected. Back then (apart from 6mth olds like me) most everyone in NZ was related to, or knew someone, involved. As usual, when something goes wrong in New Zealand, we respond with a knee-jerk. No more flights to Erebus.</p>
<p>Of course, what a proper capitalist country would do would be to get back on the horse.</p>
<p>Australia, 28years latter, has done. It's not on their national psyche as it is ours, and thus they have trumped us. Again.
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5485</url><title>Pacific Blue rocks</title><date>2007-12-14 05:41:57.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
I flew <a href="http://www.pacificblue.co.nz/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pacific Blue</a>  today to Wellington. What a refreshing approach to domestic travel that&nbsp;was.
</p>
<p>
For a start clearing boarding was a breeze and rapid, the staff are friendly and the <a href="http://www.boeing.com/commercial/737family/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">737-800's</a>  rock, there is definately more leg room and fun is the operative word for the&nbsp;staff.
</p>
<p>
The only slack thing was arrival at Wellington and the the Fawlty Tower upstairs/downstairs  mission to get to the baggage carousel, though i am sure this is a temporary&nbsp;situation. 
</p>
<p>
Air New Zealand  and Qantas will take a pasting from these&nbsp;guys.
</p>
<p>
When they explain the safety procedures the purser said &quot;...the seatbelt should be fasten low and tight across your sexy lap...&quot; The service is very pleasant and accomodating rather than the typical inconvenience that Air New Zealand stewards seem to&nbsp;impart.
</p>
<p>
I will definately be using these guys more. Oh and one can't complain about the&nbsp;price. 
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5485</url><title>Pacific Blue rocks</title><date>2007-12-14 05:41:57.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
I flew <a href="http://www.pacificblue.co.nz/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Pacific Blue</a>  today to Wellington. What a refreshing approach to domestic travel that&nbsp;was.
</p>
<p>
For a start clearing boarding was a breeze and rapid, the staff are friendly and the <a href="http://www.boeing.com/commercial/737family/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">737-800's</a>  rock, there is definately more leg room and fun is the operative word for the&nbsp;staff.
</p>
<p>
The only slack thing was arrival at Wellington and the the Fawlty Tower upstairs/downstairs  mission to get to the baggage carousel, though i am sure this is a temporary&nbsp;situation. 
</p>
<p>
Air New Zealand  and Qantas will take a pasting from these&nbsp;guys.
</p>
<p>
When they explain the safety procedures the purser said &quot;...the seatbelt should be fasten low and tight across your sexy lap...&quot; The service is very pleasant and accomodating rather than the typical inconvenience that Air New Zealand stewards seem to&nbsp;impart.
</p>
<p>
I will definately be using these guys more. Oh and one can't complain about the&nbsp;price. 
</p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
