<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<category>
<title>Uncategorised</title>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~3/199607179/</url><title>Fox pushes Cameron’s Avatar back to Dec ‘09</title><date>2007-12-13 07:16:53.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
20th Century Fox, the studio in charge of James Cameron's Avatar rearranged their 2009 release schedule, moving Avatar from it's original June 22nd release date to December 18, 2009.
Fox stated the reason for the change was to allow for more Post-Production time to finish the film in time for release.
The also stated that there were [...]<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=qapWdjC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=qapWdjC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=Ox5pzBc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=Ox5pzBc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~4/199607179" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~3/199607181/</url><title>Update on production of The Lovely Bones</title><date>2007-12-13 07:16:49.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
The Lovely Bones has been in production in Pennsylvania, US, for over 6 weeks now, and the good folks who run The Lovely Bones Movie Blog have been keeping track of the filming.


The crew have filmed in many different towns already and there has been plenty of people taking photos and sending them in. At [...]<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=HP5g7QC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=HP5g7QC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=QBpbttc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=QBpbttc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~4/199607181" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~3/199607182/</url><title>New trailer for 10,000BC</title><date>2007-12-13 07:16:46.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
CHUD.com has a new trailer for Roland Emmerich's 10,000BC, filmed in the South Island last year, which is released in cinemas March 7, 2008.
You can watch the trailer at this link (quicktime required).<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=TH9FwSC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=TH9FwSC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=eJhypPc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=eJhypPc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~4/199607182" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~3/199607184/</url><title>Update on The Water Horse</title><date>2007-12-13 07:16:41.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
The Water Horse: Legend of the Deep, based on the book by Dick King-Smith and directed by Jay Russel, is released in cinemas in the US on Christmas Day and in NZ on New Years Day.
We've missed a bit of news over the past few weeks for the film but I'm going to put it [...]<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=F3JoxsC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=F3JoxsC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=PT1trnc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=PT1trnc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~4/199607184" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~3/199607186/</url><title>Silvaticus 3015 to film in Wellington next year</title><date>2007-12-13 07:16:27.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
A new sci-fi film called Silvaticus 3015 has been added to the growing list of Sci-Fi films being shot here.
Los Angeles independent movie company Hawk Eye Studios will be filming the NZ$109m epic in Wellington late next year.
The film is set more than 500 years into the future and follows the story of survivors from [...]<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=6blhkIC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=6blhkIC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?a=f2vekIc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/BlackMagic?i=f2vekIc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/BlackMagic/~4/199607186" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://asianinvasion2006.blogspot.com/2007/12/fonterra-santa.html</url><title>Fonterra Santa</title><date>2007-12-13 14:05:25.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div>I was never a demanding child when it came to Christmas.  I never asked for anything that my parents could not afford.<br /><br />Such low expectations have meant of course that a non-inflationary adjusted $200 in a card is presented to me every year.  Now $200 is great when you are 12 years old.  But twenty years later?  Well even Cullen makes inflation adjustments.    And NOC's presents now come to more than mine. She's six.<br /><br />So this year I will be raising the expectational stakes to something more fitting of an adult. I'd quite like this:<br /><div><br /><br /><img alt="http://www.glamourwatches.com/site/images/cartier-watch.jpg" src="http://www.glamourwatches.com/site/images/cartier-watch.jpg" /><br /><br />Their <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322802a10.html">reported earnings</a> being well over $800K, I suspect there will be plenty of children of Fonterra's Santa lining up for likewise.<br /></div></div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.ellisnz.com/2007/12/closing-gap.html</url><title>Closing the Gap</title><date>2007-12-13 19:46:11.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Recent studies have indicated that the Average Australian income is 30% higher than the Average New Zealand Income.  What this means is that New Zealand lags so far behind Australia that it will take a quarter of a century of slightly higher growth to catch up to Australian incomes.

The table below shows that if New Zealand's average income grew at 4%, and Australia's at only 3%, in 2032 the]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.ellisnz.com/2007/12/la-rvolution-est-arrive-la-victoire-du.html</url><title>La révolution est arrivée! La victoire du marché libre!</title><date>2007-12-13 19:20:26.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
French President Nicolas Sarkozy has started cutting the bloated french civil service with an annoucement that a third of civil servants who retire next year will not be replaced, rising to 50% the following years.  Also announced are reductions in pension benefits for civil servants (including members of the National Assembly).

Already, some unions are threatening to strike over the cuts. These]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://mikeenz.blogspot.com/2007/12/round-3-greens-respond.html</url><title>Round 3: The Greens Respond</title><date>2007-12-13 19:37:40.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
This just gets better and better.  Turns out Anderton was full of shit (who would have thought) and the Greens didn't block the urgency, because they weren't asked (which is a bit of a moot point, as they would have blocked it anyway). 

Anderton refuses to control BZP, blames Greens
Thursday, 13 December 2007, 2:15 pm
Press Release: Green Party
13 December 2007

Anderton refuses to control BZP,]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://mikeenz.blogspot.com/2007/12/stanz-responds-party-pill-ban-lapse.html</url><title>Stanz Responds: Party Pill Ban Lapse Averts Disaster.</title><date>2007-12-13 19:35:20.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
The Social Tonics Association of New  Zealand today said that the pre-Christmas Party Pill ban was poorly  planned. “A pre-Christmas ban would have sent hundreds of thousands  of everyday kiwi consumers to the black market gangs to stock up for  their festivities,” said STANZ Chairman Matt Bowden, “it is hardly  surprising that such a notion doesn’t have enough support in Parliament,  it was a]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://mikeenz.blogspot.com/2007/12/post-bzp-pr-war-grinch-who-tried-to.html</url><title>The post BZP PR War... The Grinch who tried to steal Christmas</title><date>2007-12-13 19:25:45.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Drug pushers target kids as BZP Bill delayed
Thursday, 13 December 2007, 11:46 am
Press Release: New Zealand Government
14 December 2007

Drug pushers target kids with lollipops as BZP Bill delayed

The Bill to classify BZP as a Class C1 drug will not now be passed until early in the new year, Associate Minister of Health Jim Anderton said today.

The Misuse of Drugs (Classification of BZP)]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/beer-o-stu-2007-beer-picks.html</url><title>Beer O'Clock: Stu's 2007 beer picks</title><date>2007-12-14 16:00:42.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Yes, it's that time again when we look start to look back at the year that's been and, if we haven't drunk enough to forget most of them -- and as Humphrey Bogart used to say, the trouble with the world is that everyone is just one drink behind -- we begin to gather from the tangled skeins of this year's memories some sort of order.  The task this year, beer-wise at least, falls to SOBA's Stus,]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/crikey-brain.html</url><title>Crikey, a brain!</title><date>2007-12-14 13:39:21.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
I've heard suggestions that I haven't got a brain, and if I did I've never used it.  I know, I've heard you.  But me baby, I've got statistics, I've got facts.  I've got pictures.  Herewith the shocking evidence: actual picture proof that I both have a brain and, from those few splodges of colour there, that I sometimes even use it.  Frightening, isn't it.  (The pics, by the way, come from a]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/consensus-says-scientists-letter-to-un.html</url><title>"No consensus" says scientists' letter to UN head</title><date>2007-12-14 10:14:36.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
An open letter to the UN Secretary General from nearly a hundred scientists and at least a dozen economists says the UN/IPCC climate conference taking place in Bali is "taking the world in entirely the wrong direction."  "It is not possible to stop climate change, a natural phenomenon that has affected humanity through the ages," say the signatories. "We therefore need to equip nations to become]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/so-much-nonsense-spoken-about-so-much.html</url><title>So much nonsense spoken about so much nonsense</title><date>2007-12-14 08:06:13.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Rarely has so much nonsense been spoken about so much nonsense.   Careful not to overstate himself, our Bali correspondent tells his story: "In a speech likely to go down in history as an oratorical milestone in the fight against global warming [an "oratorical milestone" -- goodness!], Al Gore, former US vice-president and co-winner of this year's Nobel Peace Prize, electrified [electrified!] the]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/towers-michael-newberry.html</url><title>'Twin Towers' - Michael Newberry</title><date>2007-12-14 02:30:00.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
For what he describes as "a change of pace" from finishing his painting, Venus, artist Michael Newberry has been working on a series of drawings of the nude interacting with his shadow, about which Michael says:      There is a lot of play on metaphor, on alter-egos, and light and dark.     This is the first one finished in the group. Twin Towers.     There is something sad about]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/could-skyhawks-form-privateers-air.html</url><title>Could Skyhawks form a privateers' Air Force?</title><date>2007-12-13 15:41:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Well, why not?  Given that it's now obvious that no other Air Force is either able or willing to buy NZ's former Air Force Skyhawks; and given that they've now been shrink-wrapped in latex  so they can be parked outside in the rain; and given that they've cost taxpayers $8 million to store since the Clark Government decided they didn't have a country worth defending and didn't need a fighter wing]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/sense-and-non-sense-from-would-be-world.html</url><title>Sense and non-sense from would-be world leaders</title><date>2007-12-13 15:52:21.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Two comments from two sources this morning for your comparison, one from a politician more braindead than normal, and the other from a very unlikely source showing more sense on the global warming charade than from many so called science writers -- and certainly more sense than is coming out of Bali at present.   Here's the first comment, from Republican presidential hopeful Mike Huckabee who,]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/hard-lessons-about-right-to-self.html</url><title>Hard lessons about the right to self-defence (updated)</title><date>2007-12-13 15:39:12.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
It starts like a really bad joke, and ends really badly:  This bloke walks into a shopping mall with a 'gun-free zone.'  He has a gun.  He pulls gun and shoots.  Eight people are killed.  Bad joke. Bad law.  This bloke walks into a small missionary training centre in Denver. He has a gun.  He pulls gun and shoots.  Two people killed. He gets away.  Bad joke.  Here's the punchline: This same bloke]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pc.blogspot.com/2007/12/debate-is-over-ensure-ipcc-bali.html</url><title>"The debate is over" ensure IPCC's Bali bouncers</title><date>2007-12-14 07:44:44.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Debate at the IPCC's Bali High global warming talk-fest is being kept down by having dissenters kept out (a process all too familiar to observers of the Electoral Finance Bill, and of the methodology by which the IPCC's 'Summaries for Policymakers' are produced).   Newspapers opposing the party line have been refused press credentials, and distinguished scientists from Africa, Australia, India,]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://oswaldbastable.blogspot.com/2007/12/buy-fireman-beer.html</url><title>Buy a Fireman a beer!</title><date>2007-12-14 13:14:21.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<span>I can't praise those unpaid volunteers enough!<br /><br />I was one of the first on the scene of a nasty crash an hour ago. The vehicle had hit a power pole, the driver was badly injured and the ute was on fire.<br /><br />With my extinguisher and another from another first-aider we kept the fire down, but could not extinguish it.<br /><br />The driver was trapped and there was no way we could get her out.<br /><br />It was a real relief to see that fire crew arrive, just as the engine was starting to flare up, as we were near out of options!<br /><br /><span><span>Update:</span></span><br /><br /><a href="http://www.times-age.co.nz/localnews/storydisplay.cfm?storyid=3758273&amp;thesection=localnews&amp;thesubsection=&amp;thesecondsubsection=">Story here:</a><br /></span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://peteremcc.wordpress.com/2007/12/14/starship-or-taxpayers/</url><title>peteremcc</title><date>2007-12-13 16:32:13.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div class="snap_preview"><p>Should NZ First have given its election money to Starship not taxpayers?<br />
That's what the Herald are asking in their <strong><a target="_blank" href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/story.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482120">latest "Your Views" question</a></strong>.</p>
<p>Reading the responses is fantastic.<br />
Most people think that it is taxpayer's money and NZ First are wrong to not pay it pack.<br />
The rest seem to be the ones who realise it wouldn't go back to 'taxpayers' but back into the government/labour's coffers and consider Starship more worthy!<br />
I'm not sure which argument I prefer... <img src="http://peteremcc.wordpress.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_biggrin.gif" alt=":D" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>Next year's election is going to be great, but maybe not for Winston. <img src="http://peteremcc.wordpress.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_smile.gif" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" /></p>
</div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://hosking.blogspot.com/2007/12/us-election.html</url><title>The US election...</title><date>2007-12-14 18:18:00.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
You can find out which candidate is closest to your views if you click on <a href="http://www.speakout.com/VoteMatch/senate2006.asp?quiz=2008">this survey.</a><br /><br />Closest to me is Rudy Guiliani, which doesn't surprise me all that much.<br /><br />Second though is Hilary Clinton, which is a surprise, especially when the survey concludes I'm a 'moderate libertarian'. (The label is not one I'd choose but its probably not that far off).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://section59.blogspot.com/2007/12/77pc-of-parents-smack-study.html</url><title>77pc of parents smack - study</title><date>2007-12-14 08:13:52.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
According to a new study, 77% of parents smack their children

This from the NZ Herald
_________________________________________________
As many as 77 per cent of parents aged 25 in a study said they had smacked children, with 12 per cent admitting they severely assaulted a child in the past year. The data was gathered as part of a Christchurch Health and Development Study and reported in the]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://silentrunning.tv/?p=2564</url><title>Young Communist League, USA</title><date>2007-12-13 20:19:45.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img id="image2563" title="24-140x140.jpg" alt="24-140x140.jpg" src="http://silentrunning.tv/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/24-140x140.jpg" align="left" /></p>
<p>At the post office yesterday I was once again bemused to see symbols and language of Communism being used to sell a product. The image of Che Guevara, the communist star, etc....'Call your comrade in Cuba' it said.</p>
<p>And now, I was just on the <a href="http://yclusa.org/section-trade">Young Communist League USA</a> website. The top link invites us to <strike>purge the bourgeois</strike> go shopping!<br />
'Skip the usual holiday consumerism and buy your friends and family YCL gear! With have something for everyone- from our "Capitalism Sucks" and "iVote" t-shirts, to buttons to subscriptions to our magazine, Dynamic. No need to stand in long lines, you can order now from our online store.'</p>
<p>They need a new communications person -<br />
- Skip consumerism by <em><strong>*buying*</strong></em> from us!<br />
- They offer a <strong>choice</strong> of goods - "something for everyone"<br />
- "No need to stand in long lines" like you would for bread under an alternative economic order!</p>
<p>Well I guess they get some points for not accepting AmEx...<br />
Tips to: Act Jack for passing that one on!
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://silentrunning.tv/?p=2562</url><title>Douglas to Dancing</title><date>2007-12-13 20:03:09.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://douglastodancing.blogspot.com/2007/12/dual-citizenship-restrictions-on-mps.html">From Douglas To Dancing</a> is a new blog written ALLLL about my beloved ACT Party. Written by Geoffrey Miller, an Otago honors student.</p>
<p>His honors dissertation, also called 'Douglas to Dancing' is in the pipes now. Indeed, he's just had a report on it from on high. The title of course refers to the beginnings with Roger Douglas (whome I blogged about a few days ago) and the latest greatest achievement of ACT recognition, signified by leader Rodney Hide's televised dancing achivements.</p>
<p>I think he's a bit of a punk. Let's keep an eye on him.
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5486</url><title>Aussies select Kiwi to teach them how to play Rugby</title><date>2007-12-14 05:51:34.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/4/story.cfm?c_id=4&amp;objectid=10482083" rel="nofollow">Deans to coach Wallabies and Crusaders - 14 Dec 2007 - nzherald: Sports news - New Zealand and International Sport news and&nbsp;results</a></p>
<p>Good riddance, fecking South&nbsp;Islanders.</p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5484</url><title>Oh STFU Winston</title><date>2007-12-14 01:23:16.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/category/story.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482351" rel="nofollow">Winston Peters and Bob Clarkson at loggerheads again - 14 Dec 2007 - Politics: New Zealand Political News, Analysis and Comment - <span class="caps">NZ</span>&nbsp;Herald</a></p>
<p>We are sick of hearing about who you are going to sue next. Most of the time you lose, in fact have you ever won&nbsp;anything?</p>
<p>You are nothing short of a&nbsp;windbag. </p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5482</url><title>NZ First hypocrisy exposed fully</title><date>2007-12-13 19:22:47.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/nz_first_on_electoral_reform.html" rel="nofollow">Kiwiblog » Blog Archive » <span class="caps">NZ</span> First on Electoral&nbsp;Reform</a></p>
<p>Winston likes to think and constantly intones that his party is the only one with integrity. Perhaps he mutters under his breath whenever he says this "...of a&nbsp;whore".</p>
<p><span class="caps">DPF</span> has exposed his and his party's hypocrisy for all to&nbsp;see.</p>
<p>Winston First supporters should hang their heads in&nbsp;shame.</p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5477</url><title>Shadbolt threat to topple Govt</title><date>2007-12-13 18:52:15.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482269&amp;ref=rss" rel="nofollow">Shadbolt threat to topple Govt</a> - <i>Invercargill Mayor Tim Shadbolt says he will fight to bring down the Government if funding to the Southern Institute of Technology is cut.<br />
The Government will announce today how much money universities, polytechnics and other tertiary...</i> [<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/" rel="nofollow"><span class="caps">NZ</span> Politics</a>]
</p>
<p>
Tim Shadbolt, someone I have no time for, is mad, real mad. He is going to campaign to bring the government down.....well he will be able to place a couple of ads in the paper to do so because he will be limited to&nbsp;$120,000.
</p>
<p>
Unless of course he follows is Vietnam War protesting days and willfully breaks the&nbsp;law. 
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.holdenrepublic.org.nz/2007/12/mumpsimuses.html</url><title>Mumpsimuses</title><date>2007-12-13 17:04:57.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Kiwiblogblog has a hilarious post on "<a href="http://kiwiblogblog.wordpress.com/2007/12/13/mumpsimuses-1-monarchists/">Mumpsimuses</a>" guess who the first group persecuted are...<br /><br />Meanwhile, <a href="http://norightturn.blogspot.com/2007/12/cant-they-just-join-sca.html">No Right Turn</a> admits to dressing up like a Beefeater (I assume that's what monarchy role plays are about).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://observationz.blogspot.com/2007/12/test.html</url><title>A test</title><date>2007-12-14 16:11:34.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
This is just a test.<br /><br /><br /><span class="post-author vcard">Posted by <span class="fn">Rich</span> <span class="post-timestamp">at <a class="timestamp-link" title="permanent link" href="http://observationz.blogspot.com/2007/11/fud-from-genesis.html" rel="bookmark"><abbr class="published" title="2007-11-23T13:45:00+13:00">13:45</abbr></a></span> <span class="post-comment-link"><a class="comment-link" href="http://www.blogger.com/comment.g?blogID=8054883&amp;postID=2328509435358132799">4 comments</a></span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.philosophyetc.net/2007/12/daemons.html</url><title>Daemons</title><date>2007-12-13 22:09:17.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.princeton.edu/pr/home/02/0410_tiger/hmcap.html">Naturally</a>, I'm <a href="http://www.goldencompassmovie.com/?&start=daemons">a tiger</a> at heart:<br /><br /><br />(Though I'm a little puzzled at how their questions map on to some of the resulting character traits...)<div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?a=0RoyLzC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?i=0RoyLzC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?a=BucqphC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?i=BucqphC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?a=IyOo1Zc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/PhilosophyEtCetera?i=IyOo1Zc" border="0" /></a>
</div>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.publicaddress.net/default,4701.sm</url><title>Southerly: I've Turned Gay for Public Address</title><date>2007-12-13 20:49:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>I've been gay for about three hours now -- and, frankly, I wish I'd done it years ago.</p><p>The raison d'être for my change in sexual preference is, of course, the departure of Tze Ming Mok.  Her exit made Public Address thirty-three per cent less representative of women, and one hundred per cent less representative of New Zealand Arts Foundation laureates.  Bang went our reputation for diversity...</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.publicaddress.net/default,4699.sm</url><title>Radiation: And the Shortie killer is ...</title><date>2007-12-13 18:21:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>... I’m picking … Joey.</p><p>… who will stalk Tania. He’s behind you! Also, next year, Chris Warner is bumped off in a car crash, Toni inherits all the money and she, Guy, Tuesday and Harry move back into Warner Towers, where Guy proceeds to spend all the money on drugs. Shanti and Scotty have a totally Bollywood wedding, just because it would be fun. Before that, Shanti’s betrothed arrives from India and is totally gay and he and Gerald have a thing...</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.publicaddress.net/default,4696.sm</url><title>OnPoint: Terra Firma</title><date>2007-12-13 02:40:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Over dinner on Monday, Jon and I got into a rather sombre conversation about the last days of Hemingway, which he spent in Ketchum, Idaho. When the similarly doomed Hunter S Thompson retraced Hemingway's footsteps – right to the very last – he came to the conclusion that he was, like Hemingway, no longer connected to the zeitgeist. His life as a writer had, therefore, finished...]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.publicaddress.net/default,4695.sm</url><title>Busytown: Pavlova Paradise</title><date>2007-12-13 02:35:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
So bai bai, Tze Ming, or should that be twe meh naw? You went through this place like a dose of the salts, in a good way. I will miss your brilliant prose, your assiduous non-taking of prisoners, and your (ahem) scouring wit. It already feels quiet and, dare I say it, a little boring without you. ...]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://tumeke.blogspot.com/2007/12/sir-howard-morrison-demands-new-50c.html</url><title>Sir Howard Morrison demands new 50c stamp - claims "creatively dead" for last 20 years</title><date>2007-12-14 17:20:38.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.latimes.com/news/local/la-me-sinatra13dec13,1,7868951.story?coll=la-headlines-california">News</a>:<br /><i>Beverly Hills - Frank Sinatra's blue eyes will stare out from a commemorative postage stamp to be issued 10 years after the legendary crooner's death, United States Postal Service officials said on Wednesday.</i><br /><br />US Postal Service: <a href="http://www.usps.com/communications/newsroom/2007/sr07_083.htm">Frank Sinatra Commemorative Stamp</a>.<br /><br /><a href="http://bp2.blogger.com/_Yu6lJst3lkM/R2H-ZvLRmoI/AAAAAAAAAGE/zyPsLvSPDCQ/s1600-h/sinatra_stamp_usps_.jpg"><img src="http://bp2.blogger.com/_Yu6lJst3lkM/R2H-ZvLRmoI/AAAAAAAAAGE/zyPsLvSPDCQ/s400/sinatra_stamp_usps_.jpg" border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143671967547759234" /></a>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/where-paris-hilton-gets-her-cute-puppies/</url><title>where paris hilton gets her ‘cute puppies’..</title><date>2007-12-13 20:57:18.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
"..The HSUS’s undercover investigation relealed that many of the puppies sold at Pets of Bel Air come from puppy mills in the Midwest including Arkansas, Kansas, and Oklahoma. 
At these large-scale factory farm operations, we found hundreds of breeding dogs living in barren wire cages where they are treated like production machines. 
Some had untreated [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/yet-more-signs-of-the-meltdown/</url><title>yet more ’signs of the meltdown’..</title><date>2007-12-13 20:47:47.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
"..Bank of America Corp. said Monday that it's shutting a $12 billion a money-market fund of sorts and halting cash withdrawals after losses from complex investments tied to the mortgage crisis. 

The so-called enhanced-cash fund, which was only offered privately to institutional investors, saw its net asset value dip below $1 recently.

It closed at 99.42 [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/i-never-worked-with-ike-but-i-had-an-engineer-friend-tell-me-a-harrowing-story-about-an-all-night-cocaine-fueled-recording-session-with-ike-and-a-really-big-pistolscary/</url><title>“..I never worked with Ike, but I had an engineer friend tell me a harrowing story about an all-night cocaine-fueled recording session with Ike and a really big pistol..Scary..”</title><date>2007-12-13 19:45:21.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
ike has died..
and..(as noted here)..
he is credited with making the first rock 'n roll song..ever..!
'rocket 88&#8242;..recorded/produced at/by sun records/sam phillips..in 1951..
this also links to a 'ripping' performance of perhaps the most 'religious' pop song..ever..
'river deep mountain high'..
(and..y'know..i debated whether to include  'river' in the whoar fm one playlist..
with grounds for rejection being 'over-use'..(slipping into [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/alan-greenspan-steals-from-bart-simpsoni-didnt-do-it/</url><title>alan greenspan ’steals’ from bart simpson..”..i didn’t do it..!..”</title><date>2007-12-13 19:27:56.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
the former head of the american federal reserve..and one of the prime architects of the millennium-madness-housing-bubble..
(think on..!..before this madness..property 'value' increases had only matched inflation..for forty-five years..!
..and there is now a 70% 'over-value' in property..
..so..the five percent drop of the last year..
..only indicates the direction things are heading..
eh..?..)
well..anyway..greenspan is trying to wash his hands of [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/favourite-things/</url><title>“..favourite things..”</title><date>2007-12-13 19:16:53.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
"..My greatest film experience happened on a rooftop in the desert in Jordan.
I was there taking part in the Sundance Middle Eastern screenwriting lab, and every night they showed us movies under the stars.
One night they showed us Yousry Nasrallah's 1999 film "El Medina."
Set in Cairo, it showed a city that was sexy, turbulent and [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://whoar.co.nz/2007/dyareckon-therell-be-a-soft-landing/</url><title>d’yareckon there’ll be a ’soft landing’..?</title><date>2007-12-13 18:57:01.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
"..However, a "soft landing" doesn't seem likely.
Aside from the problems in the financial system and credit markets - which do not seem to have passed - there is the problem of falling home prices.
Just as the fantasy-based prices of the late 1990s stock market were much broader than a "tech bubble," this is not just [...]]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.geekzone.co.nz/tonyhughes/4239</url><title>Google Adsense URL Channels - Very Convenient</title><date>2007-12-13 05:54:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
I just noticed this morning when updating some details in Google Adsense, that you can create new channels, and simply assign URLs to them. Use the same Adsense ID on all your websites, and Google does all the hard work in splitting the stats and earning details by site.<br /><br />Not sure how long thats been around, but very cool nonetheless.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.geekzone.co.nz/freitasm/4248</url><title>Air New Zealand Grab a plane</title><date>2007-12-13 20:39:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Ok, let's get into this game... One of our moderators, Steve Biddle, has created a &quot;<a href="https://www.grabaplane.co.nz/Join.aspx?fgfCode=24KYRPCBK" target="_blank">Geekzone flight</a>&quot; in the latest <a href="https://www.grabaplane.co.nz/Join.aspx?fgfCode=24KYRPCBK" target="_blank">Air New Zealand promotion Grab a plane</a>. <br /><br />You can <a href="https://www.grabaplane.co.nz/Join.aspx?fgfCode=24KYRPCBK" target="_blank">join the Geekzone flight now</a>&nbsp;- full planes go in the draw to win the flight to anywhere in New Zealand for a full day - for everyone in the plane. The flight plan is Wellington - Dunedin. so if you join the flight, be prepared to depart from Wellington.<br /><br />You can also create your own flight to other destinations.
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/gzfreitasm?a=a2GWSR"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/gzfreitasm?i=a2GWSR" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=Q6IvuOC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=Q6IvuOC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=rO9UZQC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=rO9UZQC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=esQFD3c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=esQFD3c" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?a=yrUh66c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/gzfreitasm?i=yrUh66c" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/gzfreitasm/~4/199935892" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://brainstab.blogspot.com/2007/12/year-9-what-do-i-have-to-do-to-get-into.html</url><title></title><date>2007-12-13 06:20:15.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
Year 9 “What do I have to do to get into Classics?”<br />Me “Well, Classics is a Year 13 subject, so you’re a good couple of years away from that being an issue.”<br />Year 9 “Yeah, but what do I need to get into it in Year 13?”<br />Me “Well, you have three years in which to not make me angry – basically, that is the sole entry requirement.”<br />Year 9 “I’m a good student, and I never make you angry.”<br />Me “See, that’s a lie, which makes me angry. You haven’t gotten off to a good start...”]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://diversity.net.nz/google-and-accounting/2007/12/14/</url><title>Google and accounting…</title><date>2007-12-13 17:17:18.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>With a hat tip to a clean shaven Mike, this <a href="http://www.readwriteweb.com/archives/online_accounting_google_apps.php" target="_blank">post</a> over on RWW surmises that an online accounting system might be in the pipline from Google. The rationale for the idea of Google entering this space is pretty much the rationale for them entering every space - eyeballs, data and stickiness.</p>
<p>If we look however at who Google are - they are predominantly a mass market player - as such they're keen to get the maximum number of eyeballs in any one particular space.</p>
<p>With that in mind, I'm picking that Google will launch a financial offering, but it'll be more along the lines of "Google your money" than "Google business money". I'm picturing home budgeting (obvious advertising fit there ) and cashflow. Some nice calculators to work stuff out and the like. All these things can be rolled out pretty globally without customisation, accounting is much more location specific and not completely within the current Google model.</p>
<p>I'm sure they do have people looking at the business accounting space but I don't see it happening in the near future... but then again I could be wrong. I wonder if <a href="http://www.xero.com" target="_blank">Xero</a> feel like commenting on the possibiilty?</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/free-home-makeover.html</url><title>Free Home Makeover</title><date>2007-12-14 01:02:05.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
A new reality television show is offering to help you declutter your home and give it a stylish new look. If your home is cluttered, lacks storage and is in need of a new look, then a new TV home show can help you for free. All they need is your time and willingness to participate. Experts will help you to get organised, streamline your home, and turn it into the sanctuary you’ve always dreamed of. Along with the completed form, please send of a photo of the people in your household, as well as photos of each room, and the house’s exterior. Delivery details of where to send your form and photos are on the application form. For more information email The Factory TV or phone 09-376-9963. Related Stories: Click here for other opportunities to be on TV game shows, competitions and reality TV]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/apply-now-for-deal-or-no-deal-2008.html</url><title>Apply now for Deal or No Deal 2008</title><date>2007-12-13 21:53:45.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<img src="http://bp1.blogger.com/_HZlxBZQcoGI/RsJpCLB9eZI/AAAAAAAAA9Y/-lwY5TzWeQg/s400/Dealornodeal2.JPG" alt="Deal or No Deal" border="0" /><br />TV3 and Imagination TV are inviting applications for the next series of <a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/search/label/Deal%20or%20No%20Deal">Deal or No Deal</a> to air in 2008.<br /><br />To apply you must be 18 years of age or older and a NZ resident. Head on over to <a href="http://www.tv3.co.nz/Programmes/DealOrNoDeal/ContestantApplications/tabid/275/Default.aspx#top">TV3 to fill out the application form</a>. Remember you will be judged on your application, so the more personality you can put into it, the better your chances are of being selected!<br /><br /><span>Related Stories:</span><br /><a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/search/label/Auditions">Click here for other opportunities to be on TV game shows, competitions and reality TV</a>
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?a=5uAboa"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?i=5uAboa" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=GtOceXC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=GtOceXC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=HiGIK9c"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=HiGIK9c" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=wRosMpc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=wRosMpc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=IoyppLc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=IoyppLc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NewZealandRealityTv/~4/199954046" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.nzrealitytv.com/2007/12/be-on-property-challenge.html</url><title>Be On Property Challenge</title><date>2007-12-13 08:33:12.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<img src="http://bp3.blogger.com/_HZlxBZQcoGI/R2DuIrsnMRI/AAAAAAAABUo/mi6rbCqt0Nk/s320/j0414038.jpg" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5143372607393313042" border="0" />Cream Media is taking the Kiwi zeal for property trading and turning it into a reality television show.<br /><br />Two Kiwi couples will be given a start-up house. The goal is to be the first to trade their way up to their dream home, renovating four houses to come close to the million dollar mark.<br /><br />For each house the couples have at their disposal a renovation budget.<br /><br />If you've been wondering lately how you'll ever make it into the property market, this could be your chance. This is a competition of skill and planning.<br /><br />The winning couple will be lavishly rewarded with an abundance of prizes.<br /><br />Click here for the <a href="http://www.creammedia.co.nz/default,446,property_challenge.sm">application form for Property Challenge<br /></a><br />Click here for <a href="http://www.nzrealitytv.com/search/label/Auditions">other opportunities to be on TV</a>.
<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?a=gFsOeS"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~a/NewZealandRealityTv?i=gFsOeS" border="0" /></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=20CiatC"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=20CiatC" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=Yfchhxc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=Yfchhxc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=mFV1Lgc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=mFV1Lgc" border="0" /></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?a=9wGMcNc"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~f/NewZealandRealityTv?i=9wGMcNc" border="0" /></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/NewZealandRealityTv/~4/199629113" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~3/200070213/for-love-of-everything-useful-stop.html</url><title>For the love of everything useful, stop searching for Britney Spears people!</title><date>2007-12-14 15:50:40.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist2007/index.html" title="2007 Google Zeitgeist"><img src="http://i6.photobucket.com/albums/y211/miramarmike/google_zeitgeist_2007.png" alt="2007 Google Zeitgeist" align="right" border="0" /></a>Google has it's <a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist2007/index.html">2007 Zeitgesit</a> [<a href="http://www.google.co.nz/search?hl=en&amp;client=firefox-a&amp;rls=org.mozilla:en-US:official&amp;hs=nuf&amp;defl=en&amp;q=define:Zeitgeist&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=glossary_definition&amp;ct=title">defined</a>] out and <a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist2007/newsmakers.html">Britney Spears was NUMBER 3 'newsmaker'</a> ... for lawds sake, stop doing searches for her ... YOU, right now, stop it!<br /><br />These are nice, from the <a href="http://www.google.com/intl/en/press/zeitgeist2007/mind.html">"Top of the mind" section</a>:<br /><blockquote><span>Who is...</span><br /><br /> 1. who is god<br /> 2. who is who<br /> 3. who is lookup<br /> 4. who is jesus<br /> 5. who is it<br /> 6. who is buckethead<br /> 7. who is calling<br /> 8. who is keppler<br /> 9. who is this<br />10. who is satan<br /><br /><span>What is...</span><br /><br /> 1. what is love<br /> 2. what is autism<br /> 3. what is rss<br /> 4. what is lupus<br /> 5. what is sap<br /> 6. what is bluetooth<br /> 7. what is emo<br /> 8. what is java<br /> 9. what is hpv<br />10. what is gout<br /><br /><span>How to...</span><br /><br /> 1. how to kiss<br /> 2. how to draw<br /> 3. how to knit<br /> 4. how to hack<br /> 5. how to dance<br /> 6. how to crochet<br /> 7. how to meditate<br /> 8. how to flirt<br /> 9. how to levitate<br />10. how to skateboard</blockquote><div class="blogger-post-footer"><hr />
<small>
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/search/label/enterprise%202.0" title="Subscribe to MirmarMike's Enterprise 2.0 postings">Enterprise 2.0 New Zealand style</a> since 2001<br />
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html" title="Subscribe to MiramarMike">Subscribe to other parts of MiramarMike</a> (Wellington, New Zealand)<br />
</small></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~4/200070213" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~3/199924736/if-youre-using-miramarmike-feed-you.html</url><title>If you're using the "MiramarMike" feed you have 30 days to change</title><date>2007-12-14 09:53:07.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<img src="http://i6.photobucket.com/albums/y211/miramarmike/rss_web_20.png" align="right" />I have deleted the MiramarMike feed (http://feeds.feedburner.com/Miramarmike) and in 30 days it will be toast.<br /><br />I'd love you all to stay subscribed to the blog as I have a lifetime of things to say.<br />Please use this feed from now on: <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/MiramarMikesBlog">http://feeds.feedburner.com/MiramarMikesBlog</a><br /><br />Thanks everyone.<div class="blogger-post-footer"><hr />
<small>
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/search/label/enterprise%202.0" title="Subscribe to MirmarMike's Enterprise 2.0 postings">Enterprise 2.0 New Zealand style</a> since 2001<br />
<a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/04/miramarmike-rss-feed-now-supports-all.html" title="Subscribe to MiramarMike">Subscribe to other parts of MiramarMike</a> (Wellington, New Zealand)<br />
</small></div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/MiramarMikesBlog/~4/199924736" height="1" width="1" />]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://dubdotdash.blogspot.com/2007/12/bullets-i-went-to-junior-reid-last.html</url><title></title><date>2007-12-14 10:48:31.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Bullets
• I went to Junior Reid last night - wicked show, splendid voice, but the number of punters I talked to complaining about the ridiculously late start-time was high - word was he was coming on at 12, and he hit the stage closer to 1am. Wake up, promoters, that's just shabby. I was talking with a mate who told me about going to see some hiphop MCs in New York, and they heard the show]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pmofnz.blogspot.com/2007/12/first-reading-of-christmas-bill.html</url><title>First reading of The Christmas Bill</title><date>2007-12-13 15:10:58.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<span>Stocking fillers all MP's could ever want and wish for is listed by Vernon Small.<br /><br />Some classics are;<br /></span> <ul>   <li>Taito - one night in Bangkok on a tiling course<br /> </li>   <li>Helen - a fourth term and older MSM hacks<br /> </li>   <li>Winnie - a compliant media, reporting the real facts as written in a Winnie diktat</li>   <li>Michael - just one more budget</li>   <li>Bill - a big non-inflationary tax cut</li>   <li>Phil - an A4 buyer<br /> </li>   <li>Chris - NCEA spell checker</li>   <li>Jeannette - more bloody bus lanes</li>   <li>Jim - a retirement date</li>   <li>Tau - a mouthguard</li>   <li>Margaret - peace in her time</li>   <li>and Hugh - a spin doctor</li> </ul> Full detail can be found <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4322658a1861.html">here</a>.<br /><br />ps: Wonder if 17 white A4's show up against the Woodbourne brown on Google Earth - too slow on dialup to have a squiz - at least a potential buyer could now see what is actually being hocked off.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://pmofnz.blogspot.com/2007/12/chasm-starts-to-open.html</url><title>The chasm starts to open?</title><date>2007-12-13 10:19:29.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<span>In a move sure to really annoy the Minister of Baubles, the party exec has requested that all 7 NZ First MP's <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&amp;objectid=10482049">vote against the EFB</a>.  Seems the word from the party faithfull is no go on restrictions on freedom of speech, even if costs you your place in the trough.  Some one else with some ethics over this matter.<br /></span><span><blockquote>the bill was not supported within the party and that the caucus was supporting it because it would help their own survival.</blockquote></span><br /><span>This will be interesting.  At least Liarbour will have a scapegoat if the bill does not pass.<br /><br />Is that devil or the deep blue sea I spy?<br /></span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.realbeer.co.nz/blog/2007/12/beer-haiku-beer-by-committee.html</url><title>Beer Haiku - Beer by Committee</title><date>2007-12-14 12:24:08.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
Writing about the Collaborator Doppelbock, Captain Hops aptly captures the problem with beers designed by a committee in today's Beer Haiku.

Brewed by committee.
How many are too many
Cooks in the kitchen?

Glass tip - As ever, Beer Haiku Daily

Our Beer in the Media Watch section is occupied for the second week in a row by the Education Review.  Tom Reece, the Chief Executive of the Extractives]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/RodDrury/~3/200063259/</url><title>Phone bits</title><date>2007-12-14 03:04:22.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Two interesting phone/email bits today.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.appleinsider.com/articles/07/12/13/apple_working_on_improved_exchange_support_for_iphone.html" target="_blank">Apple working on improved Exchange support for iPhone</a></p>
<p>Probably via Active Sync. Wonder if Apple have licensed that yet? Though they could use WebDav ala Entourage.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.geekzone.co.nz/freitasm/4246" target="_blank"> Telecom to do BlackBerry's</a></p>
<p>I had heard that Voda had the NZ rights to BB (if there is such a thing) so I wonder if the 'WorldMode' wording is important.</p>
<p>If iPhone plays nicely with Exchange is BlackBerry moot anyway? With iPhone push email what happens to RIM?</p>
<p>Roll on 2008. It's shaping up to be a big year.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.spareroom.co.nz/2007/12/14/giveaway-tickets-to-mercury-rising-07/</url><title>Giveaway — Tickets to Mercury Rising 07</title><date>2007-12-13 21:43:17.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<img id="image3283" height="200" width="390" alt="Katchafire" src="http://www.spareroom.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/katchafire.jpg" /><p class="image-caption"> Katchafire -- one of the headline acts at Mercury Rising 07</p>
As if our <a href="http://www.spareroom.co.nz/2007/11/29/gold-coast-giveaway-2/">Gold Coast giveaway</a> wasn't enough, <em>Spare Room</em> is offering readers the chance to win two tickets (2 x GA tickets with a parking permit) to Mercury Rising 07, this New Years Eve at Whitianga on The Coromandel Peninsula...]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://unpclesbian.blogspot.com/2007/12/open-letter-to-my-clients.html</url><title>Open Letter to my Clients</title><date>2007-12-14 17:23:16.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<span>Dear Clients,</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>As you know I have no problem with you booking your own bands, and in fact will encourage it as it's just less shit for me to deal with. There is however one thing you should keep in mind. When you originally saw the band playing and had a great time, you were probably drunk.</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>So, tomorrow morning when you are all nursing your hangovers and muttering to yourselves, "I danced to that!", remember, YOU booked them.</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>This has to be the worst  sound check I have ever had to endure. Lucky me though as I get to leave before they fully crank up for the night.</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>Love</span><br /><span>Unpclesbian</span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wellingtonista.com/dropkicks-job-available</url><title>Dropkicks Job Available</title><date>2007-12-14 00:15:54.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>One of the Wellingtonista's sibling blogs (and podcast), the Dropkicks, are looking for a woman to join their team.</p>
<p>Applicants will need to:</p>
<ol>
<li>Live in Wellington.</li>
<li>Have a good knowledge of sports both local and worldwide. But not too good a knowledge, just at least as good as theirs…i.e. can make stuff up if needed.</li>
<li>Be funny, or be able to enjoy a good laugh (and be able to put up with your favourite sports team being made fun of)</li>
<li>Put up with us and their inane banter, while hav­ing the ability to create your own (see point 2)</li>
<li>Have one night a week free to record the cast (usually a Monday)</li>
<li>Be a woman of the female persuasion</li>
</ol>
<p>If you think that you might be interested in joining their "dynamic and energetic team" then <a href="http://www.dropkicks.co.nz">pop on over</a> and check them out.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://wellingtonista.com/best-cities-wtf</url><title>best cities... wtf?</title><date>2007-12-13 07:42:34.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><img align="right" vspace="5" hspace="5" width="160" height="105" src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v664/wellingtonist/2007-12/Picture.jpg" alt="Best Cities on Facebook" />Usually website related pissing contests (Hot Or Not; Rate My, [er...] Kitteh etc etc <em>ad infinitum</em>) are inherently dull. </p>
<p>But maybe not so dull if you are former Wellingtonian, now <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Munich">Münchener</a> mad-genius developer <a href="http://www.bennolan.com/">Ben Nolan</a>.</p>
<p>His <a href="http://apps.facebook.com/bestcities/">Best Cities Facebook application</a> did, for a tiny golden moment, have Wellington in the top spot. Which means of course that this pissing contest is now of interest to us, too!</p>
<p>Unfortunately, Facebook being the kind of random, viral place that it is, the app has been seized upon by at least two distinct regional groups each competing within each other parochially for the title of best city. </p>
<p>The upshot of all this is that towns like <a href="http://apps.facebook.com/bestcities/cities/show/79">Slavonski Brod</a>, a no doubt <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slavonski_Brod">quite lovely town</a> with a rather pulchritudinous population but not much larger than Invercargill, is the world's fifth best city, with <a href="http://apps.facebook.com/bestcities/cities/show/3">Wellington relegated to 15th</a>.</p>
<p>This is clearly not good enough. Get to it. peeps!</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/shadbolt_threatens_government.html</url><title>Shadbolt threatens Government</title><date>2007-12-13 18:46:10.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>The <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/story.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482269">Invercargill Mayor is quoted</a> in the Herald:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>Mr Shadbolt said a proposed $8 million cut for the institute would lead to a loss of 1400 students and be bad for the region.</em></p>
<p><em>"This is a direct attack on everything we've done and everything we've achieved in the last five years and we're not going to stop on Friday and say, 'Oh well, that's the end of it'," he told Radio New Zealand.</em></p>
<p><em>"There's an election coming up and we'll be doing everything we possibly can. We're going to launch a campaign to bring down this Government if they are going to launch a campaign to bring down our province."</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Except sadly for Tim and Invercargill, their campaign will be limited to $120,000.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/deforestation.html</url><title>Deforestation</title><date>2007-12-13 02:43:29.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>National has just done <a href="http://www.scoop.co.nz/stories/PA0712/S00283.htm">a press release</a> highlighting the hypocrisy of David Parker preaching overseas about the need to end global deforestation, when their own policies in NZ have led to deforestation</p>
<blockquote><p><em>“Deforestation in New Zealand will top six million trees this year.  This comes on top of losses of three million trees in 2004, 2005, and 2006.  New Zealand planted more trees than it felled for every year from 1951, when records began, until 2003.</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Deforestation contributes to global warming, so goes totally against the rhetoric of carbon neutrality.  Anyway I thought I would make a graph out of the data with the PR about net planted forest area.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/forests.JPG" title="forests.JPG"><img src="http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/forests.JPG" alt="forests.JPG" /></a></p>
<p>Another case of all rhetoric, and no action.  Actually in this case it is worse than inaction.  Their actions have caused a 50 year trend of expanding forests to slow and then reverse.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/around_the_blogs-2.html</url><title>Around the blogs</title><date>2007-12-13 02:32:26.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>Steven Price has an interesting <a href="http://www.medialawjournal.co.nz/?p=35">post about Dom Post editor Tim Pankhurst's address</a><br />
to the journalism conference. I wanted to attend that conference but was too busy.</p>
<p><a href="http://poneke.wordpress.com/2007/12/13/for-god-queen-and-country-sun-sets-on-the-new-zealand-league-of-rights/">Poneke celebrates</a> the demise on the anti-Jewish League of Rights.</p>
<p><a href="http://miramarmike.blogspot.com/2007/12/google-maps-is-fully-here-in-new.html">Miramar Mike blogs</a> on the launch of Google Maps in NZ (yay)</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://coffee.geek.nz/2007/12/14/bookmooch.html</url><title>bookmooch</title><date>2007-12-14 05:23:00.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>i have discovered the joys of bookmooch.com</p>
<p>List the books you have, but no longer want -- and then go request books from other people. It's a points based system. I sent a few books off to people for free (i paid postage) and now i have points. I then requested some books from elsewhere, and they arrive to me!</p>
<p>This be the books i don't want:<br /><a href="http://bookmooch.com/m/inventory/br3nda">http://bookmooch.com/m/inventory/br3nda</a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://grabthar.blogspot.com/2007/12/out-to-get-me-thin.html</url><title>Out to get me, thin</title><date>2007-12-13 00:15:00.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
I have this sneaking suspicion that New World (yes, the supermarket) is saying something about my current physique. Every time I go there to get one of their award-winning steak and cheese pies (made with actual bits of steak!)  they are "out" or "not doing them today". This causes me to turn around and get a healthy sandwich from the make-a-sandwich-bar thingy behind me.<br /><br />I know what you're trying to tell me. Bastards!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://idealog.co.nz/weekly/nothing-in-common-perfect</url><title>Nothing in common? Perfect</title><date>2007-12-13 01:55:34.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<div><img src="http://idealog.co.nz/assets/images/weekly/200712/fish.jpg" alt="Article illustration" /></div><strong>In this week&rsquo;s issue:</strong> Nothing in common? Perfect, dazed and bemused, soothing vibrations, hey dad cn u pls text me that mp3 and those pix and 5 hundy? Cheers, taxing the taxi, beauty on the inside, Christmas lessons, last and least with a little bit of yeast and quote of the week]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://unpclesbian.blogspot.com/2007/12/open-letter-to-my-clients.html</url><title>Open Letter to my Clients</title><date>2007-12-14 04:15:00.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<span>Dear Clients,</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>As you know I have no problem with you booking your own bands, and in fact will encourage it as it's just less shit for me to deal with. There is however one thing you should keep in mind. When you originally saw the band playing and had a great time, you were probably drunk.</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>So, tomorrow morning when you are all nursing your hangovers and muttering to yourselves, "I danced to that!", remember, YOU booked them.</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>This has to be the worst  sound check I have ever had to endure. Lucky me though as I get to leave before they fully crank up for the night.</span><br /><span></span><br /><span>Love</span><br /><span>Unpclesbian</span>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5486</url><title>Aussies select Kiwi to teach them how to play Rugby</title><date>2007-12-14 05:51:34.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/4/story.cfm?c_id=4&amp;objectid=10482083" rel="nofollow">Deans to coach Wallabies and Crusaders - 14 Dec 2007 - nzherald: Sports news - New Zealand and International Sport news and&nbsp;results</a></p>
<p>Good riddance, fecking South&nbsp;Islanders.</p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5484</url><title>Oh STFU Winston</title><date>2007-12-14 01:23:16.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/category/story.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482351" rel="nofollow">Winston Peters and Bob Clarkson at loggerheads again - 14 Dec 2007 - Politics: New Zealand Political News, Analysis and Comment - <span class="caps">NZ</span>&nbsp;Herald</a></p>
<p>We are sick of hearing about who you are going to sue next. Most of the time you lose, in fact have you ever won&nbsp;anything?</p>
<p>You are nothing short of a&nbsp;windbag. </p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5482</url><title>NZ First hypocrisy exposed fully</title><date>2007-12-13 19:22:47.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.kiwiblog.co.nz/2007/12/nz_first_on_electoral_reform.html" rel="nofollow">Kiwiblog » Blog Archive » <span class="caps">NZ</span> First on Electoral&nbsp;Reform</a></p>
<p>Winston likes to think and constantly intones that his party is the only one with integrity. Perhaps he mutters under his breath whenever he says this "...of a&nbsp;whore".</p>
<p><span class="caps">DPF</span> has exposed his and his party's hypocrisy for all to&nbsp;see.</p>
<p>Winston First supporters should hang their heads in&nbsp;shame.</p>
<p class="poweredbyperformancing">Powered by <a href="http://scribefire.com/" rel="nofollow">ScribeFire</a>.</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.whaleoil.co.nz/?q=node/5477</url><title>Shadbolt threat to topple Govt</title><date>2007-12-13 18:52:15.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>
<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/index.cfm?c_id=280&amp;objectid=10482269&amp;ref=rss" rel="nofollow">Shadbolt threat to topple Govt</a> - <i>Invercargill Mayor Tim Shadbolt says he will fight to bring down the Government if funding to the Southern Institute of Technology is cut.<br />
The Government will announce today how much money universities, polytechnics and other tertiary...</i> [<a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/" rel="nofollow"><span class="caps">NZ</span> Politics</a>]
</p>
<p>
Tim Shadbolt, someone I have no time for, is mad, real mad. He is going to campaign to bring the government down.....well he will be able to place a couple of ads in the paper to do so because he will be limited to&nbsp;$120,000.
</p>
<p>
Unless of course he follows is Vietnam War protesting days and willfully breaks the&nbsp;law. 
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/toonedin/2007/12/14/early-christmas-presents-and-labours-pains/</url><title>Early Christmas presents and Labour’s pains</title><date>2007-12-13 20:32:05.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards4.jpg" title="rickards4.jpg"></a><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards4-295-x-561.jpg" title="rickards4-295-x-561.jpg"></a><img vspace="5" width="265" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards4-295-x-561.jpg" hspace="5" alt="rickards4-295-x-561.jpg" height="505" title="rickards4-295-x-561.jpg" /></p>
<p>This will have to be a brief post since my wife is going into labour and I need to finish my cartoon for tomorrow as soon as possible. Yikes! No pressure, eh? Fortunately there's lots of good material to choose from.</p>
<p>We're planning to have a home birth, so I'll be around the house throughout the day, popping in and out from my studio. We had our last child at home too, and I was working at the <em>Nelson Mail</em> at the time. I remember finishing at 11am as soon as the paper went to press, then racing home on my bike as Fran's contractions were getting stronger and more frequent. By 1:30pm we had a new addition to our family. Talk about good timing!</p>
<p>Anyway, here are some new pics. Wish us all luck ...<br />
<a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards1.JPG" title="rickards1.JPG"><img border="0" vspace="6" align="middle" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards1.JPG" hspace="6" alt="rickards1.JPG" /></a> <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards2.JPG" title="rickards2.JPG"><img border="0" vspace="6" align="middle" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards2.JPG" hspace="6" alt="rickards2.JPG" /></a><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards3.jpg" title="rickards3.jpg"><img border="0" vspace="6" align="middle" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/rickards3.jpg" hspace="6" alt="rickards3.jpg" /></a><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/ideas1.JPG" title="ideas1.JPG"><img border="0" vspace="6" align="middle" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/ideas1.JPG" hspace="6" alt="ideas1.JPG" /></a><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/ideas2.JPG" title="ideas2.JPG"><img border="0" vspace="6" align="middle" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/ideas2.JPG" hspace="6" alt="ideas2.JPG" /></a><a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/ideas3.jpg" title="ideas3.jpg"><img border="0" vspace="6" align="middle" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/ideas3.jpg" hspace="6" alt="ideas3.jpg" /></a></p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/catwalktalk/2007/12/13/sexy-in-the-city/</url><title>Sexy in the City</title><date>2007-12-13 01:09:40.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p><em><img vspace="5" align="right" src="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/sexandthecitymovie1-1bmp.jpeg" hspace="5" alt="sexandthecitymovie1-1bmp.jpeg" title="sexandthecitymovie1-1bmp.jpeg" />Sex and the City</em> would by far be one of the most inspirational television programmes on the airwaves today. Who could resist a life living in uptown New York, wearing couture to get coffee, buying Manolos when you're down and partying with the best-looking people in town? Not to mention your job is to casually write about life in general, to pay for your penthouse suite apartment in the hottest part of NYC.</p>
<p>But let's be real here. Not many of us can pop down the road and do such things. I mean, they don't even sell Manolos here!</p>
<p>But luckily - to complement the launch of the new <em>Sex and the City</em> movie, Miami-based lingerie label Cosabella has just done a deal with HBO to release two Sex and the City underwear collections next year.</p>
<p>The first collection will be available in stores in April for the launch of the movie, and the second will go on sale later on in the year once the DVD version of the film debuts.</p>
<p>Hey - I like the fact that they're trying to include the public in a small piece of their extravagant life. Sure they won't sell it here (along with everything else that we don't have), but for some lucky few you can feel like Carrie Bradshaw every day.<br />
<a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/blogs/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/sexandthecitymovie1-1bmp.jpeg" title="sexandthecitymovie1-1bmp.jpeg"></a> </p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.dropkicks.co.nz/omg_deenz_iz_teh_awsumist</url><title>OMG!!! Deenz iz teh AWSUMIST!!!</title><date>2007-12-14 01:57:06.000004</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>While the official announcement isn't until 3pm NZ time, Stuff has already (prematurely?) <a href="http://www.stuff.co.nz/4324137a1823.html?source=RSSsport_20071214">creamed themselves</a> to tell everyone that Robbie Deans will be the new Wallabies coach.</p>
<p>Won't they look silly if it actually turns out to be David Nucifora (which it won't).</p>
<p>So now that Knuckles is gone what nickname are we gonna give Deans? Comentz pleez</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=867</url><title>You asked for it Auckland</title><date>2007-12-13 21:36:32.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>From <a href="http://www.nzherald.co.nz/section/1/story.cfm?c_id=1&amp;objectid=10482303&amp;ref=rss">The Herald</a>:</p>
<blockquote><p>The Auckland City Council has scrapped its plan to build affordable housing.</p>
<p>The last council signed a contract with the New Zealand housing Trust to build 100 homes for lower income families.</p>
<p>The contract was worth $9 million.</p>
<p>Mayor John Banks says it was a pet-project with the last council and one he did not agree with.</p></blockquote>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=867&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_867" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
<item>
<url>http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=864</url><title>John Key DVD - Director’s cut</title><date>2007-12-13 04:45:48.000003</date><description><![CDATA[
<p>John Key is the epitome of "style over substance" and his DVD showed us just how desperately he wants to be everything to everyone.</p>
<p>This <strike>Production Shed.TV</strike> user-submitted video explores the man <em>behind</em> the mask.</p>



<p>
<p class="akst_link"><a href="http://www.thestandard.org.nz/?p=864&amp;akst_action=share-this" title="E-mail this, post to del.icio.us, etc." id="akst_link_864" class="akst_share_link" rel="nofollow">Share This</a>
</p>]]></description>
</item>
</category>
